[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
DAVID J. MALAN: All right, this is CS50.
大卫·马兰：好的，这里是 CS50。
And this is week 5.
这是第五周。
And among our goals for today are to revisit some topics from past weeks
我们今天要做的其中一件事，是回顾一下之前几周的一些内容，
but to focus all the more on design possibilities, particularly
但重点是设计可能性，尤其是
by way of data structures.
通过数据结构。
So data structures, again, is this way via which you can structure your data.
所以，数据结构，再一次地，它是指你可以用它来组织数据的方式。
But more specifically in C, It's how you can
但更具体地说，在 C 语言中，它是指你可以
use your computer's memory in interesting and, daresay, clever ways
以有趣且，我敢说，聪明的方式使用你的计算机内存
to actually solve problems more effectively.
从而更有效地解决问题。
But we're going to see today that there's actually
但今天我们将看到，实际上
different types of data structures.
有不同类型的数据结构。
And we'll make the distinction between abstractions,
我们将区分抽象
like high-level descriptions of these structures
像这些结构的高级描述
and the lower-level implementation details so to speak.
以及更低级的实现细节，姑且这么说吧。
So in particular, we'll talk first today about what we call abstract data types.
因此，今天我们将首先谈论我们所说的抽象数据类型。
So an abstract data type is like a data structure.
所以，抽象数据类型就像数据结构。
But it offers certain properties, certain characteristics.
但是它提供了一些属性，一些特性。
And it's actually up to the programmer how
而程序员实际上可以决定
to implement the underlying implementation details.
如何实现底层的实现细节。
So, for instance, there's actually this abstract data type that's
例如，实际上存在一种在计算中很常见的抽象数据类型，叫做
common in computing known as a queue.
队列。
And from the real world, most of us are presumably familiar with queues,
在现实生活中，我们大多数人可能都熟悉队列，
otherwise known in the US typically as lines or forming lines.
在美国，通常被称为排队或排队。
In fact, I have here three bags of cookies.
事实上，我这里有三大袋饼干。
Could I get three volunteers to come up on stage and queue up?
三位志愿者可以上台排队吗？
OK, I saw your hand first.
好的，我第一个看到你的手了。
How about your hand second?
你的手第二个？
And in the blue.
穿蓝色衣服的你。
OK, come on down, just you three.
好的，请你们三位过来。
Come on over.
过来。
And if you want to queue up over here if you could.
如果可以的话，请你们在这里排队。
Come on down.
过来。
Thank you.
谢谢。
As we begin, do you want to introduce yourselves first?
在我们开始之前，你们想先自我介绍吗？
NAFTALI HOROWITZ: Hi.
纳夫塔利·霍洛维茨：你好。
My name is Naftali Horowitz.
我叫纳夫塔利·霍洛维茨。
I'm a first year studying computer science and economics.
我是一年级学生，学习计算机科学和经济学。
And I sleep at Hurlbut Hall.
我住在赫尔巴特大厅。
DAVID J. MALAN: All right, next.
大卫·马兰：好的，下一个。
CATHERINE: Hi, everyone, my name is Catherine.
凯瑟琳：大家好，我叫凯瑟琳。
I'm planning on studying engineering.
我计划学习工程学。
I'm not sure mechanical or electrical yet but one of the two.
我不确定是机械还是电气，但会选择其中之一。
And I'm currently in Kennedy.
我目前住在肯尼迪。
DAVID J. MALAN: Nice.
大卫·马兰：不错。
Nice to meet.
很高兴认识你。
ISABELLA: Hi, everyone.
伊莎贝拉：大家好。
I'm Isabella.
我叫伊莎贝拉。
I'm in Strauss.
我住在斯特劳斯。
And I plan on majoring in computer science.
我计划主修计算机科学。
DAVID J. MALAN: Wonderful.
大卫·J·马兰：太棒了。
Well, welcome to all three of you.
欢迎三位。
And I think this will be pretty straightforward.
我认为这会很简单。
I have here these three bags of cookies.
我这里有这三袋饼干。
You formed nicely this line or this queue.
你们排成了一条漂亮的长队。
So if you'd like to come up first and take your cookies, thank you.
所以，如果你想先上来拿你的饼干，谢谢。
And right that way, that's all there is to this demonstration.
就这样，这就是这个演示的全部内容。
Your cookies as well.
你们的饼干也一样。
Right this way.
这边来。
And your cookies.
还有你的饼干。
Right this way.
这边来。
Wonderfully well done.
干得真棒！
Thank you to our volunteers.
感谢我们的志愿者。
The point is actually sincere, though, simple as that demonstration was.
虽然这个演示很简单，但它确实说明了一个重要的道理。
And as easy as it was to get those cookies,
虽然拿这些饼干很容易，
queues actually manifest a property that actually
但排队实际上体现了一种性质，
is germane to a lot of problem solving and computing and the real world.
这与很多问题解决、计算以及现实世界密切相关。
Specifically, queues offer this characteristic, FIFO, first in first
具体来说，队列提供这种特性，FIFO，先进先出。
out.
(FIFO)。
And indeed as our volunteers just noticed,
事实上，正如我们的志愿者刚刚注意到的那样，
as they queued up on stage, 1, 2, 3, that is the order in which I
当他们在台上排队时，1、2、3，这就是我
handed them their cookies.
给他们饼干的顺序。
And daresay it's a very equitable approach.
我敢说这是一个非常公平的方法。
It's very fair.
非常公平。
First come, first served might be a more casual way
先来先服务可能是一种更口语化的说法
of describing FIFO, first in, first out.
来描述FIFO，先进先出。
Now, structures like these actually offer specific operations
现在，像这样的结构实际上提供了特定的操作
that make sense.
这些操作是有意义的。
And in the context of queues, we generally describe these operations
在队列的背景下，我们通常将这些操作描述为
as enqueueing and dequeueing
入队和出队。
So when our first three volunteers came up, they enqueued.
所以，当我们的前三位志愿者上来时，他们就入队了。
And as I handed them each a bag of cookies,
当我给他们每人发了一袋饼干时，
they dequeued and exited in that same order.
他们就出队了，并按照相同的顺序离开。
Now, how could you go about implementing a queue in code, specifically in C?
现在，如何在代码中实现一个队列，特别是在C语言中？
Well, we can actually implement it in bunches of different ways.
我们可以用很多不同的方法来实现它。
But perhaps the most obvious is to borrow our old friend, namely arrays.
但也许最明显的方法是借用我们老朋友，即数组。
And we could use a data structure that looks a little something
我们可以使用一个看起来像这样的数据结构。
like this, whereby we specify the total capacity of this data structure.
在这个结构中，我们指定了这个数据结构的总容量。
For instance, we might store a total of 50 people or just 3 in this case.
例如，我们可以存储总共50个人，或者像这个例子中只有3个人。
We might define our structure then as containing those people
然后，我们可以定义我们的结构，它包含这些人
as simply an array.
作为一个简单的数组。
And if a person is a data type that we've defined in week past,
如果一个人是我们在上周定义的数据类型，
you could imagine each of our volunteers is indeed a person.
你可以想象，我们的每个志愿者都是一个人。
And we've stored them one after the other contiguously in memory
我们已经将他们一个接一个地连续存储在内存中
by way of this actual array.
通过这个真实的数组。
But we do need to keep track inside of a queue using one other piece of data--
但我们确实需要使用另外一个数据来跟踪队列内部的信息，
namely, we need to keep track of an integer,
也就是说，我们需要跟踪一个整数，
like the size, like how many people are actually in the queue at this moment.
比如大小，比如现在队列中实际上有多少人。
Because if we have a total capacity of 50,
因为如果我们的总容量是50，
I'd like to if I only have three volunteers.
我希望只有三个志愿者。
Then I can do some quick arithmetic and know
然后我可以快速算一下，就知道
that I could have fit another 47 people in this same queue.
在这个队列中还可以容纳另外47个人。
But it's finite.
但它是有限的。
Of course, if we had 50 volunteers all wanting cookies, that's as many people
当然，如果我们有50个志愿者都想要饼干，那就和我们能处理的人数一样多。
as we could actually handle.
就是我们实际能处理的人数。
So there is this upper bound then on how many we could fit.
所以我们可以容纳的人数是有上限的。
But there's yet other ways for storing data inside of a computer's memory.
但是，在计算机的内存中还有其他存储数据的方式。
And there's this other abstract data type known as a stack.
还有另一种抽象数据类型叫做栈。
And stacks are actually omnipresent as well
而且栈实际上无处不在
even though it's not necessarily the system
尽管它不一定是
you would want when you line up on stage.
你想要在舞台上排队的系统。
For instance, could we get three more volunteers?
例如，我们可以再找到三个志愿者吗？
OK, I saw a hand here, right here, and right here.
好的，我看到这里有一只手，这里还有一只手，这里还有一只手。
Come on down.
请过来。
We'll have the orchestra come up this time.
这次让乐队过来。
All right, come on over.
好的，请过来。
And if you wouldn't mind, come on over.
如果你不介意，请过来。
We'll do introductions first.
我们先做一下自我介绍。
This will be almost as easy as the last one if you want to introduce yourself.
如果你想做自我介绍，这将和上一个一样简单。
And let me just stack you against the lectern this time.
这次我让你们在讲台上排成一列。
So if you could go there.
所以请你们到那里去。
And if you could come over here.
请你过来这边。
And if you could come over here, we'll stack all three of you.
请你过来这边，我们把你们三个都排成一列。
So you were first.
所以你第一个。
So you're first in the stack.
所以你在栈里排第一个。
SPEAKER: Hi.
嗨。
I'm [INAUDIBLE].
我叫[听不清]。
I have no idea what I'm studying.
我不知道我学什么。
And I live in Strauss.
我住在斯特劳斯。
DAVID J. MALAN: Wonderful.
太好了。
And next?
下一个？
SPEAKER: Hi.
嗨。
I'm [? Tanai. ?] I'm studying econ and CS.
我叫[？Tanai？] 我学习经济学和计算机科学。
And I live in Canada.
我住在加拿大。
CLARA: Hi.
嗨。
I'm Clara.
我叫克拉拉。
I want to study applied math.
我想学习应用数学。
And I'm in Wigglesworth.
我住在维格尔斯沃斯。
DAVID J. MALAN: Wonderful.
太好了。
Welcome, to all three of you.
欢迎你们三位。
And if I may, let me just advance a bit more information about stacks.
如果可以，我想再谈一下关于栈的一些信息。
The catch is that stacks actually support
关键是栈实际上支持
what's known as LIFO, so last in, first out, which
一种叫做LIFO的东西，也就是后进先出，这
is sort of the opposite really of a queue or a line.
实际上是队列或线的反义词。
So in fact you were last in line.
所以实际上你在队列的最后。
So here we have your cookies.
所以这是你的饼干。
Thank you so much.
非常感谢。
And if you'd like to exit that way, we have your cookies here.
如果你想从这边出去，你的饼干在这边。
Thank you so much.
非常感谢。
We'd you to exit this way.
请从这边离开。
And even though you were first, LIFO doesn't really
即使你是第一个，后进先出法（LIFO）实际上并不会
give you any cookies because you're first in, not last in.
给你任何饼干，因为你是第一个进来的，而不是最后一个进来的。
So, yeah, OK, point's made.
所以，好吧，明白了。
We'll give you the cookies.
我们会给你饼干的。
All right, so thank you to all three of our volunteers.
好了，感谢三位志愿者。
But LIFO, suffice to say, doesn't offer the same fairness
但后进先出法（LIFO）不足以说，它没有提供与队列或传统排队方式相同的公平性
guarantees as a queue or a line more traditionally.
保证。
And imagine just lining up in any store or the dining hall or the like.
想象一下在任何商店或食堂排队。
Ideally, you want the people running the place to adhere to that queue,
理想情况下，你希望经营场所的人遵守队列，
to that line so that FIFO is preserved if you indeed care about being first,
遵守排队顺序，以便如果你确实关心谁是第一个，那么先到先得法（FIFO）可以得到保留，
whereas there are contexts in which LIFO does actually make sense.
而在一些情况下，后进先出法（LIFO）确实有意义。
In fact, if you think about Gmail, your inbox, or Outlook,
事实上，如果你想想 Gmail、你的收件箱或 Outlook，
typically you're viewing your inbox as a stack right.
通常你将你的收件箱视为一个堆栈，对吧？
Because when you get new mail, where does it end up?
因为当你收到新邮件时，它会在哪里？
It actually ends up in the top.
它实际上会出现在顶部。
And if you're like me, odds are which emails do you tend to first?
如果你像我一样，你会倾向于先看哪封邮件？
I mean, probably the ones on the top, the ones that
我的意思是，可能是那些在顶部的，那些
came in last, most recently that is and that might actually
最后进来的，也就是最近的邮件，实际上可能
be to the detriment of people who emailed you earlier today or yesterday.
对今天或昨天早些时候给你发邮件的人不利。
Because once they sort of fall off the bottom of your screen,
因为一旦它们从你屏幕的底部掉下来，
frankly, unless you click next, you may never see those emails again.
坦白地说，除非你点击“下一页”，否则你可能永远不会再看到那些邮件。
But stacks are indeed one way of storing data.
但堆栈确实是一种存储数据的方式。
And Google and Microsoft presumably made the judgment
谷歌和微软可能做出了判断，
call that, in general, we users want to see the most recent data first.
认为，总的来说，我们用户希望首先看到最新数据。
The last information might be the first we want out.
最新的信息可能是我们最想得到的。
Now, just in terms of nomenclature, the two operations
现在，就术语而言，与入队和出队相似的两种操作
that are analogous to enqueueing and dequeueing
分别是入栈和出栈。
but with this property of LIFO are instead called push and pop.
它们具有后进先出法（LIFO）的特性，分别被称为入栈和出栈。
So when our first volunteer came up on stage, so to speak,
所以当我们的第一个志愿者上台时，可以这么说，
I pushed him onto the stack against the lectern there.
我把他推到讲台旁边的堆栈上。
Second person was pushed.
第二个人被推进去。
Third person was pushed.
第三个人被推进去。
And then when it was time to hand out the cookies,
然后当发放饼干的时候，
we popped them, so to speak, one after the other but preserving that LIFO
我们可以将它们“弹出”，一个接一个，但保留后进先出法（LIFO）
property.
特性。
But here's where things are a little interesting in terms
但这里在实现细节方面有点意思。
of implementation details.
在实现细节方面。
A stack could be implemented almost identically underneath the hood
堆栈可以在幕后几乎完全相同地实现
to a queue because what do you need?
与队列相同，因为你需要什么？
You need an array of people, which we could use our person data
你需要一个人的数组，我们可以使用我们在过去的课程中使用的人员数据
type for past classes.
类型。
We have to keep track of how many people are in the stack
我们必须跟踪堆栈中有多少人
so that even if we have a capacity of like 50,
这样即使我们的容量是 50，
we know at least that we can store 3 plus maybe 47 others.
我们至少知道我们可以存储 3 个人，再加上可能另外 47 个人。
Now, there's still going to be a change in the underlying implementation
现在，底层实现仍然会有一些变化。
details because not pictured here is the actual C code that actually pushes
细节是因为这里没有显示实际的 C 代码，它实际上是推入的
and pops or enqueues and dequeues.
以及弹出或入队和出队。
So whatever loops you're using, whatever code you're using,
所以无论你使用什么循环，无论你使用什么代码，
odds are that's where those properties are going to be implemented.
这些属性很可能是在那里实现的。
FIFO versus LIFO, you're going to implement maybe the loop
FIFO 与 LIFO，你可能会在循环中实现
in this direction instead of this one or some such distinction.
在这个方向而不是那个方向，或者类似的区分。
But at the end of the day, stacks and queues
但归根结底，栈和队列
are just abstract data types in the sense
只是抽象数据类型，从某种意义上说
that we can implement them in bunches of ways, two of them
我们可以用很多方法来实现它们，其中两种
among them here thus far on the screen.
其中已经出现在屏幕上。
But that array is going to come back to bite us.
但那个数组会回来咬我们。
Because if you only have a capacity of 50,
因为如果你只有 50 个容量，
what happens if 51 people want cookies next time?
如果下次有 51 个人想要饼干怎么办？
You just don't have room for them even though, clearly, we have
你根本没有空间容纳他们，尽管很明显，我们有
enough room for the people themselves.
足够的空间容纳这些人。
We have enough memory.
我们有足够的内存。
So it seems a little shortsighted to limit just how much data
所以，限制数据结构中可以容纳多少数据似乎有点目光短浅。
can fit in our data structures.
可以容纳在我们数据结构中。
So with that said, a friend of ours, Shannon Duvall at Elon University,
话虽如此，我们的一位朋友，艾伦大学的香农·杜瓦尔，
kindly put together a visualization of the same.
好心地将同样的内容可视化。
And allow me to introduce you to two fellows known as Jack and Lou.
现在让我向大家介绍两位名叫杰克和卢的家伙。
If we could dim the lights for this video.
如果可以的话，请为这个视频调暗灯光。
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
[视频播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
- Once upon a time, there was a guy named Jack.
从前，有个名叫杰克的家伙。
When it came to making friends, Jack did not have the knack.
说到交朋友，杰克没有天赋。
So Jack went to talk to the most popular guy he knew.
于是杰克去和一个他认识的最受欢迎的人聊天。
He went up to Lou and asked what do I do?
他走到卢身边问：“我该怎么办？”
Lou saw that his friend was really distressed.
卢看到他的朋友真的很痛苦。
Well, Lou began, just look how you're dressed.
“嗯，”卢开始说，“看看你穿的衣服。”
Don't you have any clothes with a different look?
“你没有穿不同风格的衣服吗？”
Yes, said Jack.
“有，”杰克说。
I sure do.
“当然有。”
Come to my house and I'll show them to you.
“来我家，我给你看看。”
So they went off to Jack's.
于是他们去了杰克的家。
And Jack showed Lou the box where he kept all his shirts
杰克给卢看一个箱子，里面放着他的所有衬衫
and his pants and his socks.
还有他的裤子和袜子。
Lou said, I see you have all your clothes in a pile.
卢说：“我看到你把所有的衣服都堆在一起。”
Why don't you wear some others once in a while?
“为什么你不时地换着穿？”
Jack said, well, when I remove clothes and socks,
杰克说：“嗯，当我脱掉衣服和袜子时，
I wash them and put them away in the box.
我会洗掉它们，然后放回箱子里。”
Then comes the next morning, and up I hop.
“然后第二天早上，我就跳起来。”
I go to the box and get my clothes off the top.
“我走到箱子旁边，从上面拿衣服。”
Lou quickly realized the problem with Jack.
卢很快就意识到杰克的问题所在。
He kept clothes, CDs, and books in a stack.
他把衣服、CD 和书堆在一起。
When he reached for something to read or to wear,
当他伸手去拿东西阅读或穿着时，
he chose the top book or underwear.
他选择了最上面的书或内衣。
Then when he was done, he would put it right back.
然后当他做完后，他会把它放回去。
Back it would go on top of the stack.
它又回到了堆顶。
I know the solution, said the triumphant Lou.
“我知道解决办法，”卢得意地说。
You need to learn to start using a queue.
你需要学习如何开始使用队列。
Lou took Jack's clothes and hung them in a closet.
Lou拿走了Jack的衣服，把它们挂在壁橱里。
And when he had emptied the box, he just tossed it.
当他清空了盒子后，他就把它扔了。
Then he said now, Jack, at the end of the day, put your clothes on the left
然后他说，Jack，在一天结束的时候，把你的衣服放在左边
when you put them away.
当你收纳的时候。
Then tomorrow morning when you see the sun
那么明天早上，当你看到太阳
shine, get your clothes from the right from the end of the line.
照耀的时候，从队列的末端，从右边拿你的衣服。
Don't you see, said Lou?
“你不明白吗，”Lou说。
It will be so nice.
这会很棒。
You'll wear everything once before you wear something twice.
在你第二次穿之前，你就会把所有东西都穿一遍。
And with everything in queues in his closet and shelf,
而随着壁橱和架子上所有东西都排成队列，
Jack started to feel quite sure of himself all thanks
Jack开始对自己非常有信心，这都要归功于
to Lou and his wonderful queue.
Lou和他的神奇队列。
[END PLAYBACK]
[播放结束]
DAVID J. MALAN: So the same--
DAVID J. MALAN：所以是一样的——
wonderful, thanks to Shannon--
很棒，感谢Shannon——
so you might have noticed I wear black all the time
所以你可能已经注意到我总是穿黑色
so we could make a similar gag about here's what my stack of clothes at home
所以我们可以做个类似的笑话，这就是我在家里的衣服堆的样子
looks.
看起来。
Even though I might own a blue and a red sweatshirt,
尽管我可能有一件蓝色和一件红色运动衫，
it doesn't really work if you're popping everything from a stack every time,
如果你每次都从堆栈中弹出所有东西，这实际上是行不通的，
cleaning it, replenishing the blacks sweaters before the red or the blue
清洁它，在红色或蓝色运动衫之前补充黑色运动衫
even get popped themselves.
甚至自己也弹出。
But we're going to focus today not just on stacks and queues
但今天我们将重点关注的不只是堆栈和队列
which for us are really meant to motivate
这对我们来说真的旨在激励
different ways of designing data even though the implementation details might
不同的数据设计方式，即使实现细节可能
differ.
有所不同。
But we're going to start focusing on solving some problems
但我们将开始专注于解决一些问题
that invariably we'd be bumping up against anyway as we
不可避免地，我们会在开发过程中遇到这些问题
develop more and more real world software, not just
开发越来越多的现实世界软件，而不仅仅是
smaller programs as in class.
课堂上的小型程序。
And arrays, recall, are what?
数组，还记得，是什么？
What's the key characteristic or definition
数组的关键特征或定义是什么？
of an array with respect to your computer's memory
数组与计算机内存相关的
and storing things in it?
以及在其中存储事物？
Yeah?
是吗？
AUDIENCE: It stores the data contiguously.
观众：它连续存储数据。
DAVID J. MALAN: Perfect.
DAVID J. MALAN：完美。
So it stores the data contiguously back to back to back.
所以它连续存储数据，一个接一个。
And as we've seen thus far, when you allocate space for an array,
正如我们迄今为止所看到的，当你为数组分配空间时，
you typically do it with square brackets.
你通常用方括号来做。
You specify a number in those brackets or maybe a constant,
你在方括号中指定一个数字，或者是一个常量，
like capacity, like I just did.
比如容量，就像我刚才做的那样。
And that fixates just how much data you can actually store in there.
这会固定你实际上可以存储多少数据。
We did see last week, though, that we could
不过我们上周看到了，我们可以
start to use malloc to allocate an equivalent number of bytes.
开始使用malloc来分配相同数量的字节。
But even that, when you call it just once,
但即使这样，当你只调用它一次时，
gives you back a specific finite number of bytes.
它会返回一个特定的有限数量的字节。
So you're similarly deciding in advance how much memory you
因此，你同样要提前决定可以存储多少内存
can store in an array.
在一个数组中。
So let's consider what kinds of problems this could get us into.
那么让我们考虑一下这可能会导致什么问题。
So here's an array of size three.
这是一个大小为 3 的数组。
And suppose for the sake of discussion we've
为了便于讨论，假设我们已经
already put three numbers into it 1, 2, and 3 literally.
将 1、2 和 3 这三个数字放入了其中。
Suppose now we want to add a fourth number to that array.
现在假设我们想在这个数组中添加第四个数字。
Well, where does it go?
那么它应该放在哪里呢？
Intuitively and pictorially, you'd like to think it could go there.
从直觉和图像上来说，你可能想把它放在那里。
But remember the context we introduced last week when
但请记住我们上周介绍的关于
we talked about computers' memories.
计算机内存的内容。
There's lots of stuff going on.
有很多事情正在发生。
And if you only ask the computer, the operating system,
如果你只询问计算机，操作系统，
room for three integers, who knows what's here and here and here,
只有三个整数的空间，谁知道这里，这里和这里是什么？
not to mention everywhere else on the screen?
更不用说屏幕上的其他地方了？
So if we zoom out for instance, we might like to put the number four there.
所以，如果我们放大来看，我们可能想把数字 4 放在那里。
But we can't if in that greater context there's a lot more stuff going on.
但我们不能，因为在更大的环境中，还有更多的事情正在发生。
So for instance, suppose that elsewhere in my same program or function
例如，假设在我的同一个程序或函数中的其他地方
I've already created a string like H-E-L-L-O, comma, space, world,
我已经创建了一个字符串，例如 H-E-L-L-O, 逗号, 空格, world,
backslash 0.
反斜杠 0。
Just by bad luck, that could be allocated right next to my 1, 2, 3.
不幸的是，它可能被分配到我的 1、2、3 的旁边。
Why?
为什么？
Well, if I ask the operating system for space for three numbers,
好吧，如果我向操作系统请求三个数字的空间，
then I ask the operating system for space for a string,
然后我向操作系统请求一个字符串的空间，
it's pretty reasonable for the computer to put those things back to back,
计算机将这些东西放在一起是相当合理的，
because it's not going to anticipate for us that, well, maybe they actually want
因为它不会为我们预先判断，嗯，也许他们实际上想要
four numbers eventually or five numbers or more.
最终要四个数字，或者五个数字，或者更多。
Now, as for all of these Oscars the Grouch,
现在，至于这些奥斯卡·葛鲁奇，
that's just meant to represent pictorially
这仅仅是图像化地表示
here the notion of garbage values.
这里垃圾值的概念。
There's clearly other bytes there and available.
这里明显还有其他字节可用。
I don't know what it is.
我不知道它是什么。
And I don't care what it is.
我并不关心它是什么。
But I do care that I can't just presume to put something right where
但我确实关心，我不能只是假定把东西放在
I want in the computer's memory unless I preemptively ask it for more memory.
我希望在计算机内存中的位置，除非我提前请求更多内存。
Now, if all of those are garbage values, which
现在，如果所有这些都是垃圾值，也就是
is to say that who cares what they are-- it's just junk left over
也就是说，谁在乎它们是什么——这只是之前函数运行时剩下的垃圾——
from previous runs of the function or the like--
来自之前函数运行的类似情况——
there's clearly plenty of room for a fourth number.
明显还有很多空间可以放第四个数字。
I could put the number four here or here or here or down here or here or here.
我可以把数字 4 放在这里，或者这里，或者这里，或者这里，或者这里，或者这里。
But why would I not want to just plop the four wherever
但是，为什么我不想把 4 直接放在
there is a garbage value currently?
现在有垃圾值的地方呢？
Yeah?
是吗？
AUDIENCE: Because you want it to be next to your array of 1, 2, 3.
观众：因为您希望它位于您的 1、2、3 数组旁边。
DAVID J. MALAN: Exactly, I want it to be next to my array of 1,
大卫·马兰：没错，我希望它在我的 1 数组旁边，
2, 3 because, again, arrays must be and must remain contiguous.
2、3 数组，因为，再次强调，数组必须是，并且必须保持连续。
Now, that's not a deal breaker because where else could I
现在，这并不是一个决定性的问题，因为我还能把
put maybe the entire array?
整个数组放在哪里呢？
Well, there's room up here for four numbers.
嗯，这里有足够的空间放四个数字。
There's room down here for four numbers.
这里还有空间可以放四个数字。
So that's fine.
所以这很好。
And that could be a solution to the problem.
这可以成为问题的解决方案。
If you've run out of space in your fixed size array,
如果你在固定大小的数组中用完了空间，
well maybe I just abstract everything else away,
也许我可以将其他所有内容抽象出来，
and I just move my array to a different location that's a little bit bigger.
然后将我的数组移动到一个更大的位置。
But there is going to be a downside.
但这样做也会有缺点。
Even though this is a solution, even though I can certainly
即使这是一个解决方案，即使我肯定可以
copy the 1, the 2, the 3-- and now I can plop the 4 there.
复制 1、2、3，现在我可以把 4 放到那里。
And, heck, I can then let go of the old memory in some way
而且，我可以以某种方式释放旧内存
and give it back to the operating system to be reused later.
并将其返还给操作系统以便稍后重用。
This is successful.
这是成功的。
But why intuitively might we not want this
但从直觉上讲，我们为什么不希望
to be our solution of creating a new array that's a little bigger,
成为我们的解决方案，即创建一个更大的新数组，
copying the old into the new, and getting rid of the old?
将旧的复制到新的中，并丢弃旧的？
Good, yeah, I think I had one more step.
好的，是的，我认为我还有一个步骤。
Suppose I want to add a fifth number, a sixth number.
假设我想添加第五个数字、第六个数字。
That's a lot of work.
那可是很多工作。
And, in fact, what's the expensive part or what's the slow part of that story?
实际上，那个故事中哪个部分最昂贵，哪个部分最慢？
Yeah?
对吧？
AUDIENCE: It takes a lot of time.
观众：这需要很多时间。
DAVID J. MALAN: It takes a lot of time.
大卫·马兰：这需要很多时间。
But specifically, what's taking time if we can put our finger on it?
具体来说，如果我们能指出的话，是什么在占用时间？
Yeah, in the back?
对，在后面的人？
AUDIENCE: You're using twice as much.
观众：你使用了双倍的内存。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK, for a period of time,
大卫·马兰：好的，在一段时间内，
I'm using twice as much memory, which certainly seems wasteful
我使用了双倍的内存，这看起来确实很浪费
because even though I don't eventually need it, it is going to mushroom
因为即使我最终不需要它，它也会像蘑菇一样疯长
and then shrink back down, which seems like an inefficient use of resources.
然后缩小，这似乎是一种低效的资源使用方式。
But what specifically is slow about this process too?
但具体来说，这个过程的哪些方面也很慢呢？
Yeah, in the middle.
对，中间的人。
AUDIENCE: You're iterating through the original array to copy it over.
观众：你在遍历原始数组以将其复制过去。
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, good choice of words.
大卫·马兰：是的，用词很好。
You're iterating over the array to copy it over using a for loop, a while loop.
你正在使用 for 循环或 while 循环遍历数组以将其复制过去。
So it's probably like big O of n steps just
所以这可能就像大 O 的 n 步
to copy the array and technically big O of n plus 1 if we had one more.
来复制数组，从技术上讲，如果我们再多一个的话，就是大 O 的 n 加 1。
But that's still big O of n.
但那仍然是大 O 的 n。
So it's the copying, the moving of the data, so to speak,
所以说，它是复制，移动数据，
that's certainly correct.
这当然没错。
But maybe it's not the best design.
但也许这不是最好的设计。
Wouldn't it be better if we could do something otherwise?
如果我们可以做些别的事，会不会更好？
Well, let's consider what this might actually translate into in code
好吧，让我们考虑一下这实际上如何在代码中体现
and what the implications then might be.
以及由此可能带来的影响。
Let me switch over here to VS Code.
让我切换到 VS Code。
Let me propose to open up a file called list.c brand new.
我建议打开一个名为 list.c 的全新文件。
And let's create this list of numbers and then add to it over time
让我们创建一个数字列表，然后随着时间的推移不断添加内容
and see when and where we actually bump up against these problems.
然后看看我们何时何地会遇到这些问题。
So let me include standard io.h in order to simply
所以，让我包含 standard io.h，以便简单地
be able to print things out ultimately, int main void, so no need
最终能够打印出内容，int main void，所以不需要
for command line arguments here.
在这里使用命令行参数。
Let me give myself an array called list just of size 3
让我给自己一个叫做list的数组，大小为3
for consistency with the picture thus far.
为了与迄今为止的图片保持一致。
And now let me go ahead and just manually
现在让我继续手动
make it look like in memory what it did on the screen.
让它在内存中看起来像它在屏幕上所做的那样。
So list bracket 0 is going to equal to number 1.
所以 list 中括号 0 将等于数字 1。
List bracket 1 is going to equal the number 2.
List 中括号 1 将等于数字 2。
And list bracket 2 equals number three.
而 list 中括号 2 等于数字 3。
So even though the array is, of course, zero indexed,
所以即使数组是零索引的，当然，
I'm using more familiar 1, 2, 3 as my digits here.
我在这里使用更熟悉的 1, 2, 3 作为我的数字。
Now, suppose I want to print these things out.
现在，假设我想打印出这些东西。
Let's just do something as a simple exercise.
让我们做一个简单的练习。
So for int i equals 0, i is less than 3 i plus plus.
所以对于 int i 等于 0，i 小于 3 i 加加。
Inside of this loop, I'm going to do something simple like print
在这个循环中，我将做一些简单的打印
out iteratively, as you note, backslash n list bracket i.
迭代地输出，正如你所见，反斜杠 n list 中括号 i。
So very simple program.
一个非常简单的程序。
It's not the best design because I've got this magic number there.
这不是最好的设计，因为我在这里有一个神奇的数字。
I'm hard coding the 3.
我硬编码了 3。
But the point is just to go through the motions
但重点是只是走过这些动作
of demonstrating how this code works.
来演示这段代码是如何工作的。
Good, you got it in before I hit compile.
很好，你在我点击编译之前完成了。
So wait.
所以等等。
Thank you.
谢谢。
All right.
好的。
Maybe round of applause.
也许掌声。
Thank you.
谢谢。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
All right.
好的。
All right, so this is going to get aggressive, though, eventually.
好的，所以这最终会变得咄咄逼人。
So let me add the semicolon.
所以让我加上分号。
Let me recompile this list.
让我重新编译这个列表。
Seems to compile OK.
似乎编译正常。
And if I do ./list, I should see, of course, 1, 2, 3.
如果我执行 ./list，我当然应该看到 1, 2, 3。
So the code works.
所以代码有效。
There's no memory constraints here because I'm not
这里没有内存限制，因为我没有
trying to actually add some values.
试图实际添加一些值。
But let me consider how I could go about implementing this idea of copying
但让我考虑如何实现这个复制的想法
everything from the old array to the new array,
将所有内容从旧数组复制到新数组，
frankly, just to see how annoying it is, how painful it is.
坦率地说，只是为了看看它有多烦人，有多痛苦。
So you're about to see the code escalate quickly.
所以你将看到代码迅速升级。
And it will be helpful to try to wrap your mind around each individual step
并且尝试理解每一个步骤将会有所帮助
even though if you take a step back, it's
即使你退一步，它也是
going to look like a crazy amount of code to solve a simple idea.
看起来像是为了解决一个简单的想法而写了大量的代码。
But that's the point.
但这就是重点。
We're going to get to a place, particularly in week 6
我们将到达一个地方，尤其是在第六周
where all of what we're about to do reduces to one line of code.
我们即将要做的事情将简化为一行代码。
So hang in there for now.
所以现在坚持住。
So let me go ahead and do this.
所以让我继续做这件事。
If I want to create a version of this code that can grow to fit more numbers,
如果我想创建一个可以扩展以容纳更多数字的代码版本，
for instance, how can I go about doing this or at least demonstrate as much?
例如，我该怎么做呢？或者至少演示一下？
Well, I cannot use an array in this traditional way of using square
好吧，我不能用这种传统的用方括号的方式来使用数组。
brackets because that makes list, the variable, forever of size 3.
因为那样会使变量 list 永久地成为大小为 3 的列表。
I can't free it.
我不能释放它。
Remember free you can only use with malloc.
记住，free 只能与 malloc 一起使用。
So you can't give it back and then recreate it using this syntax.
所以你不能将它归还，然后使用这种语法重新创建它。
But I can use this trick from last time, whereby,
但我可以用上次的这个技巧，即
if I know there is this function called malloc, whose purpose in life
如果我知道有一个叫做 malloc 的函数，它的作用是
is to give me memory, I could, for instance re-declare
为我分配内存，我可以例如重新声明
list to be a pointer so to speak that is the address of a chunk of memory.
list 为一个指针，它指向一块内存的地址。
And I could ask malloc for a chunk of memory namely of size 3 but not 3
我可以向 malloc 请求一块内存，大小为 3，但不是 3
per se, three integers for good measure.
本身，而是三个整数，以确保充足。
So technically that's three times the size of whatever an int is.
因此，从技术上讲，这相当于 int 大小的三倍。
Now, for our purposes today, that's technically 3 times 4 or 12.
现在，对于我们今天的目的，从技术上讲，这是 3 乘以 4 或 12。
But I'm trying to do this very generally in case we use it
但我试图以一种非常普遍的方式来做这件事，以防我们使用它
on an old computer or maybe a future computer, where the size of an int
在旧电脑上，或者可能是未来的电脑上，int 的大小
might very well change.
可能会有很大变化。
That's why I'm using size of int.
这就是我使用 sizeof(int) 的原因。
It will tell me always the correct answer for my computer.
它将始终告诉我我的计算机的正确答案。
So to use malloc--
所以要使用 malloc--
not going to catch me on this one-- what header file do I need to add?
不会抓到我的--我需要添加什么头文件？
Standard?
标准？
AUDIENCE: Standard lib.h.
听众：stdlib.h。
DAVID J. MALAN: Standard lib.h.
大卫·J·马兰：stdlib.h。
So I'm going to go ahead and include standard lib.h, which
所以我会继续包含 stdlib.h，它
gives me access to malloc.
让我可以访问 malloc。
And what I'm going to additionally do is practice what I preach last week,
另外，我要练习上周我所讲的，
whereby in extreme cases malloc can return not the address
即在极端情况下，malloc 可能返回的不是地址
of an actual chunk of memory.
而是一块实际的内存。
What else can malloc return in cases of error?
在出错的情况下，malloc 还可以返回什么？
Yeah?
对吗？
AUDIENCE: Null.
听众：NULL。
DAVID J. MALAN: Null, N-U-L-L in all caps,
大卫·J·马兰：NULL，全部大写，
which represents technically address 0.
它在技术上代表地址 0。
But you're never supposed to use address 0.
但你永远不应该使用地址 0。
So it's a special sentinel value that just means something went wrong.
所以它是一个特殊的哨兵值，表示出现错误。
Do not proceed.
不要继续。
So it's going to add some bulk to my code.
所以它会给我的代码增加一些负担。
But it is good practice.
但这是个好习惯。
So if list at this point actually equals equals null,
所以如果此时的 list 实际上等于 NULL，
there's no more work to be done here.
这里就不用再做任何工作了。
I've got to abort the demo altogether.
我必须完全中止演示。
So I'm going to return 1 just arbitrarily
所以我会随意返回 1
to say we're done with this exercise.
表示我们完成了这个练习。
It's not going to be germane for class.
这对课堂来说并不重要。
We can surely find room for three integers but best practice
我们肯定能找到容纳三个整数的空间，但最好的做法是
whenever using malloc.
在使用 malloc 的时候。
Now, this code here does not need to change because list is now still
现在，这里的代码不需要改变，因为 list 仍然是
a chunk of memory of size 12, I can actually
一块大小为 12 的内存，我可以实际上
get away with still using square bracket notation
仍然可以使用方括号表示法
and treating this chunk of memory as though it's an array.
并将这块内存视为数组。
And this is a bit subtle.
这有点微妙。
But recall from last time, we talked briefly about pointer arithmetic,
但回想一下上次，我们简要讨论了指针运算，
whereby the computer can do some arithmetic, some addition, subtraction
计算机可以在实际地址上进行一些运算，一些加法、减法
on the actual addresses to get from one location to the other.
以从一个位置移动到另一个位置。
And that's what the computer is going to do here.
这就是计算机在这里要做的。
Because it says list bracket 0, that's essentially
因为它说列表方括号 0，这本质上
just going to put the number 1 literally at the beginning
只是将数字 1 放在这块内存的开头
of that chunk of memory.
。
And because this is a modern computer, it's going to take four bytes in total.
而且因为这是一台现代计算机，它将总共占用 4 个字节。
But I don't want to put the number 4 here to shift it over myself.
但我不想在这里放数字 4 来自己把它移过去。
Because I'm using square brackets and because the computer
因为我使用方括号，并且因为计算机
knows that this chunk of memory is being treated
知道这块内存被视为
as a chunk of addresses of integers, pointer arithmetic magically kicks in.
一组整数的地址，指针运算就会神奇地启动。
So what the computer is going to do for me is put this 1 at location 0.
所以计算机将为我做的就是把这个 1 放到位置 0。
It's going to put this number 2 at location 1 times size of int, so 4.
它将把这个数字 2 放到位置 1 乘以 int 的大小，也就是 4。
And it's going to put this number 3 at location 2 times
它将把这个数字 3 放到位置 2 乘以
size of int, which gives me 8.
int 的大小，这给我 8。
So in other words, you don't have to think
换句话说，你不需要考虑
about how big that chunk of memory is if you already gave the compiler a clue as
这块内存有多大，如果你已经给编译器一个线索，
to the size.
大小。
For our purposes today, don't worry too much about that.
就我们今天而言，不必太担心。
The bigger takeaway is that when you allocate space using malloc,
更大的收获是，当你使用 malloc 分配空间时，
you can certainly treat it as though it's
你当然可以把它当作
an array using week 2 notation, which is arguably simpler than using
使用第 2 周的符号表示的数组，这可以说比使用
dots and stars and all of that.
点和星号以及所有这些更简单。
But this isn't quite enough now because let
但这现在还不够，因为让
me stipulate that for the sake of discussion,
我规定，为了讨论起见，
at this point in time here on line 16, where the cursor is blinking,
此时，在第 16 行，光标正在闪烁，
suppose I realize just for the sake of discussion,
假设我意识到，为了讨论起见，
oh, I should have allocated space for four integers instead of three.
哦，我应该为四个整数分配空间，而不是三个。
Now, obviously, if I were writing this for real,
现在，很明显，如果我是真的在写这个，
I should just go fix the code now and recompile it altogether?
我应该现在就去修复代码并重新编译它？
But let's just pretend for the sake of discussion
但让我们假设，为了讨论起见，
that somewhere in your program you want to dynamically allocate more space
在你的程序中的某个地方，你想要动态地分配更多的空间
and free up the old in order to implement this idea of copying
并释放旧的，以实现这个复制的想法
from old to new memory.
从旧内存到新内存。
So how could I do that?
那我该怎么做呢？
Well, let me go ahead and temporarily give myself another chunk of memory.
好吧，让我先给自己再分配一块内存。
And I'm going to literally call it tmp for short,
我将把它简称为 tmp，
which is a common convention, tmp.
这是一个常见的约定，tmp。
I'm going to set that equal to the amount of space
我将把它设置为我现在真正需要的空间大小。
that I actually do now want.
。
So I'm to say four times the size of an int.
所以我要说四倍于 int 的大小。
So technically it'll give me 16 but space for four integers this time.
所以从技术上讲，它会给我 16，但这次是四个整数的空间。
And what that's doing for me in code is essentially
在代码中，它基本上是
trying to find me space for four integers elsewhere
尝试在其他地方为我找到四个整数的空间
that might very well be garbage values now.
这些值现在很可能都是垃圾值。
But I can, therefore, reuse them.
但因此我可以重用它们。
So once I've done this, something could still go wrong.
所以，一旦我做完这件事，仍然可能出现问题。
And I could check if temp equals equals null,
我可以检查 temp 是否等于 null，
then actually I should exit altogether and finish up.
然后我应该完全退出并结束。
But there's a subtlety here.
但这里有一个微妙之处。
And you don't need to dwell too much on this for today.
今天你不必太关注这一点。
But there is technically a bug right now.
但现在技术上确实存在一个 bug。
Why based on week 4, last week, might it not be correct technically
为什么根据上周的第 4 周，技术上来说它可能不正确
to immediately return 1 and abort the program altogether at this point?
立即返回 1 并完全中止程序？
AUDIENCE: I think when you allocate memory sometimes it has garbage values.
观众：我认为当你分配内存时，有时它会包含垃圾值。
DAVID J. MALAN: OK, so when you allocate memory,
大卫·马兰：好的，所以当你分配内存时，
sometimes there might be garbage values there that is true.
有时那里可能会有垃圾值，这是真的。
But that is to say that those 16 bytes might be garbage values,
但也就是说，这 16 个字节可能是垃圾值，
have Oscar the grouch's all on the screen.
屏幕上全是奥斯卡·格鲁奇。
But tmp itself will literally be the return value of malloc.
但 tmp 本身实际上将是 malloc 的返回值。
And malloc will always return to you the address of a valid chunk of memory.
而 malloc 总是会返回一个有效内存块的地址给你。
Or it will return null.
或者它会返回 null。
So this line is actually OK.
所以这行代码实际上是 ok 的。
What I don't love is that I'm returning 1 immediately.
我不喜欢的是我立即返回 1。
AUDIENCE: I think [INAUDIBLE].
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Yes, so this is where it's subtle.
大卫·马兰：是的，所以这里很微妙。
It's not quite right to just abort right now and return 1.
现在就中止并返回 1 并不完全正确。
Why?
为什么？
Because up here, remember, a few moments ago
因为在上面，请记住，几分钟前
we used malloc presumably successfully.
我们使用了 malloc，推测成功了。
Because if we got all the way down here, we did not abort on line 9.
因为如果我们一直走到这里，我们没有在第 9 行中止。
So we kept going.
所以我们继续运行。
But that means we've allocated three times size event, so 12 bytes earlier.
但这意味着我们已经分配了三倍大小的事件，所以之前分配了 12 个字节。
So frankly, if you compile this code, run it, and then ask Valgrind,
所以坦率地说，如果你编译这段代码，运行它，然后询问 Valgrind，
it's going to identify a memory leak of size 12 because, as you know,
它将识别出大小为 12 的内存泄漏，因为，如你所知，
we did not free the original memory.
我们没有释放原始内存。
So this is where frankly C does get a little annoying because you and I
所以，坦率地说，C 在这里有点烦人，因为你和我都
as the programmers have to remember all of these details.
作为程序员必须记住所有这些细节。
So what I really want to do here, before I return 1, to be best practice,
所以，为了最佳实践，在我返回 1 之前，我真正想做的是
I want to free the original list.
我想释放原始列表。
So I give back those bytes to the operating system.
所以我把那些字节还给操作系统。
Now, as an aside, technically when any program quits, all of the memory
现在，顺便说一下，从技术上讲，当任何程序退出时，所有的内存
is going to be given back to the operating system.
都将被归还给操作系统。
But practicing what I'm preaching now will get you into better situations
但现在练习我正在宣扬的东西将让你处于更好的境地
later.
以后。
Because if you don't free up memory, you will have leaks.
因为如果你不释放内存，你就会有泄漏。
And that's when our own Macs and PCs tend
而当我们的 Mac 和 PC 倾向于
to start to slow down and use up more memory than they should.
开始变慢并使用比它们应该更多的内存。
But let's avoid discussion of more error checking there.
但让我们避免在那里讨论更多错误检查。
Let's just assume that now I'm on line 23
让我们假设我现在在程序的第 23 行
of this program, whereby I have presumably successfully allocated
在这个程序中，我可能已经成功分配了
enough space.
足够的内存空间。
So the next step after allocating these four bytes is to, as you noted earlier,
所以，在分配完这四个字节之后，下一步是，就像你之前提到的，
iteratively copy the old numbers into the new space.
迭代地将旧数字复制到新的内存空间中。
So this is actually pretty straightforward.
其实这很简单。
I'm going to go ahead.
我会继续进行。
And for int i gets 0, i is less than 3 i plus plus just
然后对于 int i 等于 0，i 小于 3，i 加加，就像
like I was printing last time.
我上次打印的那样。
I'm going to go ahead and set the i-th location of temp
我会继续设置 temp 的第 i 个位置
equal to the i-th location of list, semicolon.
等于 list 的第 i 个位置，分号。
And that's it.
就这样。
I'm just copying into the temporary array whatever was in the old array.
我只是将旧数组中的内容复制到临时数组中。
But that still leaves me with this fourth byte, of course--
当然，这样一来我仍然会剩下这个第四个字节，
or, sorry, this fourth location, where I want to put the number 4.
或者说，抱歉，这个第四个位置，我想在这里放置数字 4。
But if I'm going to do that for the sake of discussion
但为了讨论起见，如果我要这样做
even though this isn't really a compelling real world program,
即使这并不是一个真正令人信服的现实世界程序，
I'm going to just manually go into the last location in tmp, a.k.a.
我将手动进入 tmp 中的最后一个位置，也就是
tmp bracket 3 and set that equal to my fourth number.
tmp 中的方括号 3，并将其设置为我的第四个数字。
So that's all.
就这样。
The whole point here is to mimic in code what it was we wanted to do here.
这里的主要目的是在代码中模仿我们想要在这里做的事情。
But now there's one more step.
但现在还有一步。
What was the next step after copying the 1, the 2, the 3, and adding the 4?
在复制 1、2、3，并添加 4 之后，下一步是什么？
What do I want to do?
我想做什么？
Now, I can safely free the list.
现在，我可以安全地释放 list。
Now I want to go ahead and get rid of the original memory
现在我想继续摆脱原来的内存
or at least hand it back to the operating system.
或者至少将其还给操作系统。
So here is where I can free the list, not in the case of an error
所以，在这里我可以释放 list，而不是在出现错误的情况下
but actually deliberately free the original list because I
而是故意释放原来的 list，因为我
don't need those 12 bytes anymore.
不再需要这 12 个字节了。
But now if I want to really have quote, unquote list
但现在，如果我想真正拥有所谓的 list
point at this new chunk of memory, well, then I could also do this,
指向这块新的内存，那么我也可以这样做，
list equals temp.
list 等于 temp。
So this is a little weird.
所以这有点奇怪。
But recall that list has just now been freed.
但请记住，list 现在刚刚被释放了。
So even though list technically contains the address of a chunk of memory,
因此，即使 list 技术上包含一块内存的地址，
it's no longer valid because, again, it was freed.
它不再有效了，因为，再次强调，它已经被释放了。
So, yes, it's still technically there.
所以，是的，它在技术上仍然存在。
But it's effectively garbage values now.
但它实际上现在是垃圾值了。
So I'm certainly free--
所以我当然可以自由地
no pun intended.
没有双关语的意思。
I'm certainly allowed to update the value of list.
我当然可以更新 list 的值。
And I want list to now point to the new chunk of memory.
我想让 list 现在指向这块新的内存。
So sort of metaphorically, if list was originally
所以，打个比方，如果 list 最初
pointing at a chunk of memory there, maybe now I want it to point over here.
指向那里的某一块内存，也许现在我想让它指向这里。
So I'm just updating the value of list ultimately.
所以，我最终只是更新了 list 的值。
All right, now that I've got this all done,
好了，现在我完成了这一切，
I think I can just use this same loop as before.
我想我可以继续使用之前相同的循环。
I could change the 3 to a 4 because I now have four numbers.
我可以把 3 改成 4，因为我现在有四个数字了。
At the very bottom of this program though, also subtle,
不过在这个程序的最底部，也比较微妙，
I should probably now at the very end free this list.
我应该在最后释放这个列表。
And for good measure, let me go ahead and return 0.
为了确保万无一失，我返回 0。
But now I think I have a complete program that, again,
但我认为现在我已经编写了一个完整的程序，再次强调，
to be clear is not how you would write this in the real world
这并不是你实际编程中写代码的方式
because you would not allocate three integers then
因为你不会先分配三个整数，
decide you want to allocate four then fix all of this.
然后决定要分配四个，再修复所有这些东西。
But we could probably borrow, copy and paste
但我们可以借用、复制和粘贴
some of this code into production code eventually, whereby this would
一些代码到生产代码中，这样一来，它将
solve some actual problems dynamically.
动态地解决一些实际问题。
So let me cross my fingers, make list.
所以，我祈祷一下，生成列表。
So far so good, ./list.
目前看来还不错，./list。
And I should see 1, 2, 3, 4.
我应该看到 1、2、3、4。
So long story short, it's a lot of work just to get from the original array
简而言之，从原始数组到第二个数组，需要做很多工作
to the second.
到第二个数组。
So ideally, we would not do any of this in the first place.
理想情况下，我们一开始就不应该做任何这些事情。
Ideally, what could we do instead?
理想情况下，我们应该怎么做呢？
Well, maybe we should just allocate more memory
好吧，也许我们应该分配更多的内存
from the get go in order to avoid this problem altogether.
从一开始就分配更多的内存，以完全避免这个问题。
So how might I do that?
那么我该如何做到呢？
Well, instead of having allocated an array of size 3, let alone an array
嗯，与其分配一个大小为 3 的数组，更不用说一个大小为 4 的数组了
of size 4, why don't I just proactively from the beginning of my program
为什么我不能从程序一开始就主动分配一个大小为 30、甚至 300 或 3000 的数组呢？
allocate an array of size 30 or heck 300 or 3,000
分配一个大小为 30 的数组，甚至 300 或 3000 的数组
and then just keep track of how much of it I'm using?
然后跟踪使用了多少内存？
That would be correct.
那是正确的。
It would solve the problem of not painting yourself into a corner
它将解决你没有把自己逼入绝境的问题
so quickly.
如此迅速地。
But what remains as an issue?
但仍然存在一个问题？
AUDIENCE: You're using a lot of memory.
观众：你正在使用大量的内存。
DAVID J. MALAN: I'm using a bunch more memory.
大卫·J·马兰：我正在使用更多内存。
Especially if this program's only going to ever manage a few numbers,
尤其如果这个程序只会管理几个数字，
why are you wasting 100 times more memory than you might actually?
为什么浪费实际需要的 100 倍内存呢？
And there's an another corner case that could still arise
还有一个极端情况仍然可能出现，
even though this solves the problem.
即使这解决了问题。
AUDIENCE: If you add another list, you'll run out of memory.
观众：如果你添加另一个列表，你就会内存不足。
DAVID J. MALAN: Exactly, we can eventually
大卫·J·马兰：没错，最终我们仍然
still run into the exact same problem because if I
会遇到同样的问题，因为如果我想
want to put 301 numbers in the list or 3,001, well,
把 301 个数字或 3001 个数字放到列表中，那么，
I'm still going to have to jump through all of these hoops
我仍然需要经历所有这些步骤
and reallocate all of that space.
并重新分配所有那些空间。
And, honestly, now per year concern about the looping, iterating 300 times
而且，说实话，现在每年的关注点是循环，300 次循环，
3,000 times is certainly eventually going
3000 次循环，最终肯定
to start to add up if we're doing it a lot in terms of speed and slowdown.
如果我们经常这样做，就会开始累积，从而导致速度下降。
So maybe there's a better way altogether than doing this.
所以，也许有更好的方法，而不是这样做。
And indeed there is if we start to treat our computer's memory as a canvas
实际上是有更好的方法，如果我们开始将计算机的内存视为一个画布
that we can start to use to design data structures more generally.
我们可以开始使用它来更普遍地设计数据结构。
Arrays are a data structure, arguably.
数组可以说是一种数据结构。
They're super simple.
它们非常简单。
They're contiguous chunks of memory.
它们是内存中的连续块。
But we could use memory a little more cleverly, especially now per last week
但我们可以更巧妙地使用内存，尤其是在上周之后
that we have pointers, which is painful as they might
我们有了指针，虽然它们可能会
be to wrap your mind around sometimes.
让人难以理解。
They really just let us point to different places in memory.
它们只是让我们指向内存中的不同位置。
And so we can start to stitch things together in an interesting way.
所以我们可以开始以有趣的方式将事物拼接在一起。
So the only syntax we'll really need to do that to stitch things together
所以我们真正需要的语法就是将事物拼接在一起
in memory and build more interesting structures
在内存中并构建更有趣的数据结构
are these things, struct, which allows us to represent structs already.
就是这些东西，struct，它让我们可以表示结构体。
And we did this with persons.
我们用它来表示人。
And we played with this last time as well.
我们上次也玩过这个。
And we saw it already for queues and stacks.
我们已经看到过它用于队列和栈。
The dot operator, we haven't used it that much.
点运算符，我们没有使用过太多。
But recall that whenever you have a struct,
但请记住，每当您拥有一个结构体时，
you can go inside of it using the dot operator.
您可以使用点运算符进入结构体内部。
And we did that for a person, person.name and person.number
我们对人进行了这种操作，person.name 和 person.number
when we were implementing a very simple address book.
当我们实现一个非常简单的地址簿时。
The star was new last week.
星号是上周才出现的新符号。
And it can mean different things in different contexts.
它在不同的上下文中可以有不同的含义。
You use it when declaring a pointer.
您在声明指针时使用它。
But you also use it when dereferencing a pointer, to go there.
但您还在解引用指针时使用它，以到达该位置。
But just so you've seen it before, it actually
但为了您之前已经看到过，实际上
tends to be a little annoying, a little confusing to use star and dot together.
将星号和点一起使用可能会有点令人讨厌，有点令人困惑。
You might remember one example last week where in parentheses I
您可能还记得上周的一个例子，在括号中我
put star something.
放入了星号加某个东西。
And then I used a dot operator to go there and then go inside the structure.
然后我使用点运算符到达那里，然后进入结构体内部。
Long story short, we'll see today that you
长话短说，我们今天会看到，您可以
can combine simultaneous use of star and dot
同时使用星号和点
into something that actually looks like an arrow, something
成为看起来像箭头的某种东西，某种东西
that vaguely looks like a foam finger that might be pointing from one place
看起来有点像泡沫手指，它可能从一个地方
to another.
指向另一个地方。
So we'll see that actually in some code.
所以我们将在一些代码中看到这一点。
So where can we take this?
那么我们可以将它用到哪里呢？
Well, let's implement the first of these ideas, namely something that's
好吧，让我们实现这些想法中的第一个，即某种东西
very canonical in computing known as a linked list.
在计算中非常典型，被称为链表。
And let's see if we can maybe do this.
让我们看看我们是否可以做到这一点。
How about Scully, could we get you to come on up and volunteer here?
斯库利，你可以上来做志愿者吗？
So our friend Scully--
所以，我们的朋友斯库利--
there's some cookies in this for you.
这里有些饼干给你。
So Scully has come prepared with a whole bunch of balloons
斯库利准备了一堆气球
to represent chunks of memory because we'd like to paint a picture here
来代表内存块，因为我们想在这里画一幅图
of what's involved in actually allocating space that's not necessarily
描述实际分配空间的步骤，该空间不一定
contiguous and might be over there or over here or over here
是连续的，可能在那边，或者这边，或者这边
in the computer's memory.
在计算机内存中。
So, for instance, if I want to start allocating space
所以，例如，如果我想开始分配空间
one at a time for a list of numbers, Scully,
一次一个，给一个数字列表，Scully，
could you go ahead and malloc one balloon for me?
你能帮我分配一个气球吗？
And in this balloon I'll store for instance, the number one ultimately.
最终，我将在气球中存储数字 1。
So we have a balloon here.
所以这里有一个气球。
We rehearsed this before.
我们之前排练过。
And these balloons are actually really hard to blow up and tie off quickly.
这些气球实际上很难快速吹起来并系好。
So thank you.
谢谢。
So here we have a chunk of memory.
所以这里有一块内存。
And I could certainly for instance go in here and store if I might the--
我当然可以在这里存储，比如...
here we go.
来了。
I could certainly go ahead here and store in this balloon,
我当然可以在这里存储在这个气球中，
for instance, the number one.
比如数字 1。
But in the world of an array, it would just be back to back to back.
但在数组的世界里，它会紧挨着。
And actually, frankly, why do we need the balloons even?
实际上，坦白说，我们为什么还需要气球呢？
I could just use these numbers, 1, 2, 3.
我可以直接使用这些数字，1、2、3。
But the problem doesn't indeed arise note,
但问题确实出现了，请注意，
that when we want to put a fourth number, well where does it go?
当我们想要放一个第四个数字时，它会放在哪里？
Well, again, just to paint a picture, ideally I
好吧，再次为了说明，理想情况下我
might allocate space for four.
可能会为四个分配空间。
But if this is my array of size 3 like where does it go?
但如果这是一个大小为 3 的数组，它会放在哪里？
This is the point.
这就是重点。
We can't just put it next to the 3.
我们不能直接把它放在 3 旁边。
Maybe there's room for the 4 over here.
也许这里有空间放 4。
But we have to somehow connect these from one to the other.
但我们必须以某种方式将它们从一个连接到另一个。
So, in fact, let's act that out.
所以，实际上，让我们演绎一下。
So if I instead use this balloon metaphor of just allocating space
如果我用这个气球的比喻，只是分配空间，
from wherever it is, can you go ahead and allocate
无论在哪里，你能帮我分配
like another chunk of memory for me?
一块内存吗？
And here is where I'll now have a chunk of memory in which I can store
现在，这里有一块内存，我可以将数字存储在这里。
the number computers a little slow.
计算机有点慢。
So in here, the second balloon I'll have a separate chunk of memory.
所以在这里，在第二个气球里，我将拥有另一块独立的内存。
AUDIENCE: Oh my gosh.
观众：我的天哪。
DAVID J. MALAN: There we go.
大卫·J·马兰：好了。
OK, good.
好的，很好。
Second chunk of memory, thank you, Scully.
第二块内存，谢谢，Scully。
Now, I can certainly--
现在，我当然可以...
Thank you.
谢谢。
I can certainly now store the number two in this chunk of memory.
现在我当然可以将数字 2 存储在这块内存中。
But it's not necessarily contiguous.
但它不一定是连续的。
This chunk came from over here as per Scully's position originally.
这块内存最初来自这里，根据 Scully 的位置。
This chunk obviously is coming from over here.
这块内存显然来自这里。
And if you don't mind holding that for a moment,
如果你不介意帮我拿一下，
this is breaking the metaphor of an array, which was indeed contiguous.
这打破了数组的比喻，它确实是连续的。
And even though I as the human can certainly go over and walk next to her,
即使我作为一个普通人可以走过去，走到她旁边，
that's the equivalent of copying values from one place to another.
这等同于将值从一个地方复制到另一个地方。
What if we're a little more clever, though?
但如果我们更聪明一些呢？
And if Scully found space for this number one over here,
如果 Scully 在这里找到了数字 1 的空间，
let's just leave this balloon here.
我们就把这个气球放在这里。
And if she found space for the number 2 over there,
如果她在那里找到了数字 2 的空间，
let's leave that balloon there.
我们就把那个气球放在那里。
But we do somehow have to connect these numbers together.
但我们必须以某种方式将这些数字连接起来。
And here is where to--
这就是我们应该……
I'll try to do this on the fly.
我将尝试即兴发挥。
Maybe I could do something like this.
也许我可以做这样的事情。
I can take this balloon here.
我可以拿来这个气球。
And I can actually tie a string to it so that if I
我实际上可以系一根绳子在它上面，这样如果我
want to connect one to the other, we can link these, if you will, together.
想要将它们连接起来，我们可以将它们链接起来，如果可以的话。
And so here now I have a linked list that is not necessarily contiguous.
因此，我现在拥有了一个并非连续的链接列表。
There's a whole bunch of memory that may very well have real values,
有很多内存，它们可能包含真实值，
may very well have garbage values.
也可能包含垃圾值。
But I've somehow now linked these two together.
但我现在以某种方式将它们连接起来了。
And maybe just as a final flourish, if we could blow up one more balloon
也许，作为最后的点缀，如果我们再吹一个气球
to represent more space-- and now she's finding room
来代表更多的空间……现在她正在寻找那个气球的空间
for that balloon over there.
在那里。
Nice.
不错。
This one is a Yale chunk of memory.
这个是一个耶鲁大学的内存块。
So now I'll need one more link, if you will.
所以，如果可以的话，我需要再加一个链接。
And if I actually connect these two in this way,
如果我以这种方式将它们连接起来，
let me go ahead and tie this off here.
让我在这里把这个系上。
Now I can go ahead and connect these two.
现在，我可以将它们连接起来了。
If you never see this demonstration again in next year's videos,
如果你明年再也没看到这个演示，
it's because this did not go very well.
那是因为这次演示不太成功。
Here now we have the number one where we first malloced it,
这里，我们拥有了第一个数字，我们在第一次分配内存时得到了它，
the number two roughly where we malloced it, and the number three--
第二个数字大约是在我们分配内存时得到的，第三个数字……
OK, so maybe we'll fix this some other year.
好吧，也许我们明年会修复它。
Now, we'll have the number 3 allocated there.
现在，我们拥有了第三个数字，它被分配在了那里。
But the whole point of this silly exercise
但这个愚蠢的练习的重点是
is that we can certainly use the computer's memory as more of a Canvas,
我们可以将计算机的内存更多地用作画布，
put things wherever we want, wherever is available so long as we somehow
把东西放到我们想要放的地方，只要我们可以以某种方式
connect the dots, so to speak and can make our way from one chunk of memory
将它们连接起来，比方说，从一块内存
to the next to the next, thereby literally linking them together.
到下一块，再到下一块，从而将它们连接起来。
But, of course, we're using balloons for this metaphor.
当然，我们用气球来做这个比喻。
But at the end of the day, this is just memory.
但说到底，这只是内存。
So how could we encode one chunk to another chunk to a third chunk
那么，我们如何将一块内存编码到另一块内存，再到第三块内存？
might you think?
你可能会想？
What's the trick?
诀窍是什么？
Yeah?
是吗？
AUDIENCE: Pointers.
观众：指针。
DAVID J. MALAN: Using pointers.
大卫·马兰：使用指针。
That's why we introduced pointers last week.
这就是我们上周介绍指针的原因。
Because as simple as an idea as it is, as hard
因为这个想法虽然简单，但有时用代码写出来却很难，它
as it is to write sometimes in code, it's
本质上就是一个指针，一根泡沫手指指向另一块内存。
literally just a pointer, a foam finger pointing to another chunk of memory.
因此，这些指针实际上是用这些绳子来隐喻性地实现的。
And so these pointers really are metaphorically
所以，我们必须稍后进行总结，并决定是否还要进行这个演示。
being implemented now in with these pieces of string.
感谢斯库利参与。
So we'll have to debrief later and decide if we ever do this demo again.
好的，我们还有很多……
But thank you to Scully for participating.
好的，公平起见。
OK, we have plenty of--
OK, fair's fair.
好的，公平起见。
There we go.
好了。
Thank you Scully.
谢谢 Scully。
So let's now actually translate this to something a little more concrete
现在让我们把这转化成更具体的东西
and then get to the point where we can actually solve this problem in code.
然后就能够在代码中解决这个问题。
So here's that same canvas of memory.
这是我们之前相同的内存画布。
And if in this canvas of memory now I actually
如果在这块内存画布上，我实际上要
want to implement this idea of the number 1, the number 2, the number 3,
实现数字 1、数字 2、数字 3 的想法，
let's stop tying our hands in terms of expecting our memory
让我们停止将内存绑到一起，期望内存
to be contiguous back to back and start to move away from using arrays.
连续排列，并开始远离使用数组。
So, for instance, suppose I want a malloc space for the number 1
例如，假设我想要一个存放数字 1 的 malloc 空间
just as I first asked of Scully.
就像我最初请求 Scully 一样。
Suppose it ends up over there on the board.
假设它最终出现在那块板上。
The important thing for discussion here is
这里讨论的重点是
that that number one, wherever it ends up, is surely located at some address.
无论数字 1 最终出现在哪里，它一定位于某个地址。
And for the sake of discussion as in the past,
为了像过去一样进行讨论，
suppose the number one just ends up at location 0x, 1, 2, 3.
假设数字 1 最终出现在 0x, 1, 2, 3 位置。
So 0x, 1 2, 3 is where Scully was originally standing right here.
所以 0x, 1 2, 3 就是 Scully 最初站在这里的地方。
Then we asked for malloc for another chunk of memory.
然后我们请求 malloc 分配另一块内存。
Suppose that it ends up over here at address 0x, 4, 5, 6.
假设它最终出现在 0x, 4, 5, 6 地址。
So that's maybe roughly here when Scully was standing in her second position.
所以，当 Scully 站在第二个位置时，大约在这里。
Lastly, we allocate the number 3.
最后，我们分配数字 3。
Maybe it ends up at location 0x, 7, 8, 9,
可能它最终出现在 0x, 7, 8, 9 位置，
which was again per Scully's third malloc roughly over here on stage.
这再次对应于 Scully 的第三次 malloc，大约在舞台上的这里。
Now, this picture alone doesn't seem to lend itself
现在，这张图本身似乎并不适合
to an implementation of the string, metaphorically, to the pointers
用字符串的方式来实现，比喻地说，就是指针
unless we allow ourselves a new luxury.
除非我们允许自己享受一种新的奢侈。
Instead of just storing the number 1, 2, 3 in our usual squares,
而不是仅仅将数字 1、2、3 存储在我们通常的方框里，
I think what I'm going to have to do is cheat and use more memory
我认为我将不得不作弊，使用更多内存
to store what?
来存储什么？
The pointers as you proposed.
正如你所提议的那样，是指针。
So here's a trade off that I promised we would
所以，这里有一个我承诺过的权衡，
start to see more and more if you want to improve your performance in terms
如果你想提高性能，你会发现它越来越多，具体说是在
of time and avoid stupid copying of data from one place
时间方面，避免将数据从一个地方
to another again and again and again.
反复复制到另一个地方。
If you want to save time, you're going to have to give up some space.
如果你想节省时间，你将不得不牺牲一些空间。
And there's going to be this trade off between time and space.
时间和空间之间将存在这种权衡。
And it's up to you to decide ultimately which is more important.
最终由你决定哪个更重要。
So if you allow yourself not enough memory for the numbers 1, 2 and 3
所以，如果你给自己分配的内存不足以容纳数字 1、2 和 3，
but twice as much memory for the numbers 1, 2, and 3 and three pointers,
但数字 1、2 和 3 以及三个指针需要两倍的内存，
one for each, what could we now do?
一个代表每个数字，我们现在能做什么？
Well, if this node--
好吧，如果这个节点--
and this is a computing term.
这是一个计算机术语。
Node is just a generic term describing a box of memory, a chunk of memory
Node 是一个泛指，描述一盒内存，一块内存
in this case.
在本例中。
If I've given you this blank slate here, what value
如果你被赋予了这里这块空白，什么值
would make sense to store here if it's associated with this number one?
如果它与这个数字 1 相关联，存储在这里会更有意义？
Yeah?
嗯？
AUDIENCE: Maybe the address of the next element.
也许是下一个元素的地址。
DAVID J. MALAN: Good, maybe the address of the next element.
很好，也许是下一个元素的地址。
So the next element technically is supposed to be the number 2.
所以下一个元素理论上应该是数字 2。
So at this location, I'm going to store the value 0x, 4, 5, 6.
所以在这个位置，我要存储值 0x，4，5，6。
What then logically should go here in the second box?
那么，第二个框里应该放什么？
0x, 7, 8, 9.
0x，7，8，9。
And then here's a little non-obvious-- it's the end of the list as of now.
然后这里有点不明显——就目前而言，这是列表的结尾。
So we can't afford to let it be a garbage value
所以我们不能让它成为一个垃圾值
because a garbage value is a value.
因为垃圾值也是一种值。
And we don't want Oscar to effectively be pointing to some random location
我们不希望奥斯卡实际上指向一个随机的位置
lest we go there.
以免我们去那里。
So what would be a good special value to put here to terminate a list?
那么，这里有什么好的特殊值可以用来终止列表呢？
So null, so not null, which we used for strings but same idea, N-U-L-L,
所以是 null，不是 null，我们之前在字符串中使用过它，但概念相同，N-U-L-L，
which we keep using now for pointers, otherwise known as the 0 address,
现在我们继续将其用于指针，也称为 0 地址，
which I could just write for shorthand as 0x0 in this case,
在这种情况下，我可以用 0x0 来简写，
which is the same thing as null.
这与 null 相同。
So here then, even though we've changed nothing about how a computer works--
所以，这里，即使我们没有改变计算机的工作方式——
this is just my computer's memory--
这只是我的计算机的内存——
I'm using more memory now to effectively link one chunk, to the next chunk,
我现在使用更多的内存来有效地将一块内存链接到下一块内存，
to the next chunk.
到下一块内存。
So easy, just to note that the downside is more space.
很简单，只是要注意缺点是占用更多空间。
But now we don't have to worry about ever copying and moving this data
但现在我们不必担心复制和移动这些数据
around, which maybe over time for really big programs
四处移动，对于非常大的程序来说，随着时间的推移，
big data sets could very well be a net positive and a win for us.
大型数据集很有可能成为净收益，对我们来说是一件好事。
So any questions first on this notion of what a linked list actually is?
关于链表到底是什么，有什么问题吗？
No, all right, well, recall from last time
没有，好的，那么，回忆一下上一次
too that rarely do we actually care what the specific addresses are.
我们很少关心具体的地址是什么。
So this is one node, two node, and three nodes.
所以这是第一个节点、第二个节点和第三个节点。
And inside of each of these nodes is two values, the actual number
每个节点内部有两个值，实际的数字
we care about and then a pointer.
我们关心的数字，然后是一个指针。
And now this is actually an opportunity to introduce a term
现在，这是一个引入一个术语的机会
that you might see increasingly nowadays, data, so 1, 2, and 3,
你可能会越来越常看到，数据，所以是 1、2 和 3，
which we obviously care about in this case.
在这种情况中，我们显然很关心它们。
And then we could actually refer to these pointers
然后，我们可以更笼统地将这些指针称为
more generally as metadata.
元数据。
It's actual data because it's helping me solve a problem, get from one
它确实是数据，因为它帮助我解决问题，从一个地方
place to another.
到另一个地方。
But metadata is distinct from data in that I don't fundamentally
但元数据与数据的区别在于，我并不根本
care about the metadata.
关心元数据。
That's an implementation detail.
那是实现细节。
But it does help me organize my actual data.
但它确实帮助我组织实际数据。
So this is more of a high-level concept.
所以这是一个更高级的概念。
So what, though, is a linked list?
那么，什么是链表呢？
It turns out the store linked list will generally use just one more value.
事实证明，存储链表通常只需要一个额外的值。
And I'm going to draw it only as a square, a single box,
我将它画成一个正方形，一个单一的框，
because if I declare now in my code, as I soon will,
因为我很快就会在代码中声明它，
a variable maybe called list that points to a node, this
一个变量，可能叫做list，它指向一个节点，这
is effectively how I could implement a linked list.
实际上是我如何实现一个链表的方式。
I use one node per value.
我使用每个值一个节点。
And I use one extra pointer to find the first of those nodes.
我还使用一个额外的指针来找到第一个节点。
And, in fact, here again is where I don't need to care fundamentally
实际上，这里我不用关心
where any of these addresses are.
这些地址在哪里。
It suffices to know that, yes, computers have memory addresses.
知道计算机有内存地址就足够了。
So I could just abstract this away.
所以我只需要抽象掉这一点。
And this is how I might pictorially represent
这就是我如何以图片形式来表示
a linked list, a cleaner version of those three balloons,
一个链表，那些三个气球的更简洁版本，
whereby I was here.
我就在这里。
This was Scully's first balloon, second balloon, third balloon.
这是斯库里的第一个气球，第二个气球，第三个气球。
These arrows now just represent pointers or strings with the balloons.
这些箭头现在只代表指向气球的指针或字符串。
So with that said, how can we go about translating this to some actual code?
那么，我们如何将这个转换成实际代码呢？
Well, here's where we can call into play some of that same syntax from last time
这里，我们可以使用上次的一些语法
and even a couple of weeks ago when we introduced the notion of a structure.
甚至几周前我们引入结构的概念的时候。
So here for instance is how we defined a couple classes ago the notion
例如，这是我们几节课前定义的一个概念
of a person?
关于一个人？
Why?
为什么？
Well, C doesn't come with a person data type.
C 没有内置的“人”数据类型。
But we concluded it was useful to be able to associate someone's name
但我们认为能够将某人的名字
with their number and maybe even other fields as well.
和他们的号码，甚至其他字段联系起来非常有用。
So we typedef'd a structure containing these two values.
因此我们用typedef定义了一个包含这两个值的结构体。
We learned last week that string is technically char star.
我们上周学过，字符串在技术上是字符指针。
But that doesn't change what the actual structure is.
但这并不改变实际的结构。
And we call this struct a person.
我们称这个结构体为“人”。
Well, here's what we revealed last time, again taking those training wheels off.
这是我们上次揭示的内容，再次去掉辅助轮。
It's just a char star.
它仅仅是一个字符指针。
Let's keep going in this direction, though.
让我们继续往这个方向走。
If I want to define not a person but maybe more generically
如果我想定义的不是“人”，而是更泛化的
something I'll call today a node, like a container
一个东西，我今天把它叫做节点，就像一个容器
for my numbers and my pointers, well, I similarly
来存储我的数字和指针，那么，我同样
just need two values, not a name and a number,
只需要两个值，不是名字和数字，
which isn't relevant today but maybe the number as an actual int
今天并不重要，但可能是数字作为实际的整数
so I can store the 1, the 2, the 3, the 4 and so forth.
这样我可以存储1，2，3，4等等。
And this is a little less obvious.
这有点不明显。
But conceptually, what should be the second value
但在概念上，第二个值应该是什么
inside of any of these nodes?
在这些节点中的任何一个里面？
Yeah?
对吧？
So indeed a pointer.
所以确实是一个指针。
A pointer to what, though?
但它指向什么呢？
AUDIENCE: Another node.
观众：另一个节点。
DAVID J. MALAN: A pointer to another node.
大卫·J·马兰：指向另一个节点的指针。
And here's where the syntax gets a little weird.
这就是语法变得有点奇怪的地方。
But how do I define there to be a pointer in here to another node?
但如何定义这里有一个指向另一个节点的指针呢？
Well, you might be inclined to say node *next because this means next is
你可能倾向于说 node *next，因为这意味着 next 是
the name of the property or the attribute the variable inside
结构体内的变量的属性或属性名。
the struct.
结构体。
Star means it's a pointer.
星号表示这是一个指针。
What is it a pointer to?
它指向什么？
Clearly a node.
显然是一个节点。
But here's where C can bite you.
但这就是 C 语言会让你感到困惑的地方。
The word node does not exist until you get to this last line of code.
直到你看到最后一行代码，节点这个词才会存在。
C goes top to bottom, left to right.
C 语言从上到下，从左到右执行。
So you literally can't use the word node here if it's not existing until here.
所以，如果节点在这里之前还不存在，你就不能在这里使用节点这个词。
The simple fix for this is to actually use a slightly more verbose way
解决这个问题的简单方法是使用稍微更详细的方式
of defining a structure.
来定义一个结构。
You can actually do this.
你实际上可以这样做。
And we didn't bother doing this with person
而我们没有费心在 person 上这样做
because it didn't solve a problem.
因为这没有解决任何问题。
But if you actually make your first line a little more verbose
但是，如果你将第一行代码稍微说得更详细一些
and say, give me a definition for a structure called node, now in here
并说，给我一个名为节点的结构定义，现在在这里
you can actually do this.
你实际上可以这样做。
This is an annoying implementation detail
在 C 语言中实现结构时，这是一个令人烦恼的实现细节
when it comes to implementing structures in C.
。
But, essentially, we're leveraging the fact
但本质上，我们利用了这样一个事实
that because C code is read from top to bottom
因为 C 语言代码是从上到下读取的
if you give this structure a name called struct node,
如果你给这个结构命名为 struct node，
now you can refer to it here.
你现在就可以在这里引用它。
But you know what?
但你知道吗？
It's annoying to write struct node, struct node, struct node everywhere
在你的代码中写 struct node，struct node，struct node 无处不在很烦人
in your code.
。
So this last line now just gives you a synonym.
所以，最后一行代码只是给你一个同义词。
And it shortens struct node to just node.
它将 struct node 简化为 node。
So long story short, this is a good template
简而言之，这是一个很好的模板
for any time you implement some notion of a node as we will today.
用于你实现节点概念的任何时候，就像我们今天要做的那样。
But it's fundamentally the same idea as a person
但它与 person 基本上是同一个概念
just containing now a number and a pointer
只是现在包含一个数字和一个指针
to the next as opposed to someone's name and phone number.
指向下一个，而不是某人的姓名和电话号码。
So let me go ahead and walk through with some code
所以，让我继续用一些代码
how we might actually implement this process of allocating a balloon
来演示我们如何实际实现分配气球的过程
and putting a number on it, allocating another balloon
并在上面写上一个数字，再分配另一个气球
and putting a number on it and then connecting those two balloons again
并在上面写上一个数字，然后将这两个气球连接起来
and again.
再连接一次。
So we'll do this step by step in a vacuum
所以，我们将一步一步地在真空中进行操作
so you can see the syntax that maps to each of these ideas.
这样你就可以看到映射到这些概念的语法。
Then we'll actually pull up VS Code and combine it all
然后我们实际上会打开 VS Code 并将所有这些结合起来
and make a demonstrative program.
并创建一个演示程序。
So here, for instance, is the single line of C code
所以，例如，这是 C 语言的一行代码
via which I can give myself the beginning of a linked
通过它我可以给自己一个链接列表的开头
list that is a pointer that will eventually be pointing to something.
列表，它是一个指针，最终会指向某个东西。
So metaphorically, it's like creating a pointer.
所以，从比喻意义上来说，这就像创建一个指针。
I know we've gotten some complaints about that in the audience.
我知道我们收到了观众的一些抱怨。
We'll use the Harvard one to represent a pointer to something.
我们将使用哈佛的例子来表示指向某个东西的指针。
But if I only do this and I only say give me
但是，如果我只做这个，并且我只说给我
a variable called list that is a pointer to a node,
一个名为 list 的变量，它是一个指向节点的指针，
that's going to leave a garbage value.
那就会留下一个垃圾值。
So this is like pointing to some random location
所以这就像指向某个随机位置
because it's previously some value.
因为它之前是某个值。
Who knows what it is.
谁知道它是什么。
But we can solve that how?
但我们该如何解决？
What would be a good initial value to set this equal to?
将此设置为一个好的初始值？
So null.
所以为空。
At least if it's null, we then know that this isn't a garbage value.
至少如果是空，我们就知道它不是一个垃圾值。
This is literally 0x0, a.k.a. null.
这实际上是 0x0，也就是空。
And I'm just going to leave it blank for cleanliness.
为了整洁，我将留空。
So this would be the right way to begin to create a linked list of size 0.
所以这将是开始创建大小为 0 的链表的正确方法。
There's nothing there.
那里什么都没有。
But at least now that foam finger is not pointing to some bogus chunk of memory,
但至少现在那个泡沫手指没有指向某个错误的内存块，
some garbage value.
某个垃圾值。
So this is how the world might exist now in the computer's memory.
所以这就是现在计算机内存中的世界可能存在的方式。
How do I go about allocating space now for a node?
我现在如何为节点分配空间？
Well, it's just ideas from last week.
好吧，这只是上周的想法。
Once the word node exists as via that typedef,
一旦节点这个词通过 typedef 存在，
I can just use malloc to ask for the size of a node.
我就可以使用 malloc 来请求节点的大小。
I don't have to do the math myself.
我不必自己进行计算。
I don't care how big a node is.
我不关心节点有多大。
Just let it do the math for me.
只要让它帮我计算就行。
Then that's going to return presumably the address of a chunk of memory
然后它将返回，大概是某个内存块的地址
big enough for that big rectangle.
足够大，可以容纳那个大矩形。
And I'm going to store that for now in a temporary variable called n
我将暂时将其存储在一个名为 n 的临时变量中
that itself is a pointer to a node.
它本身是指向节点的指针。
So this might look like a lot altogether.
所以这看起来可能很多。
But this is just like before when I allocated space for a string
但这就像之前我为字符串分配空间一样
or I allocated space for a bunch of numbers
或者我为一堆数字分配空间
and set it equal to a pointer to integers, for instance, [INAUDIBLE]
并将其设置为指向整数的指针，例如，[INAUDIBLE]
recently.
最近。
All right, so this gives me a box in memory.
好的，所以这给了我在内存中的一个框。
This gives me a pointer called n.
这给了我一个名为 n 的指针。
So it's similarly just a single square because it's just an address.
所以它同样只是一个方块，因为它只是一个地址。
And it similarly gives me a bigger chunk of memory
它也同样给了我在计算机内存中的更大内存块
somewhere in the computer's memory containing enough space
它包含足够的内存空间
for the number that's going to go there, a 1, a 2, or 3, or whatever,
用于存储要放在那里的数字，1、2、3 等等，
and a pointer to the next value.
以及指向下一个值的指针。
So these lines of code collectively, this half creates this in memory.
所以这些代码行共同创造了这些，这一半创造了这些。
This half creates this in memory.
这一半创造了这些。
And the assignment here, the equal sign, essentially
以及这里的赋值，等号，本质上
does the equivalent of that.
做了等效的操作。
I don't care what the address is, the actual number.
我不关心地址是什么，实际的数字是什么。
It's as though n is now pointing to that chunk of memory.
就好像 n 现在指向了那块内存。
But this isn't very useful.
但这没什么用。
If I want to store the number 1 here, with what code can I do that?
如果我想在这里存储数字 1，我该用什么代码来做到呢？
Well, I could do this, borrowing an idea from last week.
好吧，我可以这样做，借鉴上周的想法。
So *n presumes that n is a pointer.
所以 *n 假设 n 是一个指针。
*n means go there, go to whatever you're pointing at.
*n 意味着去那里，指向你所指向的东西。
The dot operator means if you're pointing at a structure,
点运算符意味着如果你指向一个结构体，
go inside of it to the number field.
进入该节点的数字字段。
And we did this a couple of weeks ago with number and person
几周前，我们在实现地址簿时，对数字和人员进行了类似操作。
when we implemented an address book.
我们实现了一个地址簿。
So star n is go there.
所以星号 n 表示指向那个位置。
And the dot operator means go to the number field.
而点运算符表示进入数字字段。
The one on the right hand side and the equal sign
右侧的等号
means set whatever is there equal to the number 1.
表示将该位置的值设置为数字 1。
It turns out this is the syntax, though, that I
事实证明，这种语法有点神秘，不太好记
alluded to being a little bit cryptic and not very pleasant to remember
或者打字。
or type.
或打字。
Here, though, is where you can synonymously
然而，在这里，你可以同义地
instead use this line of code, which most C programmers would use instead.
使用这行代码，大多数 C 程序员会使用它。
This means n is still a pointer.
这意味着 n 仍然是一个指针。
The arrow literally with a hyphen and a greater than sign means go there.
箭头，由连字符和大于号组成，表示指向那个位置。
It's the exact same thing as the parentheses with the star,
它与带星号的括号完全相同，
with the dot.
以及点运算符。
This just simplifies it to look like these actual pictorial arrows.
这只是将其简化为看起来像实际的箭头图片。
So this would be the most conventional way of doing this.
所以这将是最常用的方法。
How now do I update the next field?
我现在如何更新下一个字段？
Well, I think I'm going to just say the same thing,
好吧，我认为我会说同样的话，
n go there but go into the next field and set it equal to null.
n 指向那个位置，然后进入下一个字段，并将其设置为 null。
Why null?
为什么是 null？
If the whole point here was to allocate just one chunk of memory, one node,
如果这里的主要目的是分配一块内存，一个节点，
you don't want to leave this as a garbage value
你不想将其保留为垃圾值
because that value will be mistaken for an arrow pointing
因为该值会被误认为是指向
to some random location.
某个随机位置的箭头。
All right, that's a lot.
好吧，这很多。
And, again, we're doing it in isolation step
而且，我们再一次将它隔离，逐步进行
by step just to paint the picture on the screen.
一步一步地，只是为了在屏幕上描绘出这个画面。
But any questions on any of these steps?
对任何这些步骤有任何疑问吗？
Each picture translates to one line of code there.
每个图片对应一行代码。
All right, so if you're comfy enough with those lines there,
好的，如果你对那些代码行足够熟悉，
what can I proceed to now do?
我现在可以继续做什么？
Well, let me propose that what I could now do with this same approach
好吧，我建议我现在可以用同样的方法
is set list itself equal to n.
将 list 本身设置为等于 n。
Because if the whole goal is to build up a linked list,
因为如果最终目标是构建一个链表，
and list represents that linked list, list
而 list 代表该链表， list
equals n is essentially saying whatever address is here, put it here.
等于 n 实际上表示将这里的值放到这里。
And pictorially what that means is, temporarily point both pointers
从图示上看，这意味着暂时让两个指针
to the same exact place.
指向同一个位置。
Why?
为什么？
Because this is the list that I care about long term.
因为这是我长期关心的 list。
This is maybe my global variable that I'm going to keep around forever
这可能是我将在计算机内存中永远保留的全局变量。
in my computer's memory.
在我的计算机内存中。
This was just a temporary pointer so that I could get a chunk of memory
这只是一个临时指针，这样我就可以获取一块内存
and go to its locations and update it with those values.
并访问其位置，用这些值更新它。
So, eventually, this is probably going to go away altogether.
因此，最终，这个指针可能会完全消失。
And this then is a linked list of size 1.
然后，这是一个大小为 1 的链表。
This is what happened when Scully inflated one balloon,
这就是 Scully 吹了一个气球时发生的事情，
I wrote the number 1 on it, and I pointed at that single balloon.
我在上面写了数字 1，然后指向了那个气球。
All right, if I want to go ahead and do this again and again,
好的，如果我想一次又一次地重复这个过程，
we'll do this a little more quickly.
我们会更快一点。
But it's the same kind of code for now.
但现在代码类型是一样的。
Here's how I allocate space for another node.
以下是如何为另一个节点分配空间。
Here's how I can temporarily store it in n.
以下是如何将其暂时存储在 n 中。
And I'll re-delcare it here just to make clear that it's indeed just a pointer.
我将在此处重新声明它，以明确表示它确实只是一个指针。
So the left hand side of the expression gives me this.
所以表达式的左侧给了我这个。
The right hand side of the expression gives me this.
表达式的右侧给了我这个。
Where could it be?
它在哪里呢？
I mean, I put it here.
我的意思是，我把它放在这里。
It could have been there.
它可能在那里。
It could have been anywhere else.
它可能在其他任何地方。
But malloc gets to decide that for us.
但 malloc 会为我们决定。
n equals this, just sets that temporary pointer equal to that chunk of memory.
n 等于这个，只是将那个临时指针设置为与那块内存相等。
I should clean this up.
我应该清理一下。
How do I now put the number 2 into this node?
现在我如何将数字 2 放入这个节点？
Well, I start at n.
好吧，我从 n 开始。
I go there.
我去了那里。
I go to the number field, which I keep drawing on top.
我去了数字字段，我一直把它画在上面。
And I set it equal to 2.
然后我把它设置为 2。
Now, it's a little non-obvious what we should do here.
现在，我们应该做什么有点不太明显。
So I'm going to be a little lazy at first.
所以一开始我会有点懒。
And rather than put these numbers into the linked list in sorted order,
而不是按照排序顺序将这些数字放入链表中，
like ascending order 1, 2, 3, 4, I'm just
比如升序 1, 2, 3, 4，我只是
going to plop it at the beginning of the list.
将它放在列表的开头。
Why?
为什么呢？
Because it's actually a little simpler.
因为实际上它更简单。
Each time I allocate a new node, I just prepend it,
每次我分配一个新节点时，我都会把它放在前面，
so to speak, to the beginning of the list
可以这么说，放在列表的开头
even though it's going to end up looking backwards in this case.
即使在这种情况下，它最终看起来会是倒序的。
So, notice, at this point in the story, I've
所以，请注意，在这个故事的这个阶段，我已经
got list pointing to the original linked list.
让 list 指向原始的链表。
I've got n pointing to the brand new node.
让 n 指向全新的节点。
And, ultimately, I want to connect these just as Scully
最终，我想像 Scully 和我用绳子连接一样连接它们。
and I did with the strings.
和我用绳子做的一样。
This is just temporary.
这只是暂时的。
So I want to connect these things.
所以我想连接这些东西。
Here's how I could do it wrong.
以下是如何做错的。
If I proceed now and update, rather, after one more line setting this equal
如果我现在继续，并且更新，也就是说，再增加一行将它设置为
to null-- sorry, let's at least get rid of that garbage value--
为 null——抱歉，至少让我们去掉那个垃圾值——
here's how I could proceed to maybe do this wrong.
以下是如何继续可能会做错。
Let me go ahead and update, for instance, list equals n.
让我继续更新，例如，将 list 设置为 n。
So if I update list equaling n, that's going
所以，如果我更新 list 等于 n，那将会
to point the list at this new node.
让 list 指向这个新节点。
But what has just happened?
但发生了什么？
What did I do wrong?
我做错了什么？
Yeah?
是吧？
AUDIENCE: Nothing's pointing to 1.
观众：没有东西指向 1。
DAVID J. MALAN: So nothing's pointing to 1.
大卫·J·马兰：所以没有任何东西指向1。
And even though you and I obviously have this bird's eye view of everything
尽管你和我都明显地拥有对一切的鸟瞰视角
in the computer's memory, the computer doesn't.
但在计算机的内存中，计算机却并非如此。
If you have no variable remembering the location of that node,
如果你没有变量记住那个节点的位置，
for all intents and purposes, it is gone.
从本质上来说，它就不复存在了。
So what I've essentially done is this.
所以我本质上做的就是这个。
When I update that pointer to point at the number 2, it's as though--
当我更新那个指针指向数字2的时候，就好像——
this was a much nicer idea in theory when we talked about it.
这在理论上是一个非常棒的想法，当我们讨论它的时候。
But it's not really working.
但它实际上并不起作用。
But this is effectively what we've tried to achieve, which is I've orphaned,
但这实际上是我们试图达成的目标，也就是说我遗弃了，
so to speak, the number 1.
可以说是，数字1。
And that too is a technical term in the context of memory.
在内存的语境中，这也是一个专业术语。
If no one is pointing at it if no string is connected to it,
如果没有人指向它，如果没有任何字符串连接到它，
I have indeed orphaned a chunk of memory, a.k.a.
我确实遗弃了一块内存，也就是
a memory leak.
内存泄漏。
And Valgrind would not, in fact like this.
Valgrind 实际上不会喜欢这样。
And Valgrind would, in fact, notice this.
Valgrind 实际上会注意到这一点。
So what would be the better approach?
那么更好的方法是什么呢？
Let me rewind.
让我倒带一下。
Instead of updating that address to be that of this node, let's
与其更新那个地址指向这个节点，不如我们
rewind to where we were a moment ago where list is still
回到我们刚才所在的位置，在那里 list 仍然
pointing at the original, n is still pointing at the new chunk of memory.
指向原始的，n 仍然指向新的内存块。
And what should I do instead?
那我还应该做什么呢？
Well, what should I do is maybe this.
好吧，我应该做的事情可能是这个。
Let's go to the next field of the new node.
让我们去到新节点的下一个字段。
So follow the arrow.
所以沿着箭头走。
Go to the next field.
去到下一个字段。
And what should I put here instead?
那我应该在这里放什么东西呢？
Why don't I put the memory address of the original node?
为什么不我把原始节点的内存地址放进去呢？
How can I get that?
我怎样才能得到它呢？
Well, that's actually this.
好吧，实际上就是这个。
So if list is pointing at the original node,
所以如果 list 指向原始节点，
I can just copy that address into this next field,
我就可以把那个地址复制到这个下一个字段，
which has the effect of doing that, albeit in duplicate.
这将产生同样的效果，尽管是重复的。
I've updated the next field to point at the very thing
我更新了下一个字段，指向原始 list 已经指向的东西。
that the original list is already pointing at.
And now for the sake of discussion, let me
现在为了讨论起见，让我
get rid of my temporary node called n.
去掉我这个叫做 n 的临时节点。
And what you'll see, ultimately, is that once we
你最终会看到，一旦我们
set list equal to n and get rid of it, now
把 list 设置为 n，并去掉它，现在
we can just treat the whole linked list as being connected and linked this way.
我们就可以把整个链表视为以这种方式连接在一起的。
How do we do this?
我们怎样做到这一点呢？
Again, we won't belabor the point with more.
再说一次，我们不会用更多的话来强调这一点。
But suppose I want to allocate a third node.
但假设我想分配一个第三个节点。
I have to do the exact same thing.
我必须做完全相同的事情。
But I have to update this next field to point at the existing list
但我必须更新这个下一个字段，指向现有的列表
before I update list itself.
在我更新 list 本身之前。
Long story short, order of operations is going to be super important.
长话短说，操作顺序将非常重要。
And if I want to stitch these data structures together,
如果我想把这些数据结构缝合在一起，
I would encourage you to think ultimately-- certainly
我鼓励你最终要思考--当然
when it comes time to write something like this,
当要写这样东西的时候，
think about what it is that we're actually trying to tie together.
想想我们到底要将什么联系起来。
So let me go ahead and do this.
所以让我继续做下去。
I'm going to go over to VS Code here.
我要去到这里的VS Code。
I'm going to delete the old code for list.c.
我要删除list.c的旧代码。
And perhaps now we can transition away from our old approach
也许现在我们可以从旧方法过渡过来
and actually do something with these pointers instead.
并用这些指针做点实际的事情。
So I'm going to go ahead, and let's say #include
所以我会继续下去，假设#include
as before, #include standard io.h.
像之前一样，#include standard io.h。
Let's go ahead and include standard lib.h proactively.
让我们继续并提前包含standard lib.h。
And let's go ahead and create that data type.
让我们继续并创建那个数据类型。
So typedef a struct called node.
所以typedef一个叫做node的结构体。
And inside of this node, let's give us an integer called number
在这个节点里面，让我们赋予一个名为number的整数
to store the 1, the 2, the 3, the 4.
用于存储1、2、3、4。
And then let's create a struct node star value called next whose purpose in life
然后让我们创建一个名为next的结构体节点星型值，它的存在目的
is going to point to the next node in any such list.
将指向任何此类列表中的下一个节点。
I'm going to shorten the name of all of this to just node simply.
我将所有这些的名称简化为node。
And then in main, let's go ahead and do this.
然后在main中，让我们继续做下去。
We'll bring back our friend argc and argv
我们将会把我们的朋友argc和argv带回来
so that I can actually implement a program this time that
以便我这次可以实际实现一个程序，该程序
lets me construct a linked list using numbers
允许我使用数字构建一个链表
that I just passed at the command line.
我刚刚在命令行中传递了这些数字。
I don't want to bother with getInt again and again or the CS50 library.
我不希望一遍又一遍地使用getInt或CS50库。
So let's just use argc and argv.
所以让我们只使用argc和argv。
But with argv, recall string now as of last week is synonymous with char star.
但是关于argv，回想一下，从上周开始，字符串与字符星型是同义词。
So that's the exact same thing as we've used in week 2 onward for command line
所以这与我们在第2周开始为命令行使用的东西完全相同
arguments.
参数。
So what do I want to do?
那么我想要做什么呢？
My goal in life with this demonstration is
我用这个演示的目标是
to create and code this linked list here or at least the beginnings thereof.
在这里创建并编码这个链表，或者至少是它的开始。
So how can I do this?
那么我该如何做到呢？
Let me go back into VS Code.
让我回到VS Code。
Let me declare a linked list called list but initialize it to null.
让我声明一个名为list的链表，但将其初始化为null。
So there's nothing there just yet.
所以目前还没有任何内容。
How now can I go about building this linked list?
我现在该如何构建这个链表呢？
By taking numbers from the command line.
通过从命令行获取数字。
So let's do this.
所以让我们做这个。
For int i equals 1, i is less than argc i plus plus, let me go ahead
对于int i等于1，i小于argc，i加加，让我继续
and do this.
并做这个。
I'm going to go ahead, and just for the sake of discussion,
我会继续下去，为了讨论的方便，
let me print out where we're going with this.
让我打印出我们将要做什么。
Let me go ahead and print out %s backslash n whatever is in argv bracket
让我继续并打印出%s反斜杠n，argv括号中的任何内容
i.
i。
So I'm not doing anything interesting yet.
所以我现在还没有做任何有趣的事情。
But let's just demonstrate where we're going with this.
但让我们只是演示我们将要做什么。
Let me go ahead and make list, ./list.
让我继续并制作list，./list。
And let me put the numbers 1, 2 and 3 as command line arguments.
让我将数字1、2和3作为命令行参数输入。
Enter.
输入。
There, we just have those numbers spit out.
我们只是将这些数字输出。
I'm just jumping through this hoop to demonstrate
我只是为了演示
how I'm getting those values.
如何获取这些值。
But notice the values in argv are always strings, a.k.a.
但是注意，argv 中的值始终是字符串，也就是
char star.
字符星。
So if I actually want to convert a string to an integer like this,
因此，如果我确实想将字符串转换为像这样的整数，
how can I do this?
我该怎么做呢？
I want to set the number variable equal to argv bracket i.
我想将 number 变量设置为 argv 方括号 i。
But argv bracket i is a string.
但是 argv 方括号 i 是一个字符串。
How can I convert a string to a number anyone recall?
大家还记得如何将字符串转换为数字吗？
Yeah?
是吗？
AUDIENCE: Atoi.
观众：Atoi。
DAVID J. MALAN: Atoi, so ASCII to I, so ASCII to integer.
DAVID J. MALAN：Atoi，所以是 ASCII 到 I，也就是 ASCII 到整数。
So if I do atoi, I can actually convert one to the other in this way.
因此，如果我使用 atoi，就可以用这种方式将一个转换为另一个。
And now I can actually print this as an int instead of a string.
现在，我实际上可以将它打印为一个 int 而不是字符串。
Now, that's not going to change the aesthetics of the program
现在，如果我再次打印出来，这不会改变程序的美观性
if I print it out again.
如果我再次打印出来。
But it does, in fact, give me an integer to work with.
但是，它确实给了我一个可用的整数。
But let's not bother printing it.
但我们不要麻烦打印它。
Let's instead put this number and any other number at the command line
相反，让我们将这个数字和命令行中的任何其他数字
into a linked list.
放到一个链表中。
So let me go ahead and allocate a pointer called n.
所以，让我去分配一个名为 n 的指针。
Let me set it equal to the return value of malloc
让我将它设置为 malloc 的返回值
asking malloc for the size of one node.
向 malloc 请求一个节点的大小。
Ideally that will give me a chunk of memory
理想情况下，这将给我一块内存
that can fit this number and a pointer.
可以容纳这个数字和一个指针。
Just for good measure, I'm going to check, well, if n equals equals null,
为了确保，我要检查，如果 n 等于空，
then actually this isn't going to work.
那么实际上这将不起作用。
So we should probably free memory thus far.
所以我们应该释放到目前为止的内存。
So I'm just going to leave this like this
所以，我只是这样保留它
because there's a few steps involved.
因为这里涉及几个步骤。
So free memory thus far.
所以释放到目前为止的内存。
And then we can go ahead, for instance, and return 1.
然后，我们可以继续，例如，返回 1。
All right, if now I don't have an error and n is not in fact null,
好的，如果现在没有错误，并且 n 实际上不为空，
but it's a valid address, I can go into n.
但它是一个有效地址，我可以进入 n。
I can follow that pointer to the number field
我可以沿着该指针指向 number 字段
and set it equal to the actual number.
并将它设置为实际的数字。
So this is a little strange at first glance
所以，乍一看这有点奇怪
that I've got number on the left and number on the right.
我左边是 number，右边也是 number。
But they're different. n is currently pointing
但它们不同。n 当前指向
at a chunk of memory big enough to fit a node.
一块足够大的内存，可以容纳一个节点。
n arrow number means go to that chunk of memory
n 箭头 number 意味着转到那块内存
and go to the top half of the rectangle and update that number
并转到矩形的上半部分，更新该数字
to be whatever the human typed in after we've converted it on line 16
在将它转换为实际整数之后，该数字将变成用户在第 16 行输入的任何内容
here to an actual integer.
这里转换为实际的整数。
All right, what next do I do?
好的，接下来我该做什么？
n arrow next should probably be at this point initialized to null.
n 箭头 next 应该在此时初始化为空。
And how now do I actually add this node n to my original linked list?
现在，我如何将这个节点 n 添加到我的原始链表中？
Well, I could just do list equals n.
好吧，我可以直接将 list 设置为 n。
And that would update a la the foam finger my list variable
并且这将更新像泡沫手指一样我的列表变量
to point at this new node.
指向这个新节点。
But we said before that that's potentially bad.
但我们之前说过，这可能是糟糕的。
Why?
为什么？
Because if list is already pointing at something,
因为如果列表已经指向某个东西，
we can't just blow kindly change what it's
我们不能随便更改它正在
pointing at because we'll have orphaned any previous numbers.
指向的东西，因为我们将会使之前所有的数字成为孤儿。
It's not relevant at the moment because we're still
目前这并不重要，因为我们仍然
in the first iteration of this loop.
处于这个循环的第一次迭代。
But we don't want to orphan or leak any memory.
但我们不想使任何内存成为孤儿或泄露。
So what do I first want to do?
那么，我首先想做什么？
Before I actually point the linked list at that new node,
在我真正将链表指向那个新节点之前，
I'm going to instead say, go to this current node, arrow, next,
我将改为说，转到当前节点，箭头，next，
and actually set that equal to list.
并实际上将其设置为list。
So strictly speaking, I don't actually need to initialize it to null.
所以严格来说，我实际上不需要将其初始化为null。
I can initialize the next field of this new node to point at the existing list.
我可以将这个新节点的next字段初始化为指向现有的列表。
So what I'm going to do here is, instead of initializing the next field
所以我在这里要做的是，而不是将next字段初始化
equal to null, if I want to insert this new node in front of any nodes that
等于null，如果我想将这个新节点插入到任何节点的前面，
already exist, I can simply say set the node's next field equal to whatever
已经存在，我可以简单地说将节点的next字段设置为任何
the list currently is.
列表当前是什么。
And now in this last line I can update the list itself to point to n.
现在在这最后一行，我可以更新列表本身以指向n。
So after this, let's just go ahead and do something relatively simple even
所以在此之后，让我们继续做一些相对简单的事情，即使
though the syntax for this is going to look a little complicated at first.
尽管这的语法一开始看起来有点复杂。
How do I go about printing the whole list?
我如何打印整个列表？
So print whole list.
所以打印整个列表。
Well, there's a couple of ways to do this.
好吧，有几种方法可以做到这一点。
But if you imagine a world-- if we fast forward
但是，如果你想象一个世界 - 如果我们快进
to a world in which we now have a linked list of size 3, for instance,
到一个现在拥有一个大小为3的链表的世界，例如，
here's where we might be at some point in the computer's memory.
这就是我们可能在计算机内存中的某个时刻所在的位置。
We've inserted the 1.
我们插入了1。
Then we inserted the 2.
然后我们插入了2。
Then we inserted the 3.
然后我们插入了3。
But because we're prepending everything, it actually looks like 3, 2, 1.
但因为我们正在将所有内容追加到前面，所以它实际上看起来像3, 2, 1。
So how could I go about printing this?
那么我该如何打印它？
Well, ideally, I could do this.
好吧，理想情况下，我可以这样做。
If a computer can only look at one location at a time,
如果一台计算机一次只能查看一个位置，
I can grab my foam finger and point at the 3 and print it out, point at the 2
我可以抓住我的泡沫手指，指向3并打印出来，指向2
and print it out, point at the 1 and print it out.
并打印出来，指向1并打印出来。
And then because this is null, I'm all done pointing and printing.
然后，因为这是null，我已经完成了所有指向和打印操作。
But how can I translate this to actual code?
但是我如何将其转换为实际代码？
Well, I could implement that foam finger, so to speak,
好吧，我可以实现那个泡沫手指，可以这么说，
in the following way.
以以下方式。
I could give myself a pointer often abbreviated by computer scientists
我可以给自己一个指针，通常由计算机科学家缩写
as ptr, specify that that's indeed a pointer to a node, as per that star,
为ptr，指定它确实是指向节点的指针，根据那个星号，
and initialize that pointer to be the list itself.
并将该指针初始化为列表本身。
So this is the code equivalent of, if I have this same picture on the screen,
所以，如果我在屏幕上看到相同的照片，这就是代码等效的内容，
declaring a pointer variable and point it at whatever the list
声明一个指针变量，并将其指向列表本身存储的第一个元素。
itself is storing first.
本身存储的第一个元素。
And, now, that's akin to doing this.
现在，这类似于这样做。
If I now go back into my code, how can I do this?
如果我现在回到我的代码中，我该怎么做呢？
Well, so long as that pointer does not equal
只要该指针不等于
null-- that is, so long as that pointer is not at the end of the list,
空 - 也就是说，只要该指针不在列表的末尾，
let me go ahead and print out using printf an integer with percent i.
让我继续使用 printf 打印一个带百分号 i 的整数。
And then let's print out whatever I'm currently
然后让我们打印出我当前
pointing at in ptr arrow number.
指向的 ptr 箭头数字。
So whatever I'm pointing at, go there and print the number that you find.
所以，我指向的是什么，就去那里打印出你找到的数字。
After that, what do I want to go ahead and do?
在那之后，我想做什么呢？
I'm going to set pointer equal to pointer arrow next.
我将把指针设置为指针箭头 next。
So what does this mean?
所以这意味着什么？
If I go back to my picture here and I want
如果我回到我的图片，我想
to actually walk through this thing, that first line of code
真正遍历这个东西，第一行代码
ensures that this foam finger, a.k.a. ptr, represented here,
确保这个泡沫手指，也就是这里表示的 ptr，
is pointing at the first element of the list.
指向列表的第一个元素。
Once I've printed it out with printf, I'm then doing pointer
一旦我用 printf 打印出来，我就执行 pointer
equals pointer next, which is following this next arrow.
等于指针 next，它跟着下一个箭头走。
So ptr now points at the 2.
所以 ptr 现在指向 2。
I then print that out and set pointer equal to pointer next.
然后我打印出来，并将指针设置为指针 next。
That's like following this arrow and updating pointer to point at this node
这就像跟着这个箭头走，并将指针更新为指向这个节点
instead.
而不是。
At that point, the next step is going to be to point it to null.
在那个时候，下一步将是将其指向空。
So for all intents and purposes, I'm done.
所以，从各个方面来说，我已经完成了。
And that's why we can actually get away with this while loop
这就是我们实际上可以摆脱这个 while 循环的原因
because while pointer is not null, it's going to print and print and print.
因为只要指针不为空，它就会一直打印。
Now, let me go into my terminal window.
现在，让我进入我的终端窗口。
Let me go ahead and make list and really hope
让我继续创建列表，并真心希望
I didn't make any mistakes because this was a lot all at once.
我没有犯任何错误，因为这一切都太快了。
Seems to have compiled OK.
似乎编译正常。
When I run ./list of 1, 2, 3--
当我运行 ./list 1, 2, 3--
theoretically, this code is correct, should unbeknownst to me
理论上，这段代码是正确的，应该在我不知情的情况下
build up an entire linked list in memory.
在内存中建立一个完整的链表。
But what's it going to print out ultimately?
但它最终会打印出什么呢？
What do you think it's going to print?
你觉得它会打印什么？
Yeah?
对吗？
It could print out null if I really screwed up, yes.
如果我真的搞砸了，它可能会打印出空，是的。
What else?
还有什么？
AUDIENCE: 3, 2, 1.
观众：3, 2, 1。
DAVID J. MALAN: Or it could print out 3, 2, 1.
大卫·J·马兰：或者它可以打印出 3, 2, 1。
And frankly, that's what I'm hoping for.
坦率地说，这是我希望看到的。
So even though I've given it in argv 1, 2, 3,
所以，即使我在 argv 中给出了 1, 2, 3，
because I'm prepending to the beginning of the list, the beginning of the list,
因为我正在将它们添加到列表的开头，列表的开头，
beginning of the list each time, I think,
每次都添加到列表的开头，我认为，
indeed, we're going to see 3, 2, 1.
实际上，我们会看到 3, 2, 1。
Now, that's fine.
现在，这很好。
That's correct.
这是正确的。
But it's not necessarily what we might want.
但它不一定是我们想要的。
So how could we actually go about inserting things maybe?
那么我们如何才能真正地进行插入呢？
Otherwise, because, in fact, if we consider this algorithm,
否则，事实上，如果我们考虑这个算法，
what's the running time insert?
插入的运行时间是多少？
How many steps are required right now, given a linked list of size n
现在，给定一个大小为 n 的链表，需要多少步？
if you want to go ahead and insert one more node--
如果你想继续插入一个节点 -
there's actually a reason I took this lazy approach of prepending prepending.
我采用这种懒惰的预先添加方式，其实是有原因的。
In big O notation, how much does it cost us to insert into a linked list?
在大 O 符号中，插入到链表中需要多少代价？
Think about it this way.
这样想。
Does it matter how many nodes are already
链表中已经有多少个节点，重要吗？
in the linked list, whether it's 1 or 2 or 3 or 300 or 3,000.
是 1 个，还是 2 个，还是 3 个，或者 300 个，或者 3000 个，都没关系。
If you're prepending, it doesn't matter how long
如果你在开头添加，那么链的长度无关紧要，
that chain is, you're just constantly putting it
你只是不断地将它
at the beginning, at the beginning, at the beginning.
放在开头，放在开头，放在开头。
Now, how many steps is this?
现在，这需要多少步？
I don't know exactly.
我确切地不知道。
I'd have to count the lines of code.
我得数一下代码行数。
But it's some small number.
但它是一个很小的数字。
It's like two steps, three steps.
大约是两步，三步。
How many lines of code is it?
代码有多少行？
It's very few to prepend, prepend.
在开头添加，需要很少的代码行。
So I would dare say that the running time of insertion into a linked list
所以，我认为插入到链表中的运行时间
is actually constant time.
实际上是常数时间。
It's big O of 1.
它是 O(1)。
And that's super fast because it doesn't matter how big the list is.
这非常快，因为列表的大小无关紧要。
Boom, boom, boom, you've prepended to the list.
砰砰砰，你已经将它添加到链表开头了。
But there's a flip side.
但它也有不利的一面。
What's the running time of searching a linked list,
在链表中搜索的运行时间是多少？
looking for something in it, finding a number in it?
在其中寻找某样东西，找到其中的一个数字？
Well, if it looks like this, how long does
好吧，如果它看起来像这样，那么
it take you to find some arbitrary number
需要多长时间才能找到一个任意数字
that the human might ask you for?
是用户可能要求你的？
How many steps will it take to find me the number 1 if it's there?
如果 1 在那里，找到它需要多少步？
So big O of n-- because in the worst case, the number you're looking for
所以是 O(n) - 因为在最坏情况下，你正在寻找的数字
might be all the way at the end.
可能在链表的末尾。
And even though you and I, again, have this bird's eye view,
尽管你我，再一次，拥有这种上帝视角，
and we can obviously see where the 1 is, the only way we can get to the 1
我们可以清楚地看到 1 在哪里，我们获得 1 的唯一方式
is by starting at the 2.
是从 2 开始。
How do you get to the 2?
你如何到达 2？
You got to start at the 3.
你必须从 3 开始。
How do you get to the 3?
你如何到达 3？
You've got to start at the beginning of the list itself.
你必须从链表的开头开始。
And so whereas in the world of arrays where you had this contiguous
因此，在数组的世界中，你拥有这种连续的
chunk of memory, just like we had lockers on the stage weeks ago,
内存块，就像我们几周前在舞台上使用的储物柜一样，
and you could jump to the middle and then the middle of the middle
你可以跳到中间，然后跳到中间的中间
and the middle of the middle.
再到中间的中间。
That was all predicated on contiguousness.
这一切都是基于连续性。
Why?
为什么？
Because if you know where the first locker was, and you
因为如果你知道第一个储物柜在哪里，并且你
know where the last locker was, you can substract one
知道最后一个储物柜在哪里，你就可以减 1
from the other, divide by 2, and, boom, you
从另一个减去，除以 2，然后，砰，你
get the index or the location numerically of the middle locker.
就得到了中间储物柜的索引或位置。
And you can do that again and again.
你可以一遍又一遍地这样做。
I cannot do any such math here.
在这里我无法做任何这种计算。
The middle of this linked list is obviously here.
这个链表的中间显然在这里。
But it doesn't matter what the location of this one is in memory.
但它在内存中的位置并不重要。
It doesn't matter what the location of this
它在内存中的位置并不重要，
is in memory because they could be anywhere in the computer's memory.
因为它们可以在计算机内存的任何地方。
So you can subtract one from the other, divide by 2,
所以你可以从另一个中减去一个，除以 2，
and that's going to put you in some random location
这会把你放到一个随机的位置
because these chunks of memory are not back to back to back to back.
因为这些内存块不是紧挨着。
They're every which way.
它们是各种各样的。
So this is to say, what algorithm from week zero
所以也就是说，我们不能在链表上使用哪个算法？
can we not use on linked lists?
我们不能在链表上使用哪个算法？
So binary search.
所以是二分查找。
So that very algorithm we started the class with
所以，我们开始这门课时用的那个算法
was all predicated on contiguous chunks of memory, like an array.
都依赖于连续的内存块，比如数组。
The problem with an array of course, though,
当然，数组的问题是，
is that you paint yourself into this corner.
你会把自己逼到这个角落里。
And you have to in advance how many locations you want.
你必须提前知道你想要多少个位置。
And if you round up, you're wasting space.
如果你向上取整，就会浪费空间。
If you round down, you're wasting time.
如果你向下取整，就会浪费时间。
So you're screwed either way.
无论哪种方式你都会被困住。
A linked list avoids those problems.
链表可以避免这些问题。
It's more of a dynamic data structure that can grow.
它更像是一个可以增长的动态数据结构。
And frankly, if we code it up, it could even shrink.
坦白地说，如果我们把它编码起来，它甚至可以缩小。
We could remove these nodes back and forth.
我们可以来回删除这些节点。
And so we're not necessarily wasting time on insertion,
所以我们不一定会浪费时间在插入上，
but we are on searching this thing.
但我们是在搜索它。
We're back to Big O of n when it comes to searching a linked list as opposed
在搜索链表时，我们又回到了 O(n) 的时间复杂度，而不是
to it being log n, which was much, much better.
log(n)，这要好得多。
So the upside of prepending the nodes in this way
所以，用这种方式在链表头部添加节点的优点是
is that we have constant time insertion of new nodes
我们可以用常数时间插入新的节点
because we just continually insert, insert, insert
因为我们只是不断地插入、插入、插入
into the very beginning of the list.
到链表的开头。
Of course, a side effect of this is that the numbers
当然，这样做的一个副作用是数字
might end up in completely reverse order as they have here
可能最终会以完全相反的顺序出现，就像这里一样
because I first inserted 1.
因为我首先插入了 1。
But then I prepended 2.
然后我在头部添加了 2。
And then I prepended 3.
然后我在头部添加了 3。
Well, we could perhaps take a completely different approach
好吧，我们也许可以采取一种完全不同的方法
and append the nodes upon insertion instead.
在插入时将节点添加到链表尾部。
So, for instance, if I start off with an empty list, I could then insert 1.
例如，如果我从一个空链表开始，我就可以插入 1。
I can insert 2.
我可以插入 2。
And I can insert 3.
我可以插入 3。
And, in this case, I actually get a bit lucky that now they
而且，在这种情况下，我实际上有点幸运，因为现在它们
are in fact in sorted order.
实际上是有序的。
Now, to be fair, that's not guaranteed.
现在，公平地说，这不是保证的。
But let's at least consider what the code
但让我们至少考虑一下代码
would look like if we were to take this alternative approach of appending
如果我们采用这种在末尾添加节点的替代方法，它看起来会怎样？
nodes instead of prepending.
而不是在开头添加节点。
Well, rather than write out the code from scratch,
嗯，与其从头开始编写代码，
let me open up a premade version of list.c that even has some comments
让我打开一个预制的 list.c 版本，它甚至有一些注释
to explain what's going on.
来解释发生了什么。
Some of this code is pretty much the same.
其中一些代码基本相同。
But allow me to scroll down roughly to the middle where
但请允许我向下滚动到大约中间的位置，在那里
we'll see the actual logic in question.
我们将看到相关的实际逻辑。
So, first, on line 35 here, we're checking if the list is null.
所以，首先，在这里的第 35 行，我们检查列表是否为空。
Because if there's no list yet, it's actually pretty easy
因为如果还没有列表，实际上非常容易
to prepend or append.
在开头添加或在末尾添加。
We're just going to go ahead and update the list
我们将直接更新列表
variable to point to this new node n.
变量，使其指向这个新的节点 n。
But if the list isn't empty, and there's at least one node there already,
但如果列表不为空，并且至少已经存在一个节点，
well, then what we're going to do is this in line 45.
那么，我们将在第 45 行这样做。
We're going to iterate over that existing linked list.
我们将遍历那个现有的链表。
And I'm going to do so with a temporary variable called pointer,
我将使用一个名为指针的临时变量来进行操作，
or ptr for short, that's initialized to the beginning of the list, a foam
或者简称为 ptr，它被初始化为列表的开头，一根泡泡手指
finger pointing at that first node initially.
最初指向第一个节点。
I'm going to on every iteration update that pointer variable
在每次迭代中，我都会更新那个指针变量
to point to the next node, to the next node, pointing one node ahead
使其指向下一个节点，指向下一个节点，指向前面一个节点
with that foam finger.
用那根泡泡手指。
But on each iteration, I'm also going to make sure
但在每次迭代中，我还会确保
that the pointer variable is not null.
指针变量不为空。
Because if it is null, that means I'm pointing past the end of the list or,
因为如果它为空，这意味着我指向了列表的末尾，或者，
that is, the list has ended.
也就是说，列表已经结束了。
But if inside of that loop I notice that the current node's next field is null,
但如果在循环内部，我注意到当前节点的 next 字段为空，
I actually know logically that I'm at the end of the list
我实际上在逻辑上知道我已经到达了列表的末尾
without going past it.
而没有越过它。
So at that point, if my goal is to append this new node,
所以，在那个点，如果我的目标是追加这个新的节点，
I'm going to go ahead and set pointer arrow next,
我将继续设置指针箭头 next，
which is currently null, but set it equal to the address of this new node
它当前为空，但将其设置为这个新节点的地址
effectively appending that node to the end of the list.
有效地将该节点追加到列表的末尾。
So, for instance, if we started with a list of 1 and 2, what we've just done
例如，如果我们从包含 1 和 2 的列表开始，我们刚刚做的事情
is updated 2's next field to be equal to the address of the node containing 3.
是将 2 的 next 字段更新为等于包含 3 的节点的地址。
Meanwhile, the node containing 3's next field is null by default
同时，包含 3 的节点的 next 字段默认情况下为空
because it is now the new end of the list.
因为它现在是列表的新末尾。
Now, what are the implications for maybe performance or efficiency now?
现在，对性能或效率可能有什么影响呢？
Well, we are now appending to the list, which
嗯，我们现在正在追加到列表中，这
means we're no longer gaining constant time of insertion.
意味着我们不再获得恒定的插入时间。
Because any time we prepend it, it took us some finite number of steps.
因为每当我们在开头添加时，都需要一些有限的步骤。
We just had to update a couple of pointers at the beginning of the list--
我们只需要更新列表开头处的几个指针--
beginning of the list.
列表的开头。
And it doesn't actually matter how much longer the list
而且实际上并不重要列表有多长
is getting because we're never traversing
因为我们永远不会遍历
the list when we're prepending.
当我们进行前置时，列表就会出现。
But when we're appending, by definition we're finding the end of the list,
但是，当我们进行追加时，根据定义，我们是在寻找列表的末尾。
finding the end of the list, finding the end of the list.
寻找列表的末尾，寻找列表的末尾。
And so our running time now for insertion
因此，我们现在插入操作的运行时间
is no longer big O of 1 or constant time.
不再是 O(1) 或者常数时间了。
It's now big O of n because if there's n nodes in the list already,
它现在是 O(n) 了，因为如果列表中已经存在 n 个节点，
just to find the end of it we need to actually traverse the whole list
仅仅为了找到它的末尾，我们实际上需要遍历整个列表
to actually find where this new node should go.
来找到这个新节点应该放置的位置。
But even so, we've gotten lucky in this appending case
但即使如此，在这个追加情况下我们还是比较幸运的
that we inserted 1 then 2 then 3.
我们插入了 1、然后是 2、最后是 3。
That's just because of my choice of inputs.
这只是因为我选择了这些输入。
Suppose that we don't in advance what the inputs are going to be.
假设我们事先不知道输入将是什么。
They might be large numbers, small numbers, or anything in between.
它们可能是大数字、小数字，或者介于两者之间的任何数字。
But they might not necessarily be in order.
但是它们不一定是有序的。
But if we want to maintain this linked list in sorted order,
但如果我们想要让这个链表保持排序，
I think our logic's actually going to have to change.
我认为我们的逻辑实际上需要改变。
So let me actually go ahead and open up a new version of my linked list code,
所以让我实际操作一下，打开一个新的链表代码版本，
this one too made in advance.
这个也是事先做好的。
And in this version of my code, as we'll soon see,
在这个代码版本中，我们很快就会看到，
I've gone about changing the logic just a little bit so that I can actually
我稍微改变了一下逻辑，这样我实际上可以
now handle this additional case because when inserting nodes in arbitrary
现在处理这个额外的情况，因为当在任意位置插入节点时
order, if I wanted them to end up being sorted,
顺序中，如果我希望它们最终是排序的，
I have to consider a few possible scenarios.
我必须考虑几种可能的情况。
Maybe there's no list whatsoever.
也许根本没有列表。
So let's actually look for that.
所以让我们实际看一下。
Let me scroll down in this final version of my linked list code.
让我在这个链表代码的最终版本中向下滚动。
And, actually, that case here on line 35 is pretty much the same.
实际上，第 35 行的这种情况基本相同。
If there's no list there, and the list variable is null,
如果没有列表，并且列表变量为 null，
well, let's just update it to point to this new node.
那么，我们只需要更新它，使其指向这个新节点。
But things get more interesting when there is at least one node there.
但是，当至少存在一个节点时，事情变得更有趣了。
Because if the goal is to maintain sorted order, we now need to decide,
因为如果目标是保持排序，我们现在需要决定，
does this new node, whatever its number is,
这个新节点，无论它的数字是多少，
go before the beginning of the list, at the end of the list,
应该放在列表的开头、列表的末尾，
in the middle somewhere of the list?
还是放在列表的中间某个位置？
So let's break that down.
所以让我们分解一下。
If we find that the new node's number is less than the list's number here,
如果我们发现新节点的数字小于这里列表的数字，
well, then it belongs at the beginning of the list
那么，它应该放在列表的开头
because it's smaller than any of the numbers already there.
因为它比已经存在的任何数字都小。
So what I'm going to go ahead and do is update this new node's next field
所以我要做的就是更新这个新节点的 next 字段
to point at the current linked list.
使其指向当前的链表。
And then I'm going to update the linked list variable
然后我将更新链表变量
to equal the address of this new node.
使其等于这个新节点的地址。
The effect then is, no matter how long the existing list is if this new node's
然后，效果就是，无论现有列表有多长，如果这个新节点的
number is smaller than everything else in the list,
数字比列表中所有其他数字都小，
I want to just splice it in at the beginning.
我想要把它直接插入到开头。
So that's actually pretty straightforward with just a couple
所以这实际上非常简单，只需要几行代码
of pointer updates.
指针更新。
But the other scenario is that it doesn't just
但另一种情况是，它不只是
belong at the very beginning of the list.
属于列表的最开头。
It's somewhere else in the list.
它在列表的其他位置。
And that itself is two scenarios.
这本身就有两种情况。
Maybe it's in the middle of the list.
也许它在列表中间。
Maybe it's at the very end of the list.
也许它在列表的最末尾。
So let's consider those scenarios as well.
所以我们也来考虑一下这些情况。
Let me scroll down here.
让我向下滚动一下。
And in my else clause, it's a bit bigger this time.
在我的 else 子句中，这次代码量稍微多一些。
Why?
为什么？
Because on line 51, in this case, I'm going to induce another for loop
因为在第 51 行，在这种情况下，我将引入另一个 for 循环
as before.
和之前一样。
But this time I'm trying to determine if this node belongs at the end
但这次我试图确定这个节点属于末尾
or somewhere in the middle.
还是列表中间的某个位置。
So I'm not just looking for the end this time.
所以这次我不只是寻找末尾。
I'm actually comparing the value, the integer inside of this new node,
我实际上是在比较值，这个新节点中的整数，
against what is currently in the list.
与当前列表中的值进行比较。
So, for instance, if logically I actually find my way
例如，如果从逻辑上讲，我真的找到了我的路
all the way to the end of the list, whereby
一直到列表的末尾，当
the next field in the pointer variables node equals null,
指针变量节点中的下一个字段等于 null 时，
well, then logically I didn't find an earlier spot for this node.
那么，从逻辑上讲，我没有找到这个节点的更早位置。
So let me go ahead and update that pointer's next field
所以，让我继续更新该指针的下一个字段
to equal the address of this new node.
使其等于这个新节点的地址。
And then like before, let's just break out because I'm done.
然后，和之前一样，让我们直接退出，因为我已经完成了。
I somehow mathematically got all the way to the end of the list
我不知何故在数学上走到了列表的末尾
because there is that null pointer.
因为那里有一个空指针。
So it must be the case logically here that this new node belongs at the end.
所以，从逻辑上讲，这里这个新节点肯定属于末尾。
But this is the juicier, slightly more challenging one.
但这是更有趣，更具挑战性的部分。
But it's what ensures that we can maintain sorted order even
但它保证我们即使
if the new node belongs somewhere in the middle.
新节点属于中间的某个位置，也能保持排序顺序。
So down here on line 62, I'm going to ask this question.
所以，在第 62 行，我要问这个问题。
If the new node's number is less than the number in the next node-- that
如果新节点的数字小于下一个节点中的数字，也就是说
is to say, if my foam fingers pointing here,
我的泡沫手指指向这里，
but the number I'm trying to insert is smaller than the next node over there
但我想要插入的数字小于那边的下一个节点
and implicitly the same as or greater than the current node's number,
并且隐含地等于或大于当前节点的数字，
well, then I'm going to go ahead and do this.
那么，我将继续执行以下操作。
I'm going to update the new node's next pointer
我将更新新节点的下一个指针
to be equal to whatever the current node I'm pointing at next pointer
使其等于我指向的当前节点的下一个指针
so that I can then update that pointer's next field to equal the new node.
以便我可以更新该指针的下一个字段使其等于新节点。
And then I can break out altogether, doing a similar splice
然后，我可以完全退出，执行类似的拼接操作
in the middle of this list but manipulating a node effectively
在该列表中间，但有效地操作一个节点
to the left and the right to make room for this new node.
在左右两边腾出空间来容纳这个新节点。
So, collectively, what does this code do?
所以，总的来说，这段代码做了什么？
Well, if we start out with that initially empty list,
那么，如果我们从最初的空列表开始，
and maybe we insert the number 2, it just goes right there.
也许我们插入数字 2，它就会直接放在那里。
But suppose that we insert next the number 1, which, of course, is smaller,
但是假设我们接下来插入数字1，当然，它更小，
this code now ensures that the 1 is going to get
这个代码现在确保1将被
inserted at the beginning of the list.
插入到列表的开头。
If we then insert the number 4, well, that's bigger than 1 and bigger than 2.
如果我们然后插入数字4，好吧，它比1大，也比2大。
So it logically is going to end up at the end of the list.
所以它在逻辑上会最终出现在列表的末尾。
And, lastly, in this example, if we insert 3, which, again, is initially
最后，在这个例子中，如果我们插入3，它再次是最初
out of order, this code can ensure that we still insert it in sorted order
无序的，这段代码可以确保我们仍然按排序的顺序插入它
because it's going to end up in between nodes 2 and 4.
因为它最终会出现在节点2和4之间。
So here too in terms of running time, insertion is still big O of n.
因此，在运行时间方面，插入仍然是O(n)的。
It's not quite as bad in practice as always adding it
在实践中，它并不像总是添加到
to the end of the list, the end of the list
列表的末尾，列表的末尾
as was the case when we blindly appended new nodes.
就像我们盲目地追加新节点一样。
But it is going to be in big O of n because, in the worst case
但它将是O(n)的，因为在最坏的情况下
here, if we've got n nodes in the list already, then in the worst case
这里，如果我们列表中已经有了n个节点，那么在最坏的情况下
it might indeed be such a big number that it belongs at the end of the list.
它可能确实是一个很大的数字，它属于列表的末尾。
All right, that was a lot.
好吧，那是很多。
Let's go ahead and take a delicious cookie break here.
让我们在这里吃一个美味的饼干休息一下。
And we'll be back in 10.
我们10分钟后回来。
All right, we are back.
好了，我们回来了。
And to recap, the problems we've solved and the problems we've created are--
为了回顾，我们解决的问题和我们创造的问题是——
arrays were problematic because they were a fixed size.
数组之所以有问题，是因为它们是固定大小的。
And that can get us into trouble.
这可能会让我们陷入麻烦。
Or it causes us to waste more space preemptively
或者它导致我们预先浪费更多空间
even though we might not ever use it.
即使我们可能永远不会使用它。
So we introduce the linked lists again to solve that problem
所以我们再次引入链表来解决这个问题
by being more dynamic and only allocate as much memory
通过更加动态，并且只分配我们需要的内存
as we need on demand step by step.
根据需求，一步一步地。
But, of course, we're spending extra space for the pointers.
但当然，我们为指针花费了额外的空间。
We might gain performance if we at least prepend all of our elements to it.
如果我们至少将所有元素都预先添加到其中，我们可能会获得性能提升。
But we lose time again if we append or insert in sorted order.
但是，如果我们按排序顺序追加或插入，我们再次损失时间。
So it's not clear, frankly, I think, to me,
所以坦白地说，我认为，对我来说，
even hearing these upsides and downsides, if there's a clear win.
即使听到了这些优点和缺点，也不清楚是否有明显的优势。
But maybe there's a way to get the best of both worlds
但是也许有一种方法可以兼得两者的优势
by trying to capture the upsides of having information that
通过尝试捕捉拥有信息的优点，这些信息
is kept in sorted order that allows us to maybe divide and conquer still
以排序的顺序保存，这可能允许我们仍然进行分治
but still gives us the dynamism to grow or shrink the data structure.
但也仍然给我们提供动态性，让我们可以扩展或缩减数据结构。
And thus we're born trees.
因此，树诞生了。
So what we're about to explore are variants of these ideas of arrays
所以我们即将探索的是这些数组想法的变体
and linked lists and see if we can maybe mash up some of those building blocks
和链表，看看我们是否可以将一些那些构建块混合在一起
and create more interesting, more compelling solutions
并创造更有趣、更具吸引力的解决方案
that are even not just one-dimensional left to right
这些解决方案甚至不只是从左到右的一维
but are maybe two dimensional and have different axes to them or dimensions.
而是可能是二维的，并且拥有不同的轴或维度。
So a tree in the real world, of course, tends
所以，现实世界中的树，当然，往往
to grow up from the ground like this.
像这样从地面向上生长。
But it tends to branch out.
但是它往往会分支出去。
And branches branch.
而分支还会继续分支。
And that might already in your mind's eye evoke notions of forks
这可能已经在你的脑海中唤起了对岔路的印象，或者像我们之前看到的条件语句。
in the road or conditionals as we've seen.
或者像我们之前看到的条件语句。
And let me propose that we first consider what
我建议我们首先考虑一下
the world calls binary search trees.
世界所称的二叉搜索树。
And so bi is back in that we can do things in half and half and half
因此，"bi" 又回来了，我们可以把事情分成一半、一半、再一半
somehow if maybe we think about arrays a little bit more cleverly.
只要我们稍微聪明一点，考虑一下数组。
So here's an array of size 7.
这是一个大小为 7 的数组。
And I chose that deliberately because there's a perfect middle.
我故意这么选择，因为它有一个完美的中间。
There's a middle of middle and so forth, just like the lockers a few weeks back.
中间的中间，再中间，等等，就像几周前我们谈到的储物柜一样。
So when the world of arrays--
所以，当我们谈到数组的时候——
this was actually pretty efficient because we
这实际上非常有效，因为我们
can do binary search and middle of middle, middle of middle, and so forth.
可以进行二分查找，找到中间的中间，再找到中间的中间，等等。
And that gave us logarithmic running time.
这给了我们对数级的运行时间。
But its only size 7.
但它只有 7 个元素。
And we concluded that it's going to be like big O of n headache
我们得出结论，要把这些数据复制到一个稍微大一点的数组中，释放旧内存，
to copy this into a slightly bigger array, free the old memory,
要把这些数据复制到一个稍微大一点的数组中，释放旧内存，
and so forth.
等等。
And thus were born linked list.
于是，链表就诞生了。
But with linked lists, we lost log of n running time.
但是，在链表中，我们失去了对数级的运行时间。
Why?
为什么？
Because we have to always start at the beginning to
因为我们必须始终从开头开始，
get, for instance, to the middle or to the end of the list in the worst case.
才能在最坏情况下找到中间或者链表的末尾。
But what if we start to think a little more cleverly in multiple dimensions?
但如果我们在多个维度上稍微更聪明一些呢？
So just for the sake of discussion, let me highlight the middle of this here
为了便于讨论，让我用高亮标出这个数组的中间位置。
array.
数组。
Let me highlight the middle of the middle
让我用高亮标出中间的中间
and then the middle of the middle.
然后是中间的中间。
So there's implicit structure here.
这里存在着一种隐含的结构。
There's a pattern of sorts.
存在着某种模式。
And, in fact, just to make this more obvious,
事实上，为了更清楚地说明这一点，
let me not treat this as one dimension left to right but how about two
让我不要把它看作一个从左到右的一维结构，而是把它看作二维结构
and give myself a bit of vertical space.
并给自己留一些垂直空间。
So it's the exact same array.
所以，它还是同一个数组。
But allow me to just think about it now as
但是现在请允许我把它想象成
though the middle elements way up here.
中间的元素在上面。
The middle of the middles are slightly lower.
中间的中间略微低一些。
And the middle of the middles or the leaves
而中间的中间，或者说叶子
really are at the bottom of this tree.
实际上都在树的底部。
And that word is deliberate.
这个词是故意选择的。
We actually borrowed vernacular from the world of trees
我们实际上借用了树世界中的词汇
where the leaf nodes or leaves are the ones at the very bottom.
在那里，叶子节点或叶子位于最底部。
And the root node is the one at the very top.
而根节点位于最顶部。
So for the sake of discussion, computer scientists
所以，为了方便讨论，计算机科学家
draw trees like this, instead of this.
会这样画树，而不是那样画。
But it's the exact same idea.
但它们的想法是一样的。
They just tend to grow down in discussions, more like a family tree
它们在讨论中往往向下生长，更像是家族谱
if you drew those growing up, for instance.
比如，如果你画的是向上生长的家族谱。
So what's interesting here?
那么这里有什么有趣的地方呢？
Well, at the moment, we've broken the array model
嗯，目前我们已经打破了数组模型
because this memory is absolutely not contiguous because this number is here.
因为这块内存绝对不是连续的，因为这个数字在这里。
This number is here, here, here, and here.
这个数字在这里，在这里，在这里，还有这里。
It's all over the place.
它到处都是。
But we do have pointers now in our toolkit, whereby
但是我们现在在我们的工具包中有指针，通过它们
even if these numbers are anywhere in the computer's memory,
即使这些数字位于计算机内存中的任何地方，
we can stitch them together like we did string and those balloons.
我们可以像我们用绳子和气球做的那样把它们缝合在一起。
Now, it's not sufficient just to have one piece of string
现在，仅仅有一条绳子是不够的
for each node or one pointer.
用于每个节点或一个指针。
But what if we actually give each of these nodes, not just a number,
但是如果我们实际上给每个节点，不仅仅是一个数字，
like the number 4, the number 2, the number 6--
比如数字 4，数字 2，数字 6 --
let's give them each a number and two pointers, a so-called left child
让我们给它们每个一个数字和两个指针，一个所谓的左子节点
and a right child so to speak.
以及一个右子节点，可以这么说。
So we could do this.
所以我们可以这样做。
And I'm going to abstract away now.
我现在要抽象化。
They're not even rectangles anymore.
它们甚至不再是矩形了。
They're really long rectangles.
它们是真正很长的矩形。
Or they're upside down Ts that have three boxes to them.
或者它们是倒置的 T，有三个盒子。
But I'm just going to abstract away nodes now as just simple squares.
但我现在要把节点抽象成简单的正方形。
And it's an implementation detail as to what the structs actually are.
而结构体到底是什么是一个实现细节。
But the arrows suggest that each of these nodes now has two pointers.
但是箭头表明这些节点现在都有两个指针。
You don't have to use them.
你并不一定要用它们。
The leaf nodes have nothing to point to.
叶子节点没有指向任何东西。
So those can all be null probably.
所以那些可能都是空的。
But each of these nodes now has two pointers.
但是这些节点现在都有两个指针。
Now, what's the implication of this?
现在，这意味着什么？
This is what we call a binary search tree
这就是我们所说的二叉搜索树
because, one and first and foremost, it's obviously a tree.
因为，首先也是最重要的是，它显然是一棵树。
But it also is a data structure that's kept in sorted order,
但它也是一种以排序顺序存储数据的结构，
whereby notice what is true.
因此要注意什么是真的。
If you pick any node in this tree, like the number 4,
如果你在这棵树中选择任何节点，比如数字 4，
everything to the left of it, its left subtree so to speak, is smaller.
它左侧的所有东西，可以这么说它的左子树，都更小。
Everything to the right of it, its right subtree, is larger.
它右侧的所有东西，它的右子树，都更大。
And that's true elsewhere.
在其他地方也是如此。
Look at the six.
看看 6。
Everything to the left is smaller.
左侧的所有东西都更小。
Everything to the right is bigger and same thing over here.
右侧的所有东西都更大，这里也是一样。
So in some sense, this is a recursive data structure
从某种意义上说，这是一种递归数据结构
because you can say the same thing about each of these nodes
因为你可以对这些节点中的每一个都这么说
because each of these subtrees compose a larger tree.
因为这些子树中的每一棵都构成了更大的树。
Or, conversely, this big tree is a composition
反之，这棵大树是
of 1, 2 subtrees plus one more node.
由 1，2 棵子树加上一个节点组成。
So think back to our [INAUDIBLE] example in those bricks.
所以回想起我们在那些砖块中的 [听不见] 例子。
Well, what's a pyramid of height 4?
那么，高度为 4 的金字塔是什么？
Well, just a pyramid of height 3 plus one more row.
好吧，只是一座高度为 3 的金字塔加上一排。
What's a tree of height 3?
高度为 3 的树是什么？
Well, it's two subtrees of height 2 plus one more row or really
嗯，它是两棵高度为 2 的子树加上一排，或者说实际上
one new root node to connect them.
一个新的根节点来连接它们。
So this already is a recursive data structure by that logic.
所以根据这个逻辑，这已经是一个递归的数据结构了。
How do we translate this into code?
我们如何把它转换成代码？
Well, we won't sludge through so much low level C code this time around.
好吧，这次我们不会再费力地去处理那么多的低级 C 代码了。
But let me propose that we could implement a node now
但是我建议我们现在可以实现一个节点
as being similar in spirit to what we did last time where every node used
它在精神上类似于我们上次做的事情，在那里每个节点都使用
to have a number and a next pointer.
一个数字和一个下一个指针。
But, now, let's actually make some room for ourselves
但是，现在，让我们实际为我们自己留出一些空间
and redefine a node as still having a number but now having two pointers.
并重新定义一个节点，它仍然有一个数字，但现在有两个指针。
And I'll call them obviously left and right
我显然会称它们为左和右
though we could call them anything we want.
尽管我们可以随心所欲地称呼它们。
I could call it next and previous.
我可以称它为下一个和上一个。
But really left and right would seem to make more sense with children
但是，左和右对一个节点的子节点来说更有意义
of a given node like this.
像这样。
So this in C is how we might implement, therefore,
所以在 C 中，这就是我们可能实现的方式，因此，
a node in a binary search tree.
二叉搜索树中的一个节点。
And so let's consider pictorially what the running time is
让我们以图示的方式考虑一下运行时间是多少
of searching for something.
搜索某样东西。
If this here is the tree and it follows that binary search tree
如果这里就是树，并且它遵循二叉搜索树
definition where everything to the left is smaller everything to the right
定义，其中左侧的所有内容都比右侧的所有内容更小
is bigger, well, how many steps might it take if you
更大，那么，如果你有
have n nodes in a tree like this?
n 个节点在像这样的树中？
Well, it's not going to take me n steps because I certainly
好吧，它不会花费我 n 步，因为我当然
don't have to look through every node.
不需要查看每个节点。
And, in fact, just like a linked list starts
事实上，就像一个链表从
on the left hand side, so to speak.
左侧开始，可以这么说。
So that's just an artist's rendition.
所以那只是艺术家的演绎。
Just as a linked list starts on one end and you
就像链表从一端开始，然后你
have to traverse the whole thing, a tree, because it's two dimensional,
必须遍历整个链表，一个树，因为它是一个二维的，
always starts in memory at the root node.
总是在内存中的根节点开始。
So this is always where you start any operation, insertion,
所以，这总是你开始任何操作的地方，插入、
deletion, searching.
删除、搜索。
So by that logic, in the worst case if there's n nodes here,
所以根据这个逻辑，在最坏的情况下，如果有 n 个节点在这里，
how many steps would it seem to take?
它看起来需要多少步？
It's not big O of n.
它不是 O(n)。
So it's actually back to bi O of log n.
所以它实际上回到了 O(log n)。
Why?
为什么？
Because, actually, if you think of the height,
因为，实际上，如果你考虑高度，
there's roughly eight nodes in here.
这里大约有八个节点。
And log base 2 of 8 is actually 3.
以 2 为底的对数 8 实际上是 3。
And so 1, 2, 3 is the height of this tree.
所以 1、2、3 就是这棵树的高度。
So in the worst case at the moment, it seems
所以，在目前最坏的情况下，似乎
that it's only going to take me like 1 node, 2 nodes, 3 nodes, or really
它只花费我 1 个节点、2 个节点、3 个节点，或者实际上
just two steps to get to the very bottom of this tree
只需要两步就能到达这棵树的最底部
to decide is a number there or not.
来决定那里是否有一个数字。
I certainly can ignore this entire subtree.
我当然可以忽略这整个子树。
Why?
为什么？
Because I'm searching for the number 7.
因为我正在搜索数字 7。
Just like the phone book from week 0, I can divide and conquer this problem.
就像第 0 周的电话簿一样，我可以分而治之来解决这个问题。
If I'm looking for 7, I don't need to bother
如果我正在寻找 7， 我就不需要费心
wasting any time looking at this entire subtree, which is almost 50%
浪费任何时间去看这整个子树，它几乎占了屏幕上的图片的 50%
of the picture on the screen.
屏幕上的图片
And so I can focus on this half then this half.
所以我可以关注这一半，然后这一半
And, boom, I'm done.
然后，砰，就完成了
So we sort have binary search back.
所以我们有点像二分搜索
We have the metaphor of the lockers back by operating now in two dimensions
我们又有了储物柜的隐喻，现在我们在二维空间中操作
to mitigate the reality that our memory is no longer contiguous.
以减轻我们的内存不再连续的现实
But that's fine.
但这没关系
We can follow these arrows.
我们可以沿着这些箭头走
We can use these pointers instead to get anywhere that we actually want.
我们可以使用这些指针来获得我们真正想要到达的任何地方
So any questions now on trees or specifically binary search trees,
所以现在关于树，或者更具体地说关于二叉搜索树，有什么问题吗？
which I dare say are the best of both worlds, all of the upsides of an array.
我敢说，它们是两全其美，拥有数组的所有优点
And it's log n running time.
而且它的运行时间是 log n
And all of the upsides of the dynamism of linked list because this thing
以及链表的动态性的所有优点，因为这个东西
can grow and shrink and doesn't need to be contiguous.
可以增长和缩小，并且不需要是连续的
Any questions on this?
对此有什么问题吗？
All right, well, the code too lends itself to relative simplicity.
好吧，代码本身也相对简单
And here's where recursion applies not just to the structure of the data
这就是递归不仅适用于数据结构
but also the code itself.
而且也适用于代码本身
So just for the sake of discussion, we won't run this code.
所以为了讨论的缘故，我们不会运行这段代码
We'll just look at it on screen here.
我们只是在屏幕上看看它
Suppose you're implementing a function called search whose purpose in life
假设你正在实现一个名为 search 的函数，它的生命意义
is to search a tree and return, true or false,
是在树中搜索并返回真或假，
I found the number you're looking for.
我找到了你正在寻找的数字
Well, here's the number I'm looking for.
嗯，这就是我要找的数字
It's one of the arguments.
这是参数之一
And the first argument more importantly is actually a pointer to the tree
更重要的是，第一个参数实际上是指向树的指针
itself a pointer to the root of the tree.
本身是指向树根的指针
And that's all the information we need to search a tree
这就是我们搜索树所需的所有信息
and go left, go right, go left, go right.
然后向左，向右，向左，向右
How?
怎么做呢？
Well, let me do this.
好吧，让我来做这个
As always, we'll have a base case when it comes to recursion.
和往常一样，当涉及递归时，我们将有一个基本情况
Because if there's no tree there, then it
因为如果那里没有树，那么它
makes no sense to even ask me this question.
甚至问我这个问题都没有意义
I'm just going to return false.
我将直接返回 false
If you hand me null, there's nothing to do, return false.
如果你给我 null，就没什么可做的，返回 false
But suppose that you don't hand me null.
但是假设你没有给我 null
And suppose that the number I'm looking for
假设我要找的数字
is less than the number in the tree at the moment, the number at that root.
小于此时树中的数字，即根节点处的数字
Well, what do I want to do?
好吧，我想做什么？
I effectively want to go left.
我实际上想要向左走
I want to search the left subtree.
我想搜索左子树
How do I do that?
我要怎么做呢？
I'm going to return the recursive return value from the same search
我将返回来自同一 search 函数的递归返回值
function passing in a slightly smaller tree, a so-called subtree
函数，传入一棵稍微小一点的树，即所谓的子树
but the same number.
但数字相同
And this is where recursion is beautiful.
这就是递归的魅力所在。
Look at the relative simplicity of this.
看看它的相对简洁性。
If search exists, which it doesn't exist in its entirety yet.
如果搜索存在，它还没有完全存在。
But we'll get there.
但我们会实现的。
If you want to search half of the tree, just go there.
如果你想搜索树的一半，直接去那里。
So go to the root of the tree.
所以到树的根部。
Follow the left child pointer and pass that in because it's a tree.
沿着左子节点指针，传入它，因为它是一棵树。
It's just a smaller tree but pass in the same number.
它只是一棵更小的树，但传入相同的数字。
What if, though, it's a bigger number?
但是，如果它是一个更大的数字呢？
So what if the number you're looking for is
那么，如果你要找的数字是
bigger than the number at the root of the tree?
大于树根处的数字呢？
Well, then just search the right subtree instead.
那么，就搜索右子树。
And now, logically, what's the fourth and final case?
现在，从逻辑上讲，第四种也是最后一种情况是什么？
So I can express that as if the number you're looking for equals
所以我可以这样表达，如果你要找的数字等于
equals the number in the tree, that is, the root of the tree,
等于树中的数字，也就是树根，
then I'm going to go ahead and return true.
那么我将返回真。
And you might remember from our days with Scratch
你可能还记得我们用Scratch的那些日子
even this conditional is not necessary.
即使这个条件也不必要。
I just did it to be explicit.
我只是把它写出来，以便清楚明白。
We can tighten it up as just an else instead.
我们可以把它简化为一个else。
And that's it.
就是这样。
And this is where, again, recursion finally
而在这里，递归最终
is maybe a little more accessible, a little more obvious in its cleanliness.
可能更容易理解，在简洁性上更明显。
There's relatively little logic here.
这里的逻辑相对很少。
But what's important is that these recursive calls here and here are
但重要的是，这里和这里的递归调用
dividing and conquering the problem implicitly.
隐式地将问题分而治之。
Why?
为什么？
Because it's solving the same problem search for a number.
因为它在解决同一个问题——搜索一个数字。
But it's doing it on just half of the tree or the other half of the tree.
但它只在树的一半或另一半上进行。
And because we have this base case here, even
而且因为我们这里有这个基本情况，即使
if you get all the way to the bottom of the tree
你到达了树的底部
and you try to go down the left child or you try to go down the right child
并且你试图沿着左子节点或右子节点向下移动
but those pointers are null, then you know
但是这些指针为空，那么你就知道
you didn't find it because you would have returned true sooner
你没有找到它，因为如果你找到了，你就会更早地返回真
if anything had been in fact equal.
如果任何东西实际上是相等的。
So that then is recursive code for searching a binary search tree, which
所以这就是搜索二叉搜索树的递归代码，它
is, again, just to connect the dots of what we introduced
再次，只是为了将我们之前介绍的内容联系起来
last time of actually doing things now recursively
上一次实际上是递归地做事
and revisiting some of our own week 0 problems.
并重新审视我们自己的第 0 周的一些问题。
But I'm kind of lying to you here.
但我在这里有点在骗你。
Yes, this is a binary search tree.
是的，这是一棵二叉搜索树。
But it's not always as pretty as this.
但它并不总是像这样漂亮。
It's certainly not always seven elements.
它肯定并不总是七个元素。
But it doesn't actually have to be as well-balanced as this one here is.
但它实际上不必像这里的那样平衡。
In fact, suppose that we insert the following numbers
事实上，假设我们插入以下数字
into an empty list starting with 2.
到一个空列表中，从 2 开始。
I can plop the 2 right there.
我可以把 2 放在那里。
That's the current root of this tree.
那是这棵树的当前根节点。
Suppose, though, that I insert next the number--
但是，假设我接下来插入数字——
how about 1?
1 怎么样？
Well, it stands to reason that it should go now to the left.
好吧，它应该去左边，这很合理。
And so now this is the tree of size 2.
所以现在这棵树的大小是 2。
Now, I insert the number, say, 3.
现在，我插入一个数字，比如 3。
It, of course, can go there.
当然，它可以放在那里。
So that makes perfect sense.
这很有道理。
And I just got lucky.
我只是运气好。
Because I inserted these numbers as 2 then one then 3,
因为我插入的数字是 2 然后 1 然后 3，
I very cleanly got a balanced tree that waited properly left and right.
我非常干净地得到了一棵平衡树，它左右都处于适当的位置。
But what if you have a more perverse set of inputs so to speak.
但如果你有更多“病态”的输入呢，可以这么说。
You're not lucky.
你没有那么幸运。
And the worst possible situation happens in terms
在人类输入数据顺序方面，最糟糕的情况发生了
of the order in which the human is inputting data
人类输入数据顺序方面，最糟糕的情况发生了
into this data structure.
到这个数据结构中。
What if the human inserts 1 first?
如果人类首先插入 1 呢？
OK, well, it goes as the root of the tree.
好的，它就作为树的根节点。
But here's where things start to devolve.
但事情从这里开始恶化。
What if the human then inserts 2?
如果人类接着插入 2 呢？
OK, it goes there.
好的，它就在那里。
What if the human then inserts 3?
如果人类接着插入 3 呢？
Well, according to our definition, it goes there.
好吧，根据我们的定义，它就在那里。
It looks like part of a tree because of how I've drawn it.
因为它是我画的，所以看起来像树的一部分。
But what is it really if you tilt your head, right?
但如果你歪着头看，它究竟是什么呢？
It looks really just like a linked list.
它看起来真的就像一个链表。
And there really is no second dimension.
实际上它没有第二个维度。
I've drawn it this way.
我这样画了它。
But this for all intents and purposes is a linked list of size 3.
但就所有意图和目的而言，这是一个大小为 3 的链表。
Why?
为什么？
Because there's no halving.
因为没有二分。
There's no actual choosing left or right.
实际上没有选择左边或右边。
Now, this is fixable.
现在，这是可以修复的。
How could you fix this?
你如何修复它？
It's still the same numbers 1, 2, 3.
它仍然是相同的数字 1、2、3。
And it does adhere to the binary search tree definition.
它确实符合二叉搜索树的定义。
Every number to the right is greater.
右边的每个数字都更大。
Every number to the left is-- well, it's inapplicable.
左边的每个数字...好吧，它不适用。
But it certainly doesn't violate that definition.
但这当然没有违反那个定义。
Could you fix this tree somehow and make it
你能以某种方式修复这棵树，并使其
balanced so it's not devolving into big O of n
平衡，这样它就不会退化为 O(n)
but is still technically log of n?
但仍然在技术上是 log(n)？
What should be the root?
根节点应该是什么？
AUDIENCE: You just reverse the pointer from 1 to 2.
观众：你只需将指向 1 的指针反转到指向 2。
DAVID J. MALAN: So I could reverse the pointer from 1 to 2.
David J. Malan：所以我可以将指向 1 的指针反转到指向 2。
And so sort of pictorially if I take this
所以如果我从图像上来看，把这个
and I just swing everything over and make 2 the new route,
把所有东西都移过去，让 2 成为新的根节点，
then, indeed, this could be the new root up here.
那么，确实，这个可以作为这里的新根节点。
1 could be hanging off of it over here and 3 can be hanging off of the 2
1 可以从这里挂在它上面，3 可以从 2 上挂下来
as is.
就这样。
So long story short, when it comes to binary search trees, by themselves
所以长话短说，当谈到二叉搜索树本身时，
they don't necessarily guarantee any balance.
它们不一定能保证任何平衡。
So even though theoretically, yes, it's big O of log n, which is fantastic,
所以即使从理论上讲，是的，它是 log n 的 O 大，这太棒了，
not if you get a perverse set of inputs that
但如果你得到了一组反常的输入，
just happen to be, for instance, the worst possible scenario-- now,
恰好是，例如，最糟糕的场景——现在，
it is fixable.
是可以解决的。
And, in fact, in higher level courses in computer science,
事实上，在计算机科学的高级课程中，
specifically on algorithms and data structures,
特别是关于算法和数据结构的课程中，
you'll be introduced, if you go down that road, of how
如果你走上这条路，你会被介绍到如何
you can tweak the code for insertion and deletion in a binary search tree
调整二叉搜索树中插入和删除的代码
to make these fixes along the way.
以便沿途进行这些修复。
And it's going to cost you a few more steps to fix things
修复这些问题会让你多花几步。
when they get out of whack.
当它们变得不正常时。
But if you do it every insertion or every deletion,
但是如果你在每次插入或删除时都这样做，
at least you can maintain a balanced tree.
至少你可以保持树的平衡。
And you'll learn about different types of balanced trees.
你将学习不同类型的平衡树。
But for our purposes now, we don't necessarily
但对于我们现在的目的，我们不一定
get that property even if we do want log n unless you
能得到那个属性，即使我们确实想要 log n，除非你
keep it balanced along the way.
一路保持它的平衡。
Now, what about other combinations of arrays and linked lists?
现在，数组和链表的其他组合呢？
We can really start to mash these things up and see what comes out of them.
我们可以真正开始将这些东西混合在一起，看看会产生什么。
Dictionaries are another abstract data type
字典是另一种抽象数据类型
similar in spirit to stacks and queues in that you can implement them
与堆栈和队列类似，因为你可以用不同的方式实现它们
in different ways.
以不同的方式。
A dictionary is a data structure that stores keys and values.
字典是一种存储键和值的数据结构。
And those are technical terms, keys and values.
而这些是专业术语，键和值。
The analog in the human world would be literally a dictionary
在人类世界中，它的类似物就是一本真正的字典
that you'd have in a classroom, a dictionary with words
你将在教室里拥有的字典，一本包含单词的字典
and definitions, more generally known as keys and values.
和定义，更广为人知的键和值。
So that's all a dictionary is.
这就是字典的全部内容。
It associates keys with values.
它将键与值关联起来。
So, for instance, you could think of it almost as
所以，例如，你可以把它看成几乎像
like two columns in a spreadsheet, where on the left
电子表格中的两列，左边
you put the key, on the right you put the value.
你放键，右边你放值。
Or, specifically, you put the word in a dictionary and the definition
或者，具体来说，你在字典中放单词，然后放定义
thereafter.
在那之后。
And that's roughly how the printed pages in a dictionary are laid out.
字典中打印的页面大致就是这样排列的。
So dictionaries associate words with definitions or more generally
所以字典将单词与定义相关联，或者更一般地
keys with values.
将键与值相关联。
But it's an abstract data type in that we could
但它是一种抽象数据类型，因为我们可以
implement this in a bunch of ways.
用很多种方式实现它。
We could use maybe two arrays, one array for the keys,
我们可以使用两个数组，一个数组用于键，
one array for the definitions.
一个数组用于定义。
And you just hope that they line up.
你只需要希望它们排成一行。
Bracket i in this one maps to bracket i in this one.
这个数组中的索引 i 对应于这个数组中的索引 i。
But an array is not going to give us the dynamism that we want.
但数组不会给我们我们想要的那种动态性。
You might run out of space when Merriam-Webster or whoever
当韦氏词典或其他机构
adds new words to the English language.
将新单词添加到英语中时，你可能会用光空间。
You might not want to be using an array.
你可能不想使用数组。
You might want to use a linked list.
你可能想使用链表。
But, again, linked lists then devolve into big O of n.
但是，同样地，链表会退化为O(n)的时间复杂度。
And that's not good for dictionaries and spell checking.
这对字典和拼写检查来说是不利的。
If you have to check every possible word to find something,
如果你必须检查每个可能的单词来查找某个东西，
getting something that's a little faster than that is compelling.
找到比这更快的方法就很有吸引力。
So let's consider how maybe Apple, maybe Google, maybe others are actually
所以让我们考虑一下苹果，谷歌，或者其他公司是如何实现通讯录的。
implementing contacts.
通讯录的。
Because even though I implied in week 0 and maybe outright said,
因为虽然我在第零周暗示过，也可能直接说，
it's an array-- it's a big list of all of your names of contacts maybe of some
它是一个数组——它是一个包含你所有联系人名字的很大的列表，可能是固定大小的
fixed size--
固定大小的——
they probably better be using some variant of a linked list, otherwise,
他们可能最好使用链表的某种变体，否则，
you could never add more friends potentially.
你可能永远无法添加更多朋友。
You'd max out.
你会达到上限。
And they'd say you have to unfriend someone just to fit it.
他们会说你必须取消关注某个人才能容纳下来。
As an aside, this is sort of true in the social media world.
顺便说一句，这在社交媒体的世界里是有点真实的。
Once you have 5,000 friends on Facebook, you can't have 5,001.
一旦你在 Facebook 上有 5000 个朋友，你就不能再有 5001 个朋友了。
Once you have some number on LinkedIn, you can't have more connections.
一旦你在 LinkedIn 上有一定数量的连接，你就不能再有更多连接了。
That's not necessarily that they're using arrays.
这并不一定意味着他们使用的是数组。
But it is the same implication that they've
但这意味着他们已经
chosen some finite size for memory.
为内存选择了某个有限的大小。
So how might we consider implementing a dictionary specifically
那么我们该如何考虑专门为你的地址簿或联系人实现字典，
for your address book or your contacts so you
这样你就可以
can store the names of everyone ideally alphabetically
存储所有人的姓名，理想情况下按字母顺序排序，
but also their phone numbers and maybe anything else?
但也要存储他们的电话号码，以及可能的其他信息？
Well, ultimately, we want to be able to get at someone's name
好吧，最终，我们希望能够获取某人的姓名
and lead to their number.
并找到他们的号码。
So the keys and values for our discussion
因此，在我们讨论中，键和值
here will be names are the keys and phone numbers or the values.
将是姓名作为键，电话号码作为值。
But the values themselves could also include email address and a mailing
但值本身还可以包含电子邮件地址和邮寄地址等等。
address and all of that.
地址等等。
But we'll keep it simple, names and phone numbers.
但我们会保持简单，姓名和电话号码。
So here's how you might think about this or draw it
所以你可以这样思考或画出来，
on a chalkboard, two columns or in a spreadsheet, left and right.
在黑板上画两列，或者在电子表格中画两列，左边和右边。
But how could we actually implement this in memory?
但我们如何在内存中实现它呢？
Because, ideally, we don't want it to devolve into something linear.
因为理想情况下，我们不希望它退化为线性结构。
We don't want to have to look through all of my friends
我们不想必须查看我所有朋友的
and family and colleagues to find someone whose name starts
家人和同事，才能找到一个名字以
with Z, for instance, or anything else.
Z 开头的人，或者其他任何名字的人。
It would be nice to have something logarithmic with binary search.
如果能有对数时间复杂度的东西，使用二分搜索就好了。
But with binary search again, we have to maybe use a tree instead.
但再次使用二分搜索，我们可能需要使用树。
But now we have to use two pointers instead of one.
但现在我们必须使用两个指针而不是一个。
there's a lot of trade offs here.
这里有很多权衡。
But let's see how else we could solve this same problem.
但让我们看看如何用其他方法解决同一个问题。
Because wouldn't it be nice-- and we've not really talked about this before--
因为不是很好吗——我们以前没有真正谈论过这个——
if we instead aspire to this Holy Grail of algorithms?
如果我们渴望得到这种算法的圣杯呢？
The best algorithm out there is surely one that's big O of 1,
最好的算法一定是 O(1) 的算法，
like constant time, because what that means
比如常数时间，因为这意味着
is it doesn't matter if you have 1 friend, 10 friends, 100, 1,000,
无论你有 1 个朋友、10 个朋友、100 个朋友、1000 个朋友，
a million, a billion friends--
一百万个朋友、十亿个朋友——
it doesn't matter how big n is, your searches will always
无论 n 的大小，你的搜索总是
take you the same amount of time.
花费相同的时间。
It is independent of n.
它与 n 无关。
And that's why it's sort of the ultimate goal for performance.
这就是为什么它被认为是性能的终极目标。
So can we get to this aspiration?
所以我们能实现这个目标吗？
Well, a couple of building blocks.
嗯，几个组成部分。
There's this notion in computing known as hashing.
在计算机中有一个叫做哈希的概念。
And hashing is a technique, literally a function
哈希是一种技术，实际上是一个函数
in math or in code that actually takes any number of inputs and maps
在数学或代码中，它可以接受任意数量的输入并将它们映射
them to a finite number of outputs.
到有限数量的输出。
So if you think back to high school math, domains, and ranges,
所以如果你回忆一下高中数学中的定义域和值域，
you can take an infinite domain with any values in the world.
你可以取一个无限的定义域，它可以包含世界上任何值。
But it reduces them, a hash function, to a finite range of specific values.
但是哈希函数将它们简化为一个有限的值域。
So, for instance, it's no accident that we have these four buckets on the stage
例如，我们现在舞台上的这四个桶并非偶然，
now, each of which has a suit from a deck of cards.
它们分别代表一副扑克牌中的一个花色。
We got for visibility's sake the biggest cards we can.
为了便于观察，我们选用了最大的扑克牌。
These are the super, jumbo playing cards.
这些是超大型的扑克牌。
And in this box are a bunch of randomly ordered playing cards.
这个箱子里放着一堆随机排列的扑克牌。
And, typically, if you were to ever play some game
通常，如果你要玩一些游戏，
or you wanted to these for some reason, how would
或者出于某种原因，你想使用它们，你会怎么做？
you go about sorting them by suit and also by number?
你会如何按花色和数字对它们进行排序？
Odds are if you're like me, you'd probably take some shortcuts
如果你像我一样，你可能会采取一些捷径，
and maybe pull out all of the hearts, pull out all of the spades,
比如把所有的红桃都拿出来，把所有的黑桃都拿出来，
pull out all of the clubs, or you bucketize it into categories.
把所有的梅花都拿出来，或者你把它们分类到不同的桶里。
And that term is actually technical.
这个词实际上是专业的术语。
Here are four buckets to make this clear.
这里有四个桶来使这一点更清楚。
And, for instance, if the first card I find is the five of hearts,
例如，如果我找到的第一张牌是红桃 5，
you know what?
你知道吗？
Just to make my life easier, I'm going to put that into the hearts bucket.
为了方便起见，我要把它放到红桃的桶里。
Or here we have 4.
或者这里有 4。
Here we have 5.
这里有 5。
Here we have 6.
这里有 6。
Here we have queen.
这里有 Q。
And notice that I'm putting these cards into the appropriate buckets.
请注意，我正在把这些牌放到合适的桶里。
Why?
为什么呢？
Because, ultimately, then I'm going to have four problems but of smaller
因为最终，我将有四个问题，但它们都更小，
size, a 13 size problem, 13, 13, 13.
规模，13 个问题，13 个，13 个，13 个。
And, frankly, it's just going to be easier cognitively, daresay
坦率地说，从认知上讲，这将更容易，甚至可以这么说，
algorithmically, to then sort each of the 13 cards in these buckets
从算法上讲，然后对这些桶里的 13 张牌进行排序
rather than deal with four suits somehow combined all together.
比将四种花色混合在一起处理要容易得多。
So if you've ever in life made piles-- if you've ever literally used buckets
所以如果你在生活中曾经做过一堆堆的东西——如果你曾经用过像这样的桶
like this, you are hashing.
那么你就是在使用哈希。
I'm taking some number of inputs, 52 in this case.
我正在接收一些输入，本例中是 52 个。
And I'm mapping it to a finite number of outputs, 4 in this case.
我将它们映射到有限数量的输出，本例中是 4 个。
So hashing, again, just takes in inputs and hashes them
所以哈希，再次强调，它接收输入并对其进行哈希处理
to output values in this way.
以这种方式输出值。
So beyond that terminology, let's consider
除了术语之外，让我们考虑一下
what we can now do with hash functions that's
现在我们可以用哈希函数做些什么，它
a little more germane to storing things like our friends and family
与存储像朋友、家人这样东西更相关
and colleagues in dictionaries.
以及同事在字典中。
A hash function is just one that does that.
哈希函数就是这样做的。
I as the human was just implementing or behaving like a hash function.
作为人类，我只是在实现或模拟一个哈希函数。
But technically a hash function is actually
但从技术上讲，一个哈希函数实际上是
a math function or a function in C or scratch
一个数学函数，或者一个 C 语言函数或 Scratch 函数
or soon Python or other languages that takes as input some value,
或者很快的 Python 或其他语言，它接收一个值作为输入，
be it a physical card or a name or a number or something else,
无论是实体卡、姓名、数字还是其他东西，
and outputs some value.
并输出一个值。
And we can use hashing as an operation to implement
我们可以使用哈希作为一种操作来实现
what we'll call hash tables.
我们所说的哈希表。
And that's what that dictionary was.
这就是那个字典。
If you think about how I drew it on the screen as two columns,
如果你想想我在屏幕上如何将其绘制成两列，
it's like a table of information, keys on the left, values on the right.
它就像一张信息表，左边是键，右边是值。
So what is a hash table?
那么什么是哈希表呢？
The simplest way to think about it is that this
最简单的理解方式是，它
is an amalgam, a combination of arrays and linked lists right.
是一个融合体，数组和链表的组合。
We borrowed some ideas of linked lists a moment ago
我们借用了链表的一些概念
to give us trees in two dimensions.
来构建二维树。
What if we stick with this idea of having two-dimensional worlds
如果我们坚持二维世界的概念
but now use an array initially?
但现在最初使用一个数组呢？
So we get the speed benefits of arrays because everything's contiguous.
这样我们就获得了数组的速度优势，因为所有元素都是连续的。
We can do simple arithmetic and jump to the middle or the middle or the middle
我们可以进行简单的算术运算，并跳转到中间，或中间，或中间
or the first or the last very easily.
或者第一个或最后一个，非常容易。
And then you know what?
然后你猜怎么着？
Let's use the horizontal part of the screen
让我们使用屏幕的水平部分
to give us linked lists as needed.
来提供我们所需的链表。
So, for instance, if the goal at hand is to implement the contacts in my cell
例如，如果当前的目标是实现我的手机、Mac 或 PC 中的联系人，
phone or my Mac or PC, let me propose that we start at least in English
我建议我们至少用英语开始
with an array of size 26.
一个大小为 26 的数组。
Of course, it's 0 index.
当然，它是 0 索引。
So it's really location 0 through 25.
所以实际上它是位置 0 到 25。
And for the sake of discussion, let me propose that location 0 represents
为了讨论，我建议位置 0 代表
A. Location 25 represents z.
A，位置 25 代表 z。
And then everything else in between.
然后是介于两者之间的所有其他字母。
Why?
为什么？
We know from C that we can convert thanks to ASCII and Unicode
我们从 C 语言中得知，我们可以借助 ASCII 和 Unicode 进行转换
from letters to numbers and back and forth.
将字母转换为数字，反之亦然。
So in constant time, we can find location A. In constant time
所以我们可以用恒定时间找到位置 A，用恒定时间
we can find location Z. Why?
我们可以找到位置 Z。为什么？
Because we're using an array just like in week 2.
因为我们使用的是数组，就像第 2 周一样。
All right, well, suppose that I want to think
好吧，假设我想考虑一下
about these more as letters of the alphabet, the English alphabet
将这些更多地看作字母表，即英语字母表
rather than numbers.
而不是数字。
So it's equivalent to label them A through Z.
所以，相当于将它们标记为从 A 到 Z。
And suppose now I want to start adding friends and family and contacts
假设现在我想开始添加朋友、家人和联系人
to my address book.
到我的通讯录中。
How might this look?
这可能是什么样子？
Well, if the first one I want to add is Mario--
嗯，如果我想添加的第一个是马里奥——
Mario's name starts with an M. And so that's A, B, C, D, E, F--
马里奥的名字以 M 开头。所以，这是 A、B、C、D、E、F——
OK, M goes there.
好的，M 放在那里。
So I'm going to put Mario at that location in the array.
所以我要将马里奥放在数组中的那个位置。
After that, I add a second person, for instance, how about Luigi?
在那之后，我添加第二个人，例如，路易吉怎么样？
Well, L comes just before M. So it stands
嗯，L 在 M 之前。所以，它代表
to reason that it goes there in the array.
可以理解，它应该放在数组中的那个位置。
Meanwhile, if I go and add another character like peach,
同时，如果我去添加另一个角色，例如碧奇，
she's going to go there a few spots away because her name starts
她将会放在离那个位置几个位置的地方，因为她的名字以
with P. Meanwhile, here's a whole bunch of other Nintendo characters
P 开头。同时，这里有一堆其他任天堂角色
that happen to have unique letters of their first names.
碰巧他们的名字首字母都是唯一的。
And there's room for everyone, room for everyone on the board A
而且每个人都有空间，每个人在 A 上都有空间
through Z with some blanks in the middle.
到 Z，中间有一些空白。
But you can perhaps see where this is going.
但也许你可以看到事情的发展方向。
When and where might a problem arise with this array-based approach?
这种基于数组的方法何时何地会遇到问题？
AUDIENCE: When you add [INAUDIBLE].
观众：当你添加 [听不清]。
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, so when we add someone
大卫·马兰：是的，所以当我们添加某人
else who's name collides with one of these existing characters,
其他人，他们的名字与这些现有角色之一冲突，
just because by accident, they have a name that starts with the same letter--
仅仅因为偶然，他们的名字首字母相同——
So, for instance, there's Lakitu here who collides with Luigi potentially.
例如，这里有拉基图，他可能会与路易吉冲突。
Here is Link who collides with both of them.
这里有林克，他与他们两个都冲突。
But I've drawn a solution to this along the way.
但我已经沿途绘制了解决方案。
I could if I was Kronion just remove Luigi from the data structure
如果我是克罗尼翁，我可以从数据结构中删除路易吉
and put Lakitu in or remove and then put Link in there instead.
并将拉基图放进去，或者删除然后将林克放进去。
But that's stupid if you can only have one friend whose name starts with L.
但如果你的朋友中只有一个名字以 L 开头，那就太蠢了。
That's just bad design.
这仅仅是糟糕的设计。
But what if we now in the off chance I have two friends whose names start
但如果现在碰巧我有两个朋友的名字以
with the same letter, well, I'll just string them together,
相同字母开头，好吧，我只要把它们串在一起，
link them together, no pun intended, using pointers of sorts.
将它们连接起来，没有双关语的意思，使用指针之类的东西。
So my vertical here is an array.
所以这里我的垂直方向是一个数组。
And this is just an artist's rendition.
这只是一个艺术家的描绘。
There's no actual notion of up, down, left, right in the computer's memory.
在计算机的内存中没有向上、向下、向左、向右的实际概念。
But this is my array always of size 26.
但我的这个数组始终大小为 26。
And each of the elements in this array are now not a simple number.
而且这个数组中的每个元素现在不再是一个简单的数字。
But it's a pointer to a linked list.
而它指向一个链表。
And if there's nothing there, it's just null, null, null, null.
如果那里什么也没有，它就是 null、null、null、null。
But, otherwise, it's a valid address that points to the first node.
但，否则，它是一个有效的地址，指向第一个节点。
And you know what?
你知道吗？
If we have multiple names with the same letters,
如果我们有多个名字有相同的字母，
we can just string these nodes together together using pointers as well.
我们也可以使用指针将这些节点串联在一起。
So a hash table then as implemented here is an array of linked lists.
因此，这里实现的哈希表是一个链接列表数组。
And that allows us to, one, get some speed benefit
这让我们可以，首先，获得一些速度优势
because look how fast we inserted or found Mario, Luigi, and Peach.
因为你看我们插入或找到马里奥、路易吉和碧奇的速度有多快。
But it still covers the scenario where, OK, some people
但这仍然涵盖了这样的情况，好吧，有些人
can have the same first letters.
可能会有相同的首字母。
Some of these names will collide.
这些名字中的一些会发生冲突。
So collisions are an expected problem with a hash table,
所以冲突是哈希表中预期的一个问题，
whereby two values from some domain happen to map to the same value.
即来自某个域的两个值恰好映射到同一个值。
And, frankly, you'll see this here too.
坦白地说，你在这里也会看到这一点。
So these buckets are technically a finite size.
所以这些桶在技术上是有限大小的。
They're definitely big enough for 13 cards each.
它们肯定足够大，每个桶可以容纳 13 张牌。
But you could imagine a world where if I'm using 2 decks, 3 decks, or 4 decks,
但你可以想象一个世界，如果我使用 2 副牌、3 副牌或 4 副牌，
I'm going to run out of space.
我将耗尽空间。
And then my data structure can't fit any more information.
然后我的数据结构无法容纳更多信息。
But we're not going to have this problem here
但我们在这里不会遇到这个问题
because the linked lists, as we've seen, can grow and even shrink
因为我们已经看到，链接列表可以增长甚至缩小
as much as they want.
它们想要多大就多大。
In the world of Nintendo there's actually lots of collisions.
在任天堂的世界里，实际上有很多冲突。
And these aren't even all of the characters.
而且这些甚至不是所有的角色。
So that's then a hash table.
这就是哈希表。
So with a hash table in mind, how fast is it?
那么，考虑到哈希表，它的速度有多快？
Did we achieve that Holy Grail of constant time?
我们是否实现了常数时间的圣杯？
Well, for some of these names if I back up, yeah, it's kind of constant time.
嗯，对于其中的一些名字，如果我后退，是的，它有点像常数时间。
Yoshi and Zelda, boom, constant time, location 24, location 25.
耀西和塞尔达，砰，常数时间，位置 24，位置 25。
Some of them, though, like Luigi, Link, it's
然而，其中一些，比如路易吉、林克，它
not quite constant time because I first have to get to Luigi's location.
不是完全的常数时间，因为我首先要到达路易吉的位置。
And then I have to follow this linked list.
然后我必须沿着这个链接列表走。
So, technically, then what's the running time of searching a hash table?
所以，从技术上讲，搜索哈希表的时间复杂度是多少？
Sometimes you'll get lucky.
有时你会很幸运。
But sometimes you won't.
但有时你不会。
Consider the worst case.
考虑最坏的情况。
Big O is often used to describe worst case.
大 O 通常用来描述最坏情况。
So what would be the worst case in your own context?
那么在你自己的语境中，最坏的情况是什么？
A little louder.
大声点。
So NY.
所以纽约。
AUDIENCE: Because you might use [INAUDIBLE]..
观众：因为你可能会使用 [听不清]..
DAVID J. MALAN: Correct.
大卫·J·马兰：没错。
And so to summarize in some weird scenario
所以，概括地说，在某种奇怪的情况下
all of your friends and family and contacts
你所有的朋友、家人和联系人
could have names that start with the same letter.
可能都有以同一个字母开头的名字。
And then it doesn't matter that this is a hash table
然后，这个哈希表是什么就无关紧要了
with an array of linked lists.
这是一个链接列表数组。
For all intents and purposes, if your friends names only
从本质上来说，如果你的朋友的名字只
start with the same letter, all you have is a linked list.
以同一个字母开头，你拥有的就是一个链接列表。
Much like with a tree, if you don't keep it balanced, all you have really
就像树一样，如果你不保持它的平衡，你拥有的实际上
is a linked list.
就是一个链接列表。
So technically speaking, yes, hash tables are big O of n
所以从技术上讲，是的，哈希表的复杂度是 O(n)
even if you're good about--
即使你很擅长--
even if you have--
即使你拥有--
in the worst case, hash tables are big O of n.
在最坏的情况下，哈希表的时间复杂度为 O(n)。
Why?
为什么？
Because it can devolve into this perverse scenario
因为哈希表可能会演变成这种奇怪的情况
where you just have lots and lots of collisions all at the same values.
你会有很多很多碰撞，而且它们都发生在相同的键值上。
But there's got to be a way to fix this.
但一定有办法解决这个问题。
How could we chip away at the length of these chains so to speak?
我们可以用什么方法缩短这些链条的长度呢？
Could I decrease the length of these linked lists
我可以减少这些链表的长度吗？
so that with much higher probability there's no collisions?
这样碰撞发生的概率就会大大降低？
Well, maybe the problem is that I started with just 26 buckets.
也许问题在于我一开始只用了 26 个桶。
I mean, four buckets here, 26 here.
也就是说，这里有 4 个桶，这里有 26 个桶。
Maybe the problem is the size of my array.
也许问题在于我的数组的大小。
So what if I instead just give myself a bigger array,
那么，如果我给我的数组分配更大的空间呢？
and it's too big to fit on the screen--
而且它太大了，无法显示在屏幕上——
but what if I instead have a dollar for names that start with Laa and Lab,
但是，如果我为以 Laa 和 Lab 开头的名字分配一个桶呢？
and Lac, Lad, do, dot, dot, all the way down?
还有 Lac、Lad、do、dot、dot，一直到最后？
Now, when I hash these names into my hash table,
现在，当我将这些名字哈希到我的哈希表中时，
Lakitu is going to end up at their own location
Lakitu 将会落到它自己的位置
here, link at their own location here, Luigi at their own location here.
在这里，link 落到它自己的位置在这里，Luigi 落到它自己的位置在这里。
And so now I don't have linked lists.
所以现在我就不再有链表了。
I really just have an array of names.
我实际上只有一个包含名字的数组。
So now I'm actually back to constant time.
所以我现在又回到了常数时间。
Why?
为什么？
Because so long as every letter of the alphabet has an ASCII value,
因为只要字母表中的每个字母都有一个 ASCII 值，
I can get that in constant time.
我就能在常数时间内得到它。
And we did that as far back as week one.
我们早在第一周就做过这个了。
And so I can figure out what the arithmetic location
所以我可以计算出每个桶的算术位置
is of each of these buckets just by looking
只需要看一看
at 1, 2, 3 characters or the total number of letters that I care about,
1、2、3 个字符，或者我关注的字母总数，
which is just 3 in this case.
在本例中，它只有 3 个。
So this feels like a solution.
所以这看起来像是一个解决方案。
Even though I haven't drawn all the names,
虽然我没有画出所有的名字，
it feels like we've solved the problem.
但感觉我们已经解决了这个问题。
But what's the downside or trade off of what we've just done?
但是，我们刚做的有什么缺点或权衡呢？
AUDIENCE: Memory.
观众：内存。
DAVID J. MALAN: Sorry?
大卫·马兰：抱歉？
AUDIENCE: Memory.
观众：内存。
DAVID J. MALAN: Memory.
大卫·马兰：内存。
So not pictured here is the dot, dot, dot, and everything
所以这里没有画出点、点、点，以及所有
above and everything below.
上面的和下面的东西。
This just exploded in terms of the number of locations in this array.
从数组中位置数量的角度来看，这简直是爆炸式增长。
Why?
为什么？
Because if I'm taking into account not just the first letter
因为如果我不仅仅考虑第一个字母，
but the first, the second, and third, that's 26 to the third power,
还要考虑第一个、第二个和第三个字母，那就是 26 的三次方，
26 times 26 times 26.
26 乘以 26 乘以 26。
And even though there's going to be a crazy number of names
虽然会有很多名字根本不存在——
that just don't exist--
我不认为有一个任天堂角色的名字是以 Laa 开头的——
I can't think of a Nintendo character whose name starts with Laa--
你仍然需要那个桶。
you still need that bucket.
为什么？
Why?
因为，否则，你就无法保持连续性。
Because, otherwise, you don't have contiguousness.
You can't just arbitrarily label these buckets.
你不能随意给这些桶贴标签。
If you want to be able to use a function that
如果你想使用一个函数，
looks at first, second, third letter and then arithmetically figures
它可以查看第一个、第二个、第三个字母，然后算出
out where to go, whether it's 0 to 25 or 0 to 26 to the third power minus 1
应该去哪里，无论是从 0 到 25 还是从 0 到 26 的三次方减 1，
being the number of buckets there--
作为桶的数量——
so there's a trade off there.
所以这里有一个权衡。
You're wasting a huge amount of memory just to give yourself that time.
你只是为了给自己争取时间而浪费了大量的内存。
But that would then give us constant time.
但这会让我们获得恒定时间。
So in that sense, if we have an ideal hash function whereby
从这个意义上说，如果我们有一个理想的哈希函数，
the function ensures that no values collide,
该函数确保没有值发生冲突，
we do actually obtain that that Grail of big O of 1 because it only
我们实际上得到了那个 O(1) 的圣杯，因为它只需要
takes one or maybe three steps to find that names location.
一到三步就能找到那个名字的位置。
Now, to make this clear, how do we translate this to something like code?
现在，为了说明这一点，我们如何将其转化成类似代码的东西呢？
Well, here again is the struct we used last time for that of a person
好吧，这里又是我们上次使用过的结构体，用于表示一个人
and a person had a name and a number.
一个人有名字和号码。
Here, for a hash table, we might do something a little bit differently.
这里，对于哈希表，我们可能会做一些不同的事情。
We might now have a node in a hash table storing the person's name,
我们现在可能在哈希表中有一个节点，它存储着该人的姓名，
person's phone number, and a pointer to the next such person
电话号码，以及指向下一个此类人的指针
in that chain if needed.
在该链中，如果需要。
Hopefully this is going to be null most of the time, all of the time.
希望这在大多数情况下，都是空的。
But we need it just in case we do have that collision.
但我们需要它，以防万一发生冲突。
We've seen in our pictures the names, like Mario, Luigi, and so forth.
我们已经看到了我们的图片中的名字，比如马里奥、路易吉等等。
We didn't see the numbers.
我们没有看到数字。
But that's what's inside of those boxes on the picture.
但这就是图片中那些方框里的内容。
But that node would give us what we need to build up these linked lists.
但那个节点会给我们构建这些链表所需的东西。
Meanwhile what is the hash table itself, that vertical strip along the left?
同时，哈希表本身是什么，左边那条垂直的条带？
Well, it's really just a variable.
嗯，它实际上只是一个变量。
We could call it table for short of size 26.
我们可以简称为 table，大小为 26。
And each of the locations in that array that was on the side
而且该数组中每个位于侧面位置的
here, at least in the simple, small version, was a pointer to a node.
东西，至少在简单的小版本中，都是指向一个节点的指针。
So it's null if there's no one there or it's
所以，如果那里没有人，它就是空值，或者它就是
a valid address of the first node in the linked list.
链表中第一个节点的有效地址。
So this then is a hash table.
所以，这就是哈希表。
And each of those nodes, to be clear, would be defined as follows.
为了明确起见，每个节点的定义如下。
So what's the takeaway then with a hash table?
那么，哈希表的要点是什么？
Ideally, with a good hash function and with a good set
理想情况下，使用一个好的哈希函数和一个好的集合
of inputs where you're not presented with some perverse set of inputs that's
输入，你不会遇到一些奇怪的输入集，这些输入集
all of the friends whose names start with the same letter,
都是名字以同一个字母开头的朋友，
ideally what the hash function will be doing for you is this.
理想情况下，哈希函数为你做的是这件事。
The input is going to be someone's name.
输入将是某人的名字。
The algorithm in the middle is going to be the hash function.
中间的算法将是哈希函数。
And the output is the so-called hash value or location in this case.
输出是所谓的哈希值，在本例中也就是位置。
So, for instance, in the case of Mario, when we had just--
例如，在马里奥的情况下，当我们只有——
when we had just 26 buckets total, the input to the hash function
当我们只有 26 个桶时，哈希函数的输入
would be Mario.
这将是马里奥。
That hash function would really just look
这个哈希函数实际上只是查看
at the first letter, M in that case, and would ideally output the number 12.
第一个字母，在这种情况下是M，理想情况下会输出数字12。
I did the same thing.
我做了同样的事情。
But in my head, whenever I pulled out a card like the five of diamonds here,
但在我脑海里，每当我抽出一张牌，比如这里的一张方块5，
I figured out, OK, that's location 0 out of my 0, 1, 2, 3, 4 four total buckets.
我就能算出来，好的，这是我的0、1、2、3、4四个桶中的第0个位置。
Here we're doing it instead alphabetically.
这里我们按字母顺序排列。
And so someone like Luigi meanwhile would have a hash value of 11.
所以像路易吉这样的人，他的哈希值为11。
These numbers would be bigger, of course,
这些数字当然会更大，
though, if we're looking at 1, 2, 3 letters instead of just one.
不过，如果我们查看1、2、3个字母，而不是只有一个字母。
So with that said, if we were to implement this in actual code,
所以说，如果我们要在实际代码中实现这个，
a hash function?
哈希函数？
I did it physically by acting out the cards.
我通过实际操作牌来实现它。
Here is how we might implement this in code
以下是我们在代码中实现这个方法的方式
using C. I could have a function called hash whose argument is a string, a.k.a.
使用C语言。我可以有一个名为hash的函数，它的参数是一个字符串，也就是
char star, a name of which is word where the word is
char star，它的名字是word，这个word就是
like the first word in their name.
他们名字中的第一个词。
We want this function to return an int, which
我们希望这个函数返回一个int，它
ideally in this case of 26 buckets would be a number from 0 to 26.
理想情况下，在这种26个桶的情况下，它将是一个从0到26的数字。
And how do we achieve that?
我们如何实现呢？
Well, if we use our old friend ctype, which had a function like toUpper
好吧，如果我们使用我们的老朋友ctype，它有一个像toUpper这样的函数
from a couple of weeks back, we could pass in the first letter of that word,
从几周前开始，我们可以传入该词的第一个字母，
capitalize it, which is going to give us a number that's 65, 66, 67
将其大写，这将给我们一个数字，分别是65、66、67
on up for the 26 English letters.
一直到26个英文字母。
And if I subtract 65, a.k.a., quote, unquote--
如果我减去65，也就是“引号”
single quotes because it's a char--
单引号，因为它是一个char
that's going to mathematically give me a number between 0 and 25 inclusive.
这将从数学上给我一个0到25之间的数字，包括0和25。
There's a potential bug.
这里有一个潜在的错误。
If I pass in punctuation or anything that's not alphabetical,
如果我传入标点符号或任何不是字母的东西，
bad things will happen.
就会出现问题。
So I should probably have some more error checking,
所以我可能应该做一些额外的错误检查，
but this is the simplest way in code that I
但这在我能够实现的代码中，是最简单的方式
could implement a hash function that looks only
来实现一个只查看
at the first letter of their name.
他们名字的首字母的哈希函数。
Probably not ideal because I can think of friends in the real world who have
可能不太理想，因为我能想到现实生活中的一些朋友，他们
the same first letter of their name.
名字的首字母相同。
Whether this is better or worse than looking a 2 letters, 3 letters, 4
这比查看2个字母、3个字母、4个字母
letters, it's going to depend on how much memory you want to spend
好还是坏，取决于你想花多少内存
and how much time you want to ultimately save.
以及你最终想节省多少时间。
Let me tweak this though a little bit.
不过，让我稍微修改一下。
It's conventional in C, just so you know,
在C语言中，你要知道，
that if you're passing in a string that is a char star to a function
如果你向一个函数传入一个字符串，它是一个char star，
and you have no intention of letting that function change the string,
而且你没有打算让那个函数改变这个字符串，
you should probably declare the argument to the function as const.
你应该将函数的参数声明为const。
And that will tell the compiler to please
这样会告诉编译器请
don't let the human programmer actually change
不要让程序员实际改变
that actual word in this function.
这个函数中的实际单词。
It's just not their place to do so.
这不在他们的职责范围内。
And we can actually do something else.
我们实际上可以做些其他事情。
In a hash function because you're using in this case, the output, the integer
在散列函数中，因为你正在使用这种情况，输出，整数
as a location in an array, it had better not be negative You want it to be
作为数组中的位置，最好不要是负数，你希望它是
or positive.
或正数。
And so, technically, if you want to impose that in code, you
因此，从技术上讲，如果你想在代码中强制执行，你
can specify that the int that's being returned has to be unsigned, that is,
可以指定返回的 int 必须是无符号的，也就是说，
it's 0 on up through the positive numbers.
它从 0 开始一直到正数。
It is not a negative value.
它不是负值。
So this is slightly better than the previous version
所以这比之前的版本稍微好一些
where we didn't have these defenses in place.
我们没有这些防御措施。
All right, so what does this actually mean in practice?
好吧，那么这在实践中到底意味着什么呢？
You don't get to necessarily pick the hash function based
你不能根据你的朋友的名字来选择散列函数。
on the names of your friends.
朋友的名字。
Presumably, Apple and Google and others already
可以推测，苹果、谷歌和其他公司已经
chose their hash function independent of what your friends names are.
独立于你朋友的名字选择了他们的散列函数。
So ideally, they want to pick a hash function that generally is quite fast,
所以理想情况下，他们希望选择一个通常速度很快的散列函数，
big O of 1.
O(1)。
But practically speaking, in a hash table
但实际上，在哈希表中
unless you get really lucky with the inputs, which you generally won't,
除非你在输入方面非常幸运，但通常不会，
really it's big O of n running time.
实际上，它的运行时间是 O(n)。
Why?
为什么？
Because in the worst possible scenario, you might have one long linked list.
因为在最坏的情况下，你可能只有一个很长的链表。
But in practice, ideally--
但在实践中，理想情况下——
and this is a little naive-- but suppose that you
这有点天真，但假设你
have a uniform distribution of friends in the world where 126 of them
在世界上有均匀分布的朋友，其中 126 个人
have names starting with and then another 126 out of B
的名字以 A 开头，然后另外 126 个人以 B 开头
and then dot, dot, dot Z. That would be a nice uniform distribution of friends.
等等，一直到 Z。 那将是一个很好的均匀分布的朋友。
Technically then, your running time of a hash table
从技术上讲，你的哈希表的运行时间
for searching it or deleting or inserting
用于搜索它、删除它或插入它
would technically be big O of n divided by k, where
从技术上讲，将是 O(n/k)，其中
k is the number of buckets, a constant.
k 是桶的数量，一个常数。
So it's technically big O of n divided by 26.
所以从技术上讲，它是 O(n/26)。
Now, again, per our discussion of big O notation, that's still the same thing.
现在，再次根据我们对大 O 符号的讨论，这仍然是一回事。
You get rid of constant factors.
你消除了常数因子。
So, yes, it's 26 times faster.
所以，是的，它快了 26 倍。
The chains are 126 the length.
链长是 126。
But asymptotically in terms of big O notation, it's still big O of n.
但就大 O 符号的渐近性而言，它仍然是 O(n)。
And here's where now we can start to veer away
这就是我们现在可以开始偏离的地方
from what is theoretically right versus what is practically right.
理论上的正确性与实际上的正确性。
In reality, in the real world, if you work for Google, Microsoft, Apple,
在现实中，在现实世界中，如果你在谷歌、微软、苹果工作，
and others, 26 times faster is actually faster in the real world
和其他公司，快了 26 倍实际上在现实世界中更快
even though a mathematician might say, that's really the same thing.
尽管数学家可能会说，这实际上是一回事。
But it's not.
但事实并非如此。
The real world wall clock time, if you watch
现实世界中的挂钟时间，如果你观察
the number of seconds passing on the clock, n over k
时钟上经过的秒数，n/k
is a much better running time than big O of n.
这是一个比大O(n)运行时间要好得多的运行时间。
So here too we're getting to the point where the conversations need
所以在这里，我们也到了谈话需要的时候
to become a little more sophisticated.
变得更加复杂一点。
It's not quite as simple as theory versus practice.
这并不像理论与实践之间的区别那样简单。
It depends on what matters ultimately to you.
这取决于对你来说最终重要的是什么。
But ideally and literally if somehow or other they picked an ideal hash
但理想情况下，如果他们以某种方式选择了理想的哈希函数
function, big O of 1 would really be the ideal here,
函数，大O(1)在这里将是理想的选择，
would really be the running time we achieve.
这将是我们能够达到的运行时间。
And what you'll generally find in the real world
而且你会在现实世界中普遍发现
is that you don't use hash functions that are as simplistic
你不会使用那些像简单地
as just look at the first letter.
看看第一个字母那样简单的哈希函数。
And, honestly, they won't generally look at the first
而且，老实说，他们通常不会看第一个
and the second and the third letter.
第二个和第三个字母。
They'll use some even fancier math to put real downward pressure
他们会使用一些更高级的数学来真正降低
on the probability of collisions so that, yes, they will still happen.
冲突的概率，所以，是的，它们仍然会发生。
But most of the time a really good hash function, even if it's not quite ideal,
但是大多数时候，一个非常好的哈希函数，即使它不完全是理想的，
will be darn close to constant time, which makes hash tables and in turn
几乎是常数时间，这使得哈希表，进而
dictionaries one of the most universally compelling data structures to use.
字典成为最普遍使用的、最有说服力的数据结构之一。
Now, with that said, we have time for just another data structure or so.
现在，说了这么多，我们还有时间再讲一个数据结构。
And this is not a typo.
这不是拼写错误。
This one's called and try.
这个叫做“尝试”。
And a try is short for retrieval, which is weird because you say retrieval.
而“尝试”是“检索”的简称，这很奇怪，因为你读的是“检索”。
But you say try.
但你说的是“尝试”。
But that's the etymology of try.
但这却是“尝试”的词源。
And a try is of the weirdest amalgamation
而“尝试”是这些东西中最奇怪的混合体
of all of these things, whereby a try is a tree of arrays.
所有这些东西，一个“尝试”是一棵数组树。
So a hash table is an array of linked lists.
所以哈希表是一个链表数组。
A try is a tree of arrays.
“尝试”是一棵数组树。
So at some point computer scientists just started
所以，在某个时候，计算机科学家们就开始
mashing together all of these different inputs,
将所有这些不同的输入混在一起，
and let's see what comes out of it.
看看会有什么结果。
But a try is actually really interesting.
但“尝试”实际上非常有趣。
And what you're about to see is a data structure that is literally
你将要看到的是一个真正的大O(1)时间，常数时间的数据结构。
big O of one time, constant time.
但有一个缺点。
But there is a downside.
所以，在“尝试”中，每个节点都是一个数组。
So in a try, every node is an array.
并且那个数组中的每个位置通常
And every location in that array generally
代表字母表中的一个字母。
represents a letter of the alphabet.
但你也可以将其推广到单词之外。
But you could generalize this away from words too.
在这种情况下，如果我们有一个根节点，那个根节点
In this case, if we have a root node, that root node
实际上是一个具有26个位置的大数组。
is technically a big array with 26 locations.
如果你想更一般地将名称或单词插入到“尝试”中，你需要做的是：
And if you want to insert names or words more generally into a try, what you do
这样做。
is this.
你一次又一次地进行哈希，为你的单词中的每一个字母创建一个数组。
You hash again and again and again creating one array
那么我的意思是什么呢？
for every letter in your word.
如果这里有26个元素，这将
So what do I mean by that?
代表A，这将代表Z。
If we've got 26 elements here, this would
。
be representing A. This would be representing Z.
And initially these are all null by default when you have just this root.
最初，当你只有这个根节点时，这些都是默认的空值。
But suppose I want to insert a few friends of mine, including
但是假设我想插入一些我的朋友，包括
Toad for instance.
比如蟾蜍。
T-O-A-D is the name.
T-O-A-D 是他的名字。
So how would I do that?
那么我该怎么做呢？
I would first find the location for T based on its number 0 through 25.
我首先会根据 T 的数字 0 到 25 找到它的位置。
And if this is T, what would I then do?
如果这是 T，我接下来该做什么呢？
I would change the null to actually be a pointer to another node, a.k.a.
我会将空值更改为指向另一个节点的指针，即
Another array.
另一个数组。
And then I would go into the second array
然后我会进入第二个数组
and hash on the second letter of Toad's name which is, of course O.
并对蟾蜍名字的第二个字母进行哈希运算，当然就是 O。
And then I would set a pointer to a third node
然后我会设置一个指向第三个节点的指针
in my tree, which would be represented here, so another 26 pointers.
在我的树中，这里会显示它，所以还有另外 26 个指针。
Then I would find the pointer representing A.
然后我会找到表示 A 的指针。
And I would create finally a fourth node, another ray representing
最后我会创建一个第四个节点，另一个代表
the fourth letter of Toad's name.
蟾蜍名字的第四个字母的数组。
But because Toad's name ends with D and therefore
但是因为蟾蜍的名字以 D 结尾，因此
I already have four nodes here, we need to specially color
我已经有了四个节点，我们需要特别地用颜色标记
though we could probably use an actual variable here.
虽然我们可能可以使用一个实际的变量在这里。
I need to somehow indicate that Toad's name stops here.
我需要用某种方式表明蟾蜍的名字到这里就结束了。
So it's not null per se, this actually means that T-O-A-D is in this data
所以它并不是严格意义上的空值，这实际上意味着 T-O-A-D 在这个数据中
structure.
结构中。
But I did this deliberately because another friend of mine
但我这样做是故意的，因为我的另一个朋友
might be Toadette in the Nintendo World.
可能是任天堂世界里的碧奇公主。
And Toadette, of course, is a superstring
当然，碧奇公主是蟾蜍的超字符串
of Toad, that is, it's longer but it shares a common prefix.
也就是说，它更长，但它有一个共同的前缀。
So Toadette could continue.
所以碧奇公主可以继续。
And I could have another node for the E, another node for the T,
我可以为 E 设立另一个节点，为 T 设立另一个节点，
another node for the second T, and another node for the last E.
为第二个 T 设立另一个节点，为最后一个 E 设立另一个节点。
But I somehow have to mark that E as the end of her name as well.
但我必须用某种方式标记那个 E 也是她名字的结尾。
So even though they share a common prefix,
所以即使它们有共同的前缀，
the fact that there's two green boxes on the screen means that T-O-A-D is
屏幕上出现两个绿色框的事实意味着 T-O-A-D 是
in this dictionary as a key as T-O-A-D-E-T-T-E is another key.
在这个字典中作为一个键，而 T-O-A-D-E-T-T-E 是另一个键。
And technically speaking, what's in these boxes
从技术上讲，这些框里
too-- it's not just a pointer.
也是——它不仅仅是一个指针。
It's probably Toad and Toadette's phone number and email
它可能是蟾蜍和碧奇公主的电话号码和电子邮件
address and the actual value of the dictionary, which is to say,
地址和字典的实际值，也就是说，
this too is in fact a dictionary.
它实际上也是一个字典。
A dictionary is just an abstract data type, a collection of key value pairs,
字典只是一种抽象数据类型，它是一组键值对，
just like I claimed a stack and a queue was.
就像我之前所说的栈和队列一样。
And how you implement it can differ.
而你的实现方式可以不同。
You could implement it with a hash table an, array of linked lists
你可以用哈希表和一个链表数组来实现
as we just did, or you can implement a dictionary as a try, a tree of arrays.
就像我们刚刚做的那样，或者你可以将字典实现为一个 try，一个数组树。
And let me add one more name to the mix, Tom, for instance,
让我再添加一个名字，比如汤姆，
a valid name from the universe.
一个来自这个宇宙的有效名字。
T-O-M just means that, OK, that name exists in this structure as well.
T-O-M 仅仅意味着，好的，这个名字也存在于这个结构中。
Now, what is the implication of storing the names
现在，存储名称的意义是什么？
in this way, which is implicitly.
以这种隐含的方式。
I'm effectively storing Toad and Toadette and Tom in this data structure
我实际上将 Toad、Toadette 和 Tom 存储在这个数据结构中
without actually storing T or O or A or D or any of the other letters.
而没有实际存储 T、O、A、D 或任何其他字母。
I'm just implicitly storing those letters
我只是隐含地存储这些字母
by actually using valid pointers that lead to another node.
通过使用指向另一个节点的有效指针。
And so what's the implication of this encode?
那么，这种编码的意义是什么呢？
Well, encode it might look like this.
嗯，它的编码可能看起来像这样。
Every node in a try is now redefined as being an array of size 26--
try 中的每个节点现在被重新定义为一个大小为 26 的数组——
and I'll call it children just to borrow the family tree metaphor--
我称它为 children，借用家族树的隐喻——
and that in each of these nodes there is room for the person's phone number,
并且每个节点都有空间存放该人的电话号码，
for instance, a.k.a. a string or char star.
例如，即一个字符串或 char 星号。
So what does this mean?
所以这意味着什么？
Well, if there's actually a non-null number there,
嗯，如果那里确实存在一个非空号码，
that's equivalent to there being a green box.
这就等同于存在一个绿色方框。
If you actually see plus 1, 617 dash whatever there,
如果你确实看到了加 1、617 减去任何东西，
that means there's a green box because Toad's number is right here.
就意味着那里有一个绿色方框，因为 Toad 的号码就在这里。
Or Toadette's number is down here.
或者 Toadette 的号码在下面。
Or Tom's is over there.
或者 Tom 的在那边。
But if this is null, that just means that maybe this is the T or the O
但是，如果它是空值，就意味着这可能是 T 或 O
or the E, which are not actually ends of people's names.
或者 E，它们实际上并不是人名的结尾。
So that's all these nodes actually are.
所以这些节点实际上就是这样。
And if we think back now to what this data structure looks like,
现在，如果我们回过头来看一下这个数据结构的样子，
this is in fact a data structure that can be navigated in constant time.
它实际上是一个可以在常数时间内进行遍历的数据结构。
Why?
为什么呢？
Well, all we need to keep track of this data structure is literally one pointer
嗯，我们只需要跟踪这个数据结构的唯一一个指针
called try that's a pointer to the first of these nodes, the so-called root
叫做 try，它指向第一个节点，即所谓的根
of the try.
这个 try 的根。
And when it comes to now thinking about the running time of a try, well,
现在，当我们考虑 try 的运行时间时，嗯，
what is it?
它是什么呢？
Well, if you've got n friends in your contacts already
嗯，如果你在你的联系人中已经有了 n 个朋友
or if there's n keys in that data structure,
或者在这个数据结构中有 n 个键，
how many steps does it take to find anyone?
找到任何人需要多少步？
Well, whether I have three names, Toad, Toadette, or Tom or three million names
嗯，无论我有三个名字，Toad、Toadette 或 Tom，还是三百万人，
in that data structure, how many steps will it take me to find Toad ever?
在这个数据结构中，找到 Toad 需要多少步呢？
T-O-A-D. How many steps for Toadette?
T-O-A-D。找到 Toadette 需要多少步？
T-O-A-D-E-T-T-E. Eight steps.
T-O-A-D-E-T-T-E。八步。
How about for Tom?
那么 Tom 呢？
1 2, 3.
1 2，3。
And, frankly, I'm sure if we looked it up,
而且，坦白地说，我相信如果我们查一下，
there's probably a limit on the number of characters in a Nintendo character's
任天堂角色的名字中可能存在字符数量的限制
name.
名字。
Maybe it's 20 characters total or maybe a little longer, 30.
也许总共是 20 个字符，或者可能更长一点，30 个。
There's some fixed value.
存在一个固定的值。
It's not unbounded.
它不是无界的。
There's not an infinite number of letters
任天堂角色的名字中没有无限个字母
in any Nintendo character's name.
在任何任天堂角色的名字中。
So there's some constant value.
所以存在一个常数。
Call it k.
我们称它为 k。
So no matter whose name you're looking for,
所以无论你在寻找谁的名字，
it's going to take you maximally k steps.
你最多需要 k 步才能找到。
But k is a constant.
但 k 是一个常数。
And we always said that big O of k is the same thing as big O of 1.
我们一直说，k 的大 O 和 1 的大 O 是相同的。
So for all intents and purposes, even though we're taking a bit of liberty
所以，就所有意图和目的而言，尽管我们在这里有点自由
here, searching a try, inserting into a try, deleting from a try
搜索一个 trie，插入一个 trie，从一个 trie 中删除
is constant time.
都是常数时间。
Because if you have a billion names in the dictionary already,
因为如果你已经在字典里存了一百万个名字，
it's going to take up a huge amount of space.
它将占用大量的空间。
But it does not affect how many steps it takes to find Toad or Toadette or Tom.
但这不会影响找到 Toad 或 Toadette 或 Tom 需要多少步。
That depends only on the length of their names
这仅仅取决于他们的名字的长度
which effectively is a constant value.
这实际上是一个常数值。
But there is a downside here.
但这里有一个缺点。
And it's a big one.
而且这是一个大问题。
In practice, I daresay most computers, most systems,
实际上，我敢说大多数计算机，大多数系统，
would actually use hash tables, not tries,
实际上使用的是哈希表，而不是 trie，
to implement dictionaries, collections of key value pairs.
来实现字典，键值对的集合。
What's the downside of this here data structure might you think?
你可能认为这个数据结构的缺点是什么？
And this is just a representative picture for Toad, Tom, and Toadette.
这只是 Toad、Tom 和 Toadette 的一个代表性图片。
All the space it takes up--
它占用的所有空间——
I mean, even for these three names, look at how many empty pointers there are.
我的意思是，即使对于这三个名字，看看有多少空指针。
So they're null to be sure.
所以可以肯定它们是空的。
But there's 25 unused spaces here, another 25 unused spaces here,
但这里有 25 个未使用的空间，这里还有 25 个未使用的空间，
24 unused spaces here.
这里有 24 个未使用的空间。
And what's not pictured is if I've got more and more names,
而没有画出来的是，如果我有越来越多的名字，
this thing's just going to blow up with more and more and more and more arrays
这个东西就会因为越来越多的数组而爆炸
even though there's not going to be someone whose name starts
即使不会有人名字以
with like Laa or Lba or Lbb.
Laa 或 Lba 或 Lbb 开头。
There's going to be so many combinations of letters
会有很多字母的组合
where it's just going to be null pointers instead.
它们只会是空指针。
So it takes up a huge amount of space.
所以它占用大量的空间。
But it does give us constant time.
但它确实给了我们常数时间。
And that then is this here trade off.
这就是这里的权衡。
So I would encourage you here on out as we exit the world of C
所以，我鼓励你在这里离开 C 的世界
and so much of today's code in the past several weeks code
以及过去几周的代码，今天的大部分代码
will soon be reduced in a week's time to just one
很快就会在一周内减少到只有一行代码，两行代码。
line of code, two lines of code.
一行代码，两行代码。
Because Python and the authors of Python will
因为 Python 和 Python 的作者将
have implemented all of this week's and last week's and prior week's
已经为我们实现了本周、上周和前几周的
ideas for us, we'll be able to operate at a higher level of abstraction.
想法，我们将能够在更高的抽象层面上操作。
And just think about what problems we want to solve
想想我们想要解决什么问题
and how we want to do so algorithmically and with data structures.
以及我们想如何用算法和数据结构来解决。
And data structures in conclusion are everywhere.
总之，数据结构无处不在。
Has anyone recognized this spot in Harvard Square?
有人认出哈佛广场的这个地方吗？
Anyone?
有人吗？
What are we looking at?
我们在看什么？
AUDIENCE: Is that Sweetgreen?
观众：那是 Sweetgreen 吗？
DAVID J. MALAN: So this is Sweetgreen, a popular salad place.
DAVID J. MALAN：所以这是 Sweetgreen，一家很受欢迎的沙拉店。
And this is actually a dictionary or really a hash table of sorts.
这实际上是一个字典，或者更确切地说，是一个哈希表。
Why?
为什么？
Well, if you buy a very expensive salad at Sweetgreen,
嗯，如果你在 Sweetgreen 买了一份很贵的沙拉，
they put it on the shelf for you if you've ordered via the app or online
如果你通过应用程序或在线订购，他们会帮你把沙拉放在货架上
in advance.
提前。
And if I, for instance, were to order a salad,
比如，如果我要点一份沙拉，
it would probably go under the D heading.
它可能会放在 D 部分。
If Carter were to order a salad, it would go under C, Julia under y.
如果 Carter 要点一份沙拉，它会放在 C 部分，Julia 则在 y 部分。
And so they hash the salads based on your first name
所以他们根据你的名字对沙拉进行哈希
to a particular location on the shelf.
到货架上的特定位置。
Why is that a good thing?
为什么那是一件好事？
Well, if it were just one long shelf that wasn't even alphabetical,
嗯，如果它只是一排长长的货架，而且不是按字母顺序排列，
it would be big O of n for me to find my salad
我找到我的沙拉的时间复杂度将为 O(n)
and for Carter and Julia to find theirs.
Carter 和 Julia 也是如此。
Because they've got 26 letters here, it's big O of 1.
因为他们这里有 26 个字母，所以时间复杂度是 O(1)。
It's one step for any of us to find our salads.
我们每个人只需要一步就能找到自己的沙拉。
Except, again, in perverse situations, where
当然，除了在一些极端情况下，比如
to might this system devolve at like 12:30 PM in the afternoon for instance?
下午 12:30 左右，这个系统可能会变得混乱。
What could go wrong?
会有什么问题？
AUDIENCE: A lot of people with names with the same first letter
观众：很多人的名字首字母相同
order a salad.
订购沙拉。
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, a lot of people with the same first letters
DAVID J. MALAN：没错，很多人名字的首字母都一样
of their names might order a salad.
可能会点沙拉。
So there's lots of like D, D, D. Where do we put the next person?
所以有很多 D、D、D。我们把下一个人放在哪里？
OK, well, maybe we overflow to E. What if there's a lot of E people?
好吧，也许我们会溢出到 E。如果有很多 E 开头名字的人怎么办？
It overflows to.
它会溢出到
F What if it overflows?
F。如果它溢出了怎么办？
Then we go to G. And it devolves anyway into a linked
然后我们转到 G。无论如何，它最终会变成一个链表
list or really multiple arrays that you have to search in big O of n time?
或者说，多个数组，你必须在 O(n) 时间内进行搜索？
I've even been to Sweetgreen at non-popular times.
我甚至在 Sweetgreen 非高峰时间去过。
And sometimes the staff just don't even choose to use the dictionaries.
有时工作人员甚至不选择使用字典。
They just put what's closest to them.
他们只是把沙拉放在离他们最近的地方。
So you have to search the same thing anywhere.
所以你必须在任何地方搜索相同的物品。
But you'll start to see now that you've seen some of these building blocks
但你会发现，当你看到这些基本的构件时
that data structures are everywhere algorithms are everywhere.
数据结构无处不在，算法也无处不在。
And among the goals of CS50 now are to harness these ideas most efficiently.
CS50 目标之一就是最有效地利用这些理念。
So that's a wrap.
所以就是这样。
We'll see you next time.
我们下次再见。
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]